<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data-related Advocacy on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </title>
    <link>https://talatera.github.io/tags/data-related-advocacy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data-related Advocacy on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 11:28:17 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://talatera.github.io/tags/data-related-advocacy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrating Data Literacy into Library and Information Science (LIS) Curriculum</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2020/01/16/integrating-data-literacy-library-and-information-science-lis-curriculum/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 11:28:17 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2020/01/16/integrating-data-literacy-library-and-information-science-lis-curriculum/</guid>
      <description>IASSIST&amp;rsquo;s Africa Regional Secretary Ms. Winny Nekesa Akullo and Prof. Constant Obura-Okello report on a data workshop at Makerere University, Kampala.
If you&amp;rsquo;re looking to orginise a similar regional or national data event, the IASSIST 2020 Event Sponsorship Proposals call is open until 26 January 2020.
IASSIST&amp;rsquo;s Membership Committee&amp;rsquo;s event sponsorship program recently sponsored a one day workshop on Integrating Data Literacy into Library and Information Science (LIS) Curriculum. The workshop aimed at bringing academicians in the field of library and information science to discuss how data literacy can be integrated in the LIS curriculum so as to have trained library professionals who are able to provide data literacy skills to their patrons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST&#39;s Statement in Response to President’s Executive Order on Visas and Immigration</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2017/02/13/iassists-statement-response-presidents-executive-order-visas-and-immigration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2017 12:00:31 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2017/02/13/iassists-statement-response-presidents-executive-order-visas-and-immigration/</guid>
      <description>February 13, 2017
Statement of the International Association for Social Science Information Services and Technology (IASSIST at http://iassistdata.org) in response to President Trump&amp;rsquo;s January 27 Executive Order on Visas and Immigration, titled &amp;ldquo;PROTECTING THE NATION FROM FOREIGN TERRORIST ENTRY INTO THE UNITED STATES&amp;rdquo;.
The recent executive order on visas and immigration issued on January 27th by US President Trump is of grave concern to IASSIST as an organization. IASSIST, the International Association for Social Science Information Services and Technology, is an international organization of professionals working in and with information technology, libraries, data services and research &amp;amp; higher education to support open science, advocate for responsible data management and use, build a broader community surrounding research data, and encourage the development of data professionals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interested in the “data revolution” and what it means for research? Here’s why you should attend IASSIST2016</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2016/05/03/interested-in-the-data-revolution-and-what-it-means-for-research-heres-why-you-should-attend-iassist2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2016 02:15:18 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2016/05/03/interested-in-the-data-revolution-and-what-it-means-for-research-heres-why-you-should-attend-iassist2016/</guid>
      <description>Part 1: Data sharing, new data sources and data protection IASSIST is an international organisation of information technology and data services professionals which aims to provide support to research and teaching in the social sciences. It has over 300 members ranging from data archive staff and librarians to statistical agencies, government departments and non-profit organisations.
The theme of this year&amp;rsquo;s conference is &amp;ldquo;Embracing the &amp;lsquo;data revolution&amp;rsquo;: opportunities and challenges for research&amp;rdquo; and it is the 42nd of its kind, taking place every year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“You can’t have a democratic society, without having a good data base.”</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2015/04/09/you-cant-have-a-democratic-society-without-having-a-good-data-base/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2015 09:49:43 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2015/04/09/you-cant-have-a-democratic-society-without-having-a-good-data-base/</guid>
      <description>Janet L. Norwood, former US Bureau of Labor Statistics commissioner, dies On the passing of this iconic defender of the neutrality of public data, I am struck how important Janet Norwood was to establishing a sound path for data advocacy as well as reminded of how necessary it is to have continuous education about this topic. In fact, swimming in ready-access to data as we are today, it&amp;rsquo;s especially important that we, as data professionals, remain alert to and defend a couple of aphorisms:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A decade against decay: the 10th International Digital Curation Conference</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2015/02/17/decade-against-decay-10th-international-digital-curation-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2015 05:34:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2015/02/17/decade-against-decay-10th-international-digital-curation-conference/</guid>
      <description>The International Digital Curation Conference (IDCC) is now ten years old. On the evidence of its most recent conference, is in rude health and growing fast.
IDCC is the first time IASSIST decided to formally support another organisational conference. I think it was a wise investment given the quality of plenaries, presentations, posters, and discussions.
DCC already has available a number of blogs covering the substance of sessions, including an excellent summary by IASSIST web editor, Robin Rice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST Fellows 2014</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2014/04/10/iassist-fellows-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2014 08:05:34 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2014/04/10/iassist-fellows-2014/</guid>
      <description>The IASSIST Fellows Committee is glad to announce through this post the four recipients of the 2014 IASSIST Fellowship award. We are extremely excited to have such a diverse and interesting group with different backgrounds and experience and encourage IASSISTers to welcome them at our conference in Toronto, Canada. Please find below their names, countries and brief bios:
Antonin Benoit, Head Librarian at the African Institute for Economic Development and Planning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>White Paper Urges New Approaches to Assure Access to Scientific Data </title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/12/23/white-paper-urges-new-approaches-assure-access-scientific-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2013 06:15:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/12/23/white-paper-urges-new-approaches-assure-access-scientific-data/</guid>
      <description>Press release posted on behalf of Mark Thompson-Kolar, ICPSR.
12/12/2013: (Ann Arbor, MI)&amp;mdash;More than two dozen data repositories serving the social, natural, and physical sciences today released a white paper recommending new approaches to funding sharing and preservation of scientific data. The document emphasizes the need for sustainable funding of domain repositories&amp;mdash;data archives with ties to specific scientific communities.
&amp;ldquo;Sustaining Domain Repositories for Digital Data: A White Paper,&amp;rdquo; is an outcome of a meeting convened June 24-25, 2013, in Ann Arbor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scientific Data Repositories Issue Call for Change on Funding Models for Data Archives </title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/09/27/scientific-data-repositories-issue-call-change-funding-models-data-archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2013 10:22:17 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/09/27/scientific-data-repositories-issue-call-change-funding-models-data-archives/</guid>
      <description>For Immediate Release September 16, 2013 Contact: Mark Thompson-Kolar, 734-615-7904 mdmtk@umich.edu
(Ann Arbor, MI) &amp;mdash; Representatives of 25 organizations that archive scientific data today released a Call for Action urging the creation of sustainable funding streams for domain repositories &amp;mdash; data archives with close ties to scientific communities.
The document was developed after a meeting of data repositories across the social and natural sciences June 24-25, 2013, in Ann Arbor. The meeting was organized by the Inter-university Consortium for Political and Social Research (ICPSR) at the University of Michigan and supported by the Alfred P.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST Fellows 2013</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/05/06/iassist-fellows-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2013 19:38:07 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/05/06/iassist-fellows-2013/</guid>
      <description>** **
The IASSIST Fellows Committee is glad to announce through this post the six recipients of the 2013 IASSIST Fellowship award. We are extremely excited to have such a diverse and interesting group with different backgrounds and experience and encourage IASSISTers to welcome them at our conference in Cologne, Germany.
Please find below their names, countries and brief bios:
**Chifundo Kanjala (Tanzania) **
Chifundo currently works as a Data Manager and data documentalist for an HIV research group called ALPHA network based at London School of Hygiene and Tropical Medicine&amp;rsquo;s department of Population Health, Chifundo spends most of his time in Mwanza, Tanzania but do travel from time around Southern and Eastern Africa to work with colleagues in the ALPHA network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSISTers and librarians are doin&#39; it for themselves</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/04/02/iassisters-and-librarians-are-doin-it-themselves/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 11:37:29 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/04/02/iassisters-and-librarians-are-doin-it-themselves/</guid>
      <description>Hey IASSISTers (gents, pardon for the video pun - couldnt&amp;rsquo; resist),
Are librarians at your institutions struggling to get up to speed with research data management (RDM)? If they&amp;rsquo;re not, they probably should be. Library organisations are publishing reports and issuing recommendations left and right, such as the LIBER (Association of European Research Libraries) 2012 report, &amp;ldquo;Ten Recommendations for Libraries to Get Started with Research Data Management&amp;rdquo; (PDF). Just last week Nature published an article highlighting what the Great and the Good are doing in this area: Publishing Frontiers: The Library Reboot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update from COSSA: Changes to the Common Rule: The Implications for the Social and Behavioral Sciences</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/03/25/update-cossa-changes-common-rule-implications-social-and-behavioral-sciences/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 14:34:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/03/25/update-cossa-changes-common-rule-implications-social-and-behavioral-sciences/</guid>
      <description>This is from the COSSA Newsletter ([Consortium of Social Science Associations).]{.st} March 25, 2013 Volume 32, Issue 6 Regarding a workshop on proposed changes to the Common Rule. Readers of these blog entries will recall that these proposed changes would require that data identitified in social science research would be required to meet HIPPA standards; potentially rendering many public datasets unuseful for research purposes.
A link to the webcast is here: http://sites.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST 2013 Fellows update</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/03/20/iassist-2013-fellows-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 14:40:47 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/03/20/iassist-2013-fellows-update/</guid>
      <description>This year the IASSIST Fellows Committee received a grand total of 44 Fellows applications from a strong range of candidates from 28 countries around the globe:[ ]{.Apple-converted-space}[ ]{.Apple-converted-space}
  18 Asia   13 Africa
  7 Europe
  3 North America
  2 Latin America
  1 Australia
  Applications have been evaluated by the IASSIST Fellows Committee and offers have been made to a number of prospective Fellows to attend the annual conference in Cologne, Germany.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Knight Foundation Data Challenge (FYI)</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2012/07/11/knight-foundation-data-challenge-fyi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2012 16:33:43 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2012/07/11/knight-foundation-data-challenge-fyi/</guid>
      <description>The Knight Foundation announced a data-related grant opportunity in a kind of &amp;ldquo;tweet your grant proposal&amp;rdquo; format. The call has closed but over 800 of the applications are viewable through Tumblr. In a simple search of the applications with the words &amp;ldquo;data professionals&amp;rdquo; returned 148 results. Of these, some of the more related are:  My submission: A passion for data, and the professionals who keep it alive{.gs-title} A proposal for a dating service for data professionals :} DATABLE | Data based dating{.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST Fellows application now closed</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2012/03/03/iassist-fellows-application-now-closed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2012 01:15:15 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2012/03/03/iassist-fellows-application-now-closed/</guid>
      <description>The application for IASSIST Fellows is now closed. Over 40 applications from 23 different countries have been received with the following number of applications by region:
 23 Latin America 12 Africa 6 Asia  The Fellows Committee is now working to evaluate the applications and will make the decisions in the following weeks. Good luck to all participants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST 2012 Fellows Program</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2012/01/31/iassist-2012-fellows-program/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2012 13:32:09 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2012/01/31/iassist-2012-fellows-program/</guid>
      <description>The IASSIST Fellows Program is now accepting applications for financial support to attend the IASSIST 2012 conference in Washington [http://www.iassist2012.org/], from data professionals from countries with emerging economies who are developing and managing data infrastructures at their home institutions.
Please be aware that funding is not intended to cover the entire cost of attending the conference. The applicant&amp;rsquo;s home institution must provide some level of financial support to supplement the IASSIST Fellow award.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST Latin Engagement Action Group </title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/11/03/iassist-latin-engagement-action-group/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2011 06:56:25 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/11/03/iassist-latin-engagement-action-group/</guid>
      <description>The Latin Engagement Action Group have come up with a number of outreach activities aimed at supporting data professionals from Spanish and Portuguese speaking educational institutions, namely:
1. Research Data Management Webinars (complete with IASSIST contribution) for Spanish/Portuguese data specialists (http://www.recolecta.net/buscador/webminars.jsp)
Stuart Macdonald and Luis Martínez-Uribe in collaboration with Alicia López Medina (UNED, Spain), the Spanish Agency of Science and Technology (FECYT) and the network of Spanish repositories RECOLECTA have organised a programme of webinars in 3 strands starting in October to discuss RDM issues:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>86 helpful tools for the data professional PLUS 45 bonus tools</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/10/29/86-helpful-tools-data-professional-plus-45-bonus-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2011 17:04:17 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/10/29/86-helpful-tools-data-professional-plus-45-bonus-tools/</guid>
      <description>I have been working on this (mostly) annotated collection of tools and articles that I believe would be of help to both the data dabbler and professional. If you are a data scientist, data analyst or data dummy, chances are there is something in here for you. I included a list of tools, such as programming languages and web-based utilities, [data mining]{.zem_slink} resources, some prominent organizations in the field, repositories where you can play with data, events you may want to attend and important articles you should take a look at.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data can be cool</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/10/06/data-can-be-cool/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2011 09:46:59 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/10/06/data-can-be-cool/</guid>
      <description>As I prepare to leave Guelph there are lots of things I will miss - but what I will maybe miss most is the Data Resource Centre and the creative people who work there. If you link to the picasa album below you will see some awesome posters they have made to showcase services and bring people into the world of Data and GIS. The images on some of the posters are really powerful&amp;hellip;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>US Budget Cuts Threaten Statistical Abstract</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/08/us-budget-cuts-threaten-statistical-abstract/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2011 07:13:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/08/us-budget-cuts-threaten-statistical-abstract/</guid>
      <description>When the big news broke last month that the US Census Bureau is proposing budget cuts that would lead to the demise of the Statistical Compendia Branch, including the beloved Statistical Abstract, the library listservs lit up with concern. It&amp;rsquo;s not too late to take action if you haven&amp;rsquo;t already notified your representatives about this issue. There are now several venues where you can add your voice:
 Sign the Change.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Science Special: Dealing with Data</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/02/17/science-special-dealing-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 04:31:07 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/02/17/science-special-dealing-data/</guid>
      <description>In the 11 February 2011 issue, Science joins with colleagues from Science Signaling, Science Translational Medicine, and Science Careers to provide a broad look at the issues surrounding the increasingly huge influx of research data. This collection of articles highlights both the challenges posed by the data deluge and the opportunities that can be realized if we can better organize and access the data. Science is making access to this entire collection FREE (simple registration is required for non-subscribers).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBE 2020 white papers available</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/02/04/sbe-2020-white-papers-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2011 00:14:24 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/02/04/sbe-2020-white-papers-available/</guid>
      <description>The Directorate for the Social, Behavioral, and Economic Sciences of the National Science Foundation (NSF/SBE) has released today a collection of white papers contributed under the &amp;ldquo;SBE 2020: Future Research in the Social, Behavioral &amp;amp; Economic Sciences&amp;rdquo; initiative. Authors were asked to outline grand challenge questions that are both foundational and transformative. For information, please visit: http://www.nsf.gov/sbe/sbe_2020/index.cfm
[](http://www.nsf.gov/sbe/sbe_2020/index.cfm){.moz-txt-link-freetext}The Open Data Foundation contributed to the following:
Maximizing the Potential of Data: Modern IT Tools, Best Practices, and Metadata Standards for SBE Sciences Pascal Heus (pascal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Torture, Numbers, and Digital Tape</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/02/02/torture-numbers-and-digital-tape/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2011 07:02:15 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/02/02/torture-numbers-and-digital-tape/</guid>
      <description>The IASSIST Quarterly (IQ) volume 33 number 3 is now on the web:
[http://iassistdata.org/iq/issue/33/3]
With this issue concentrating on quantitative investigations and the use of statistics, I came to think of the Mark Twain citation &amp;ldquo;There are three kinds of lies: lies, damned lies, and statistics.&amp;rdquo; With the violent title of the first article (see below), the article on numbers and statistics, and the report from a national statistics agency, the &amp;ldquo;Torture,Numbers, and Digital Tape&amp;rdquo; title surfaced.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SPARC Digital Repositories meeting includes session on open data</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2010/11/10/sparc-digital-repositories-meeting-includes-session-open-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2010 06:41:49 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2010/11/10/sparc-digital-repositories-meeting-includes-session-open-data/</guid>
      <description>Kathleen Shearer of the Canadian Association of Research Libraries organized and chaired a panel on Open Data was held at the SPARC Digital Repositories meeting on November 8, 2010. IASSIST members Gail Steinhart and Chuck Humphrey were two of the three members on this panel. Kevin Ashley, Director of the Digital Curation Centre (DCC), was the third. It has been two years since this group last met and the attendance was said to have doubled between meetings (looked like there were around 150 people present.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST letter to Canadian Government on loss of 2011 Census long form</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2010/10/05/iassist-letter-canadian-government-loss-2011-census-long-form/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2010 13:44:28 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2010/10/05/iassist-letter-canadian-government-loss-2011-census-long-form/</guid>
      <description>Industry Canada Office of the Honourable Tony Clement Minister of Industry C.D. Howe Building 235 Queen Street Ottawa, ON K1A 0H5 25 July 2010
Dear Minister Clement
We write on behalf of the International Association of Social Science Information Services and Technology. IASSIST is an international organization of professionals working in and with information technology and data services to support research and teaching in the social sciences. Its 300 members are from a variety of workplaces, including data archives, statistical agencies, research centers, libraries, academic departments, government departments, and non-profit organizations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>World Statistics Day</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2010/08/18/world-statistics-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2010 13:49:47 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2010/08/18/world-statistics-day/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;On 20 October, 2010 [20.10.2010] the World will celebrate the first World Statistics Day, to raise awareness of the many achievements of official statistics premised on the core values of service, professionalism, and integrity.&amp;rdquo; For more information and resources, see:
http://unstats.un.org/unsd/wsd/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CAPDU - Canadian Census</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2010/07/16/capdu-canadian-census/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2010 13:22:20 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2010/07/16/capdu-canadian-census/</guid>
      <description>More info on what the response has been in Canada is available here: http://capdu.wordpress.com/ Very interesting to watch this unfold if you are interested in data or interested in how these community responses develop. </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>