<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Analytical Methods and Software on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </title>
    <link>https://talatera.github.io/tags/analytical-methods-and-software/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Analytical Methods and Software on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 10:03:28 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://talatera.github.io/tags/analytical-methods-and-software/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>but how do i *do* qualitative research? bridging the gap between qualitative researchers and methods resources--part 4</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2017/08/07/how-do-i-do-qualitative-research-bridging-gap-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 10:03:28 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2017/08/07/how-do-i-do-qualitative-research-bridging-gap-4/</guid>
      <description>Last week Mandy shared ideas about how librarians and other data-support professionals can act as connectors, crusaders and collaborators on campus in order to better provide and develop qualitative research teaching resources. This week we want to build on Mandy&amp;rsquo;s suggestions by looking a bit more broadly at how librarians and other data-support professionals can help build community around qualitative research at their institutions.
As qualitative research methods are often not the dominant methodologies used in departments and institutions, qualitative researchers may not have a strong support network and may lack colleagues to consult with or learn from.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>But How Do I *Do* Qualitative Research? Bridging the Gap between Qualitative Researchers and Methods Resources--PART 3</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2017/07/31/how-do-i-do-qualitative-research-bridging-gap-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 06:53:37 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2017/07/31/how-do-i-do-qualitative-research-bridging-gap-3/</guid>
      <description>Connectors, Crusaders, and Collaborators Jill&amp;rsquo;s post from last week detailed ways we data-support professionals can connect researchers to library collections and other information sources for bridging the qualitative methods gap. I&amp;rsquo;d like to offer more ideas for how we can act not only as connectors but also as crusaders and collaborators on our campuses specifically in the realm of providing and developing qualitative-research teaching resources. Because we work with researchers across campus and in various capacities, data-support professionals are often more aware of methods gaps than are the academic departments we support.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>But How Do I *Do* Qualitative Research? Bridging the Gap between Qualitative Researchers and Methods Resources--PART 2</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2017/07/23/how-do-i-do-qualitative-research-bridging-gap-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2017 21:20:53 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2017/07/23/how-do-i-do-qualitative-research-bridging-gap-2/</guid>
      <description>Mandy kicked off our 4-part blog series last week with an inaugural post that provided background and context for this project, which centers around a specific challenge faced by many qualitative researchers: lack of qualitative methods training. This post offers some concrete ideas to data-support professionals on how to leverage library collections and other information sources that direct researchers to secondary and tertiary sources on qualitative methods to address this issue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>But How Do I *Do* Qualitative Research? Bridging the Gap between Qualitative Researchers and Methods Resources--PART 1</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2017/07/17/how-do-i-do-qualitative-research-bridging-gap-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2017 09:37:14 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2017/07/17/how-do-i-do-qualitative-research-bridging-gap-1/</guid>
      <description>The IASSIST Qualitative Social Science &amp;amp; Humanities Data Interest Group (QSSHDIG) was created in October 2016, its central purpose: to foster conversations regarding the needs of researchers who generate qualitative data, and what types of services librarians and other information professionals can develop to support these researchers in managing their data/source materials throughout the research lifecycle.
This four-post blog series engages in one particular conversation: challenges researchers face in terms of a lack of qualitative methods training, and strategies for how data-support professionals can address these challenges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST 2016 Program At-A-Glance, Part 2: Data infrastructure, data processing and research data management</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2016/05/06/iassist-2016-program-glance-part-2-data-infrastructure-data-processing-and-research-data-manage/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2016 07:13:42 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2016/05/06/iassist-2016-program-glance-part-2-data-infrastructure-data-processing-and-research-data-manage/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s another list of highlights from IASSIST2016 which is focusing on the data revolution. For previous highlights, see here.
Infrastructure  For those of you with an interest in technical infrastructure, the University of Applied Sciences HTW Chur will showcase an early protype MMRepo (1 June, 3F), whose function is to store qualitative and quantitative data into one big data repository.   The UK Data Service will present the following panel &amp;ldquo;The CESSDA Technical Framework - what is it and why is it needed?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the IASSIST Data Visualization Interest Group (DVIG!)</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/03/31/introducing-iassist-data-visualization-interest-group-dvig/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 11:51:27 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/03/31/introducing-iassist-data-visualization-interest-group-dvig/</guid>
      <description>Hello fellow IASSISTer&amp;rsquo;s
 With the upcoming 2013 Conference nearing, we thought it very fitting to introduce you all to the newly created IASSIST Data Visualization Interest Group. Formed over the winter and now spring of 2013, this group brings together over 46 IASSIST members from across the world (literally across-the-world! check out the map of our locations), who are all interested in data visualization. We hope to share a range of skills and information around tools, best practice visualization, and discuss innovative representations of data, statistics, and information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In search of:  Best practice for code repositories?</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/03/05/search-best-practice-code-repositories/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2013 12:45:39 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/03/05/search-best-practice-code-repositories/</guid>
      <description>I was asked by a colleague about organized efforts within the economics community to develop or support repositories of code for research. Her experience was with the astrophysics world which apparently has several and she was wondering what could be learned from another academic community. So I asked a non-random sample of technical economists with whom I work, and then expanded the question to cover all of social sciences and posed the question to the IASSIST community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A list of upcoming Big Data conferences</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2012/08/25/list-upcoming-big-data-conferences/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Aug 2012 10:38:55 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2012/08/25/list-upcoming-big-data-conferences/</guid>
      <description>check out AnalyticBridge (a social network for analytic professionals) Here is a reposting their list of upcoming conferences.
Conferences Discussions - AnalyticBridge{.rss-title}
 Sentiment Analysis Symposium, October 29-30, San Francisco{.rss-item} Beyond Hadoop: next generation of big data analytics - August 22{.rss-item} SFBay ACM - Data Mining Hackathon on Big Data on August 18{.rss-item} Data Mining: Failure to Launch ( Live Predictive Analytics Web Event 8/15 &amp;amp; 9/6 ){.rss-item} Predictive Analytics &amp;amp; Data Mining Vendor-Neutral Courses [ Wash, DC - Sept | Las Vegas - Dec ]{.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Visualization tools &amp; greater emphasis on teaching to be incorporated into R-Studio!</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2012/08/21/data-visualization-tools-greater-emphasis-teaching-be-incorporated-r-studio/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2012 08:26:26 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2012/08/21/data-visualization-tools-greater-emphasis-teaching-be-incorporated-r-studio/</guid>
      <description>Reposted from the RStudio Blog:
Welcome Hadley, Winston, and Garrett!
August 20, 2012 in News
RStudio&amp;rsquo;s mission from the beginning has been to create powerful tools that support the practices and techniques required for creating trustworthy, high quality analysis. For many years Hadley Wickham has been teaching and working on his own set of tools for R with many of the same core goals. We&amp;rsquo;ve been collaborating quite a bit with Hadley over the past couple of years and today we&amp;rsquo;re excited to announce that Hadley, Winston Chang, and Garrett Grolemund are joining RStudio so we can continue to work together much more closely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST Quarterly (IQ) volume 34-2 now on the web</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/05/17/iassist-quarterly-iq-volume-34-2-now-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2011 09:02:31 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/05/17/iassist-quarterly-iq-volume-34-2-now-web/</guid>
      <description>The new issue of the IASSIST Quarterly is now available on the web. This is the volume 34 (number 2, 2010).
 http://iassistdata.org/iq/issue/34/2
The layout has changed. We hope you&amp;rsquo;ll enjoy the new style presented. It seems to be a more modern format and more suited for the PDF presentation on the web. Walter Piovesan &amp;ndash; our publication officer &amp;ndash; had a biking accident. To show that nothing is so bad that it is not good for something Walter used his recovery time to redesign the IQ.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>