<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Understanding researcher practices on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </title>
    <link>https://talatera.github.io/tags/understanding-researcher-practices/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Understanding researcher practices on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2012 10:08:56 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://talatera.github.io/tags/understanding-researcher-practices/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>UNC Data Stewardship Report</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2012/04/04/unc-data-stewardship-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2012 10:08:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2012/04/04/unc-data-stewardship-report/</guid>
      <description>In the spring of 2011, the UNC-Chapel Provost formed the Task Force on the Stewardship of Digital Research Data and charged its members with exploring the implications of data management for the University and making recommendations for University policy. The Task Force investigated the data management landscape through research in the literature, conversations with faculty and staff, and an in-depth faculty survey designed and administered by the Odum Institute. The resulting report was submitted to administrators in mid-February 2012 with recommendations for university policies and procedures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Data Management Training online course</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/10/26/research-data-management-training-online-course/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2011 03:58:29 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/10/26/research-data-management-training-online-course/</guid>
      <description>The Research Data Management Training, or MANTRA project has produced an open, online training course for PhD and early career researchers to learn best practices in data management.
In addition to the interactive, online module which covers data management topics such as Organising Your Data, there are downloadable software modules covering data handling skills in SPSS, R, NVivo and ArcGIS.
The resource was created by EDINA and Data Library, University of Edinburgh, and was funded by the JISC Managing Research Data programme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Curation Profiles Toolkit</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/25/data-curation-profiles-toolkit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2011 13:53:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/25/data-curation-profiles-toolkit/</guid>
      <description>The Data Curation Profiles Toolkit enables librarians, archivists, and others to deepen their understanding of researchers&amp;rsquo; practices and needs regarding research data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Asset Framework</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/25/data-asset-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2011 13:34:54 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/25/data-asset-framework/</guid>
      <description>The Data Asset Framework provides organisations with a survey methodology to identify, locate, describe and assess how they are managing their research data assets. Designed for UK Higher Education Institutions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>