<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Africa on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </title>
    <link>https://talatera.github.io/tags/africa/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Africa on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 11:28:17 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://talatera.github.io/tags/africa/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrating Data Literacy into Library and Information Science (LIS) Curriculum</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2020/01/16/integrating-data-literacy-library-and-information-science-lis-curriculum/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 11:28:17 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2020/01/16/integrating-data-literacy-library-and-information-science-lis-curriculum/</guid>
      <description>IASSIST&amp;rsquo;s Africa Regional Secretary Ms. Winny Nekesa Akullo and Prof. Constant Obura-Okello report on a data workshop at Makerere University, Kampala.
If you&amp;rsquo;re looking to orginise a similar regional or national data event, the IASSIST 2020 Event Sponsorship Proposals call is open until 26 January 2020.
IASSIST&amp;rsquo;s Membership Committee&amp;rsquo;s event sponsorship program recently sponsored a one day workshop on Integrating Data Literacy into Library and Information Science (LIS) Curriculum. The workshop aimed at bringing academicians in the field of library and information science to discuss how data literacy can be integrated in the LIS curriculum so as to have trained library professionals who are able to provide data literacy skills to their patrons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chronology of data library and data centres</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2014/11/20/chronology-data-library-and-data-centres/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2014 10:01:41 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2014/11/20/chronology-data-library-and-data-centres/</guid>
      <description>A few days ago I asked on the IASSIST mailing list for some help in order to find out dates of creation of data libraries, data centres and such services. It was overwhelming to receive answers from colleagues from everywhere with dates and some other useful information about the establishment of local data support and national services.
  Newton, author of Chronology of Kingdoms   There is a wealth of information in this community around these issues and with the increasing importance of data services we need to make sure we collect and make this information accessible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST Africa Regional Report 2013-2014</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2014/05/16/iassist-africa-regional-report-2013-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2014 06:26:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2014/05/16/iassist-africa-regional-report-2013-2014/</guid>
      <description>Freeing African Data Two regional developments have the potential to get African government data into the public domain. Putting their disaggregated data out there can benefit African governance through ensuring transparency and allowing feedback from policy analysis to support better government planning. The World Bank&amp;rsquo;s Central microdata catalog has been around since 2012 and continues to expand its listing of data sources. This is currently the only comprehensive online source for microdata produced by African official data producers, as a listing of country datasets is not available on most African government websites.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST Fellows 2014</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2014/04/10/iassist-fellows-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2014 08:05:34 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2014/04/10/iassist-fellows-2014/</guid>
      <description>The IASSIST Fellows Committee is glad to announce through this post the four recipients of the 2014 IASSIST Fellowship award. We are extremely excited to have such a diverse and interesting group with different backgrounds and experience and encourage IASSISTers to welcome them at our conference in Toronto, Canada. Please find below their names, countries and brief bios:
Antonin Benoit, Head Librarian at the African Institute for Economic Development and Planning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST Fellows 2013</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/05/06/iassist-fellows-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2013 19:38:07 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/05/06/iassist-fellows-2013/</guid>
      <description>** **
The IASSIST Fellows Committee is glad to announce through this post the six recipients of the 2013 IASSIST Fellowship award. We are extremely excited to have such a diverse and interesting group with different backgrounds and experience and encourage IASSISTers to welcome them at our conference in Cologne, Germany.
Please find below their names, countries and brief bios:
**Chifundo Kanjala (Tanzania) **
Chifundo currently works as a Data Manager and data documentalist for an HIV research group called ALPHA network based at London School of Hygiene and Tropical Medicine&amp;rsquo;s department of Population Health, Chifundo spends most of his time in Mwanza, Tanzania but do travel from time around Southern and Eastern Africa to work with colleagues in the ALPHA network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST 2012 Fellows Program</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2012/01/31/iassist-2012-fellows-program/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2012 13:32:09 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2012/01/31/iassist-2012-fellows-program/</guid>
      <description>The IASSIST Fellows Program is now accepting applications for financial support to attend the IASSIST 2012 conference in Washington [http://www.iassist2012.org/], from data professionals from countries with emerging economies who are developing and managing data infrastructures at their home institutions.
Please be aware that funding is not intended to cover the entire cost of attending the conference. The applicant&amp;rsquo;s home institution must provide some level of financial support to supplement the IASSIST Fellow award.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Torture, Numbers, and Digital Tape</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/02/02/torture-numbers-and-digital-tape/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2011 07:02:15 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/02/02/torture-numbers-and-digital-tape/</guid>
      <description>The IASSIST Quarterly (IQ) volume 33 number 3 is now on the web:
[http://iassistdata.org/iq/issue/33/3]
With this issue concentrating on quantitative investigations and the use of statistics, I came to think of the Mark Twain citation &amp;ldquo;There are three kinds of lies: lies, damned lies, and statistics.&amp;rdquo; With the violent title of the first article (see below), the article on numbers and statistics, and the report from a national statistics agency, the &amp;ldquo;Torture,Numbers, and Digital Tape&amp;rdquo; title surfaced.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>