<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Other Topics on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </title>
    <link>https://talatera.github.io/tags/other-topics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Other Topics on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2011 09:06:11 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://talatera.github.io/tags/other-topics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sensitive data and the US Patriot Act</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/06/30/sensitive-data-and-us-patriot-act/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2011 09:06:11 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/06/30/sensitive-data-and-us-patriot-act/</guid>
      <description>The series of articles below might be of interest to some of you planning or working with sensitive data in the cloud.
Microsoft admits Patriot Act can access EU-based cloud data
[](http://www.zdnet.com/blog/igeneration/microsoft-admits-patriot-act-can-access-eu-based-cloud-data/11225)See also ZDNet&amp;rsquo;s Patriot Act series:
 ZDNet&amp;rsquo;s USA PATRIOT Act series Summary Part 1: USA PATRIOT Act and the controversy of Canada Part 2: Safe Harbor: Why EU data needs &amp;lsquo;protecting&amp;rsquo; from U.S. law Part 3: How the USA PATRIOT Act can be used to access EU data Part 4: USA PATRIOT Act: The myth of a secure European cloud  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>US and UK governments embrace &#39;open data&#39;</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2009/12/23/us-and-uk-governments-embrace-open-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2009 13:17:08 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2009/12/23/us-and-uk-governments-embrace-open-data/</guid>
      <description>The US Open Government Directive, released on December 8, 2009, instructs all federal agencies to provide high-value information to the public online in open, accessible, machine-readable formats. This adds to the momentum already in place at Data.gov to &amp;ldquo;increase public access to high value, machine readable datasets generated by the Executive Branch of the Federal Government.&amp;rdquo; The Open Knowledge Foundation blog describes progress to date and milestones to come.
The UK government also recently announced similar plans to open up data, and the imminent launch of a new Data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Visualization Without Computers</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2009/09/17/data-visualization-without-computers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2009 12:21:45 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2009/09/17/data-visualization-without-computers/</guid>
      <description>Vintage Infographics From the 1930s, Flowing Data (Sept. 11, 2009). Some examples from Willard Cope Brinton&amp;rsquo;s 1939 book Graphic Presentation.
  jim   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conference webcasts and presentations online!</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2009/06/09/conference-webcasts-and-presentations-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2009 12:40:46 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2009/06/09/conference-webcasts-and-presentations-online/</guid>
      <description>A week has passed since IASSIST 2009. I hope most of you have made it safely back home by now - and are ready to refresh the memories by watching the conference webcasts and viewing presentations. Webcasts of all three plenaries and Thursday and Friday&amp;rsquo;s concurrent sessions in the Small Auditorium are now available. We didn&amp;rsquo;t have cameras available during the Wednesday sessions, so no videos of these presentations, sorry! But most of the presentations are already online - a few are still missing either because we didn&amp;rsquo;t have them or we are waiting for an updated version.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Special IQ: Moving Research Data Into and Out of Institutional Repositories</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2009/05/12/special-iq-moving-research-data-and-out-institutional-repositories/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2009 14:42:09 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2009/05/12/special-iq-moving-research-data-and-out-institutional-repositories/</guid>
      <description>The IASSIST Quarterly IQ Vol. 31 issue 3&amp;amp;4 is now available on the web:
http://iassistdata.org/publications/iq/iqvol31.html
This issue will only be available on the web. There will be no printed version mailed out to the membership.
This double issue is the work of the authors and their articles are introduced below. We are presenting an integrated double issue of high quality. We should also give a special thanks to the editors of the issue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New IQ!</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2009/03/26/new-iq/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2009 08:35:15 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2009/03/26/new-iq/</guid>
      <description>The IASSIST Quarterly (IQ Vol. 31 issue 2 - 2007) is now available on the web:
http://iassistdata.org/publications/iq/iqvol31.html
This issue will be printed and mailed to the membership. From next issue IASSIST will be saving trees and only publish the IQ on the web. We hope you agree with our decision. Thanks.
Some of you are now getting ready for the IASSIST conference in Tampere, Finland 26.-29. of May. Remember if you are giving presentations that you could write the presentation as an article for the IQ.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Registration for the IASSIST 2009 is open</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2009/02/24/registration-iassist-2009-open/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2009 10:03:01 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2009/02/24/registration-iassist-2009-open/</guid>
      <description>Tervetuloa Tampereelle, Welcome to Tampere!
Registration for the 2009 IASSIST conference is now officially open. On the conference web site there is more information on registration, accommodations and excursions.
The Early Bird rate is valid until March 24, 2009. Please note that a deposit of one night for accommodation should be paid together with the registration fees. Cancellations (conference attendance, hotels, tours) on or before April 24 will receive a refund minus the administrative fees.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Symposium on Institutional Data Services at Edinburgh</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2009/02/02/symposium-institutional-data-services-edinburgh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2009 13:29:20 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2009/02/02/symposium-institutional-data-services-edinburgh/</guid>
      <description>The Edinburgh University Data Library celebrated 25 years of support for staff and students in their discovery, access, use and management of research datasets. On 5 December 2008, following on from the Digital Curation Centre international conference held in Edinburgh that week, friends and colleagues from near and far gathered in the afternoon at the EDINA offices to celebrate the milestone with short speeches and cutting the cake, along with food, drink and toasts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Scientists, Data Managers, Data Librarians, Oh My!</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2008/09/23/data-scientists-data-managers-data-librarians-oh-my/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2008 09:17:27 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2008/09/23/data-scientists-data-managers-data-librarians-oh-my/</guid>
      <description>The Skills, Role and Career Structure of Data Scientists: An Assessment of Current Practice and Future Needs is a report prepared by Alma Swan and Sheridan Brown this summer for JISC in the UK.
The Skills, Role and Career Structure of Data Scientists: An Assessment of Current Practice and Future Needs is a report prepared by Alma Swan and Sheridan Brown this summer for JISC in the UK.
 Ours is a profession that is not highly visible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canadian Research Data Strategy Working Group Established</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2008/08/26/canadian-research-data-strategy-working-group-established/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2008 09:37:46 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2008/08/26/canadian-research-data-strategy-working-group-established/</guid>
      <description>Research Data Strategy Working Group Established http ://cisti-icist.nrc-cnrc.gc.ca/media/press/rds_group_e.html, press release, August 12, 2008.
The research process generates huge amounts of data that are an important part of Canada&amp;rsquo;s scholarly record and hold enormous potential as an additional discovery and problem-solving tool for researchers. Unfortunately, Canada has no nationally adopted standards or policies governing how this data is collected, catalogued, or preserved.
Research Data Strategy Working Group Established http ://cisti-icist.nrc-cnrc.gc.ca/media/press/rds_group_e.html, press release, August 12, 2008.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>new IQ</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2008/08/15/new-iq-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2008 13:07:45 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2008/08/15/new-iq-0/</guid>
      <description>The IASSIST Quarterly (IQ Vol. 31 issue 1 - 2007) is now available on the web:
http://iassistdata.org/publications/iq/iqvol31.html
Welcome to the first issue of the IASSIST Quarterly, vol. 31. We have passed the 34th IASSIST conference, also known as the Stanford IASSIST 2008 conference - best ever. However, the IASSIST Quarterly vol. 31 is known also as the 2007 volume. Yes, we are behind our schedule; but at least we are consistently so.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNdata, UN Common Database and UN COMTRADE</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2008/02/28/undata-un-common-database-and-un-comtrade/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2008 13:32:08 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2008/02/28/undata-un-common-database-and-un-comtrade/</guid>
      <description>I took a long look at UNData the other day and came away thinking &amp;ldquo;pretty; looks functional; how does it relate to other UN products, esp. the ones we&amp;rsquo;re paying for&amp;rdquo;. I sent those questions to the feedback address and Mr. Zoltan Nagy responded with the following helpful information. Thought I&amp;rsquo;d share in case others had the same questions&amp;hellip;
I took a long look at UNData the other day and came away thinking &amp;ldquo;pretty; looks functional; how does it relate to other UN products, esp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST 2008 - Call for Papers! </title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2007/10/29/iassist-2008-call-papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2007 13:21:34 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2007/10/29/iassist-2008-call-papers/</guid>
      <description>Technology of Data: Collection, Communication, Access and Preservation The 34th International Association for Social Science Information Services and Technology (IASSIST) annual conference will be held at the Stanford University, Palo Alto, California, USA, May 27-30, 2008. This year&amp;rsquo;s conference, Technology of Data: Collection, Communication, Access and Preservation, examines the role of technology and tools in various aspects of the data life cycle.
The theme of this conference addresses how technology can affect aspects of data stewardship throughout the data lifecycle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It is official!</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2007/07/27/it-official/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2007 11:40:35 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2007/07/27/it-official/</guid>
      <description>For those not familiar with the Web 2.0 numeric data utility Swivel - their mission &amp;ldquo;is to liberate the world&amp;rsquo;s data and make it useful so new insights can be discovered and shared&amp;rdquo;. However, it looks like Swivel are going official! Some NGOs are directly uploading their data into Swivel while in other cases Swivel are gathering data directly from &amp;lsquo;official&amp;rsquo; Web sites such as OECD, ILO, UNESCO, WHO - see http://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy (40th) Birthday UK Data Archive</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2007/07/12/happy-40th-birthday-uk-data-archive/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2007 07:50:46 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2007/07/12/happy-40th-birthday-uk-data-archive/</guid>
      <description>The UKDA celebrated its anniversary in style, with a reception at the Houses of Parliament in London on Wednesday, 10th July (2007), a forward-looking workshop in its new building at the University of Essex on the 11th, with a return of some familiar faces who have moved on to retirement or other fields. See press release at http://www.jisc.ac.uk/news/stories/2007/07/news_ukda.aspx The occasion called for reflection on the past, as the news story illuminates:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RIN Consultation paper on stewardship of research data</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2007/05/02/rin-consultation-paper-stewardship-research-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2007 12:01:54 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2007/05/02/rin-consultation-paper-stewardship-research-data/</guid>
      <description>The RIN (Research Information Network) has recently published a draft consultation paper - Stewardship of digital research data: a framework of principles and guidelines (April 2007) and are seeking feedback from practitioners.
The draft discusses the shared framework of principles and guidelines required for key stakeholders (researchers, research institutions, funding bodies, libraries, data managers, learned societies and publishers) in order to maximise the potential benefits of digital research data and to help ensure that &amp;lsquo;ideas and knowledge derived from publicly-funded research should be made available and accessible for public use, interrogation, and scrutiny, as widely, rapidly and effectively as practicable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wikipedia entry for Data Library - please help!</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2006/10/05/wikipedia-entry-data-library-please-help/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2006 12:14:19 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2006/10/05/wikipedia-entry-data-library-please-help/</guid>
      <description>Luis Martinez, IASSIST member and Data Librarian at the London School of Economics, has begun an entry on Wikipedia on the topic &amp;ldquo;Data Library&amp;rdquo;. Luis welcomes this community&amp;rsquo;s help in fleshing it out and providing more context. For those who have never been involved with Wikipedia, the editors come round and add comments, and often seem to judge the importance of an entry based on the number of people involved with &amp;lsquo;curating&amp;rsquo; it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What to do about data in old formats?</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2006/06/19/what-do-about-data-old-formats/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2006 14:41:16 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2006/06/19/what-do-about-data-old-formats/</guid>
      <description>Recently I posted a message to the IASSIST mailing list about a study in in the ICPSR Publication Related Archive that had a data file in an old (SST) statistical software format. I had no tools to convert or even read that file and was looking for a solution to get the data. I solved that problem through the kindness of the software producer who converted the file for me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Defining Data Librarian - call for comments</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2006/06/12/defining-data-librarian-call-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2006 09:19:45 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2006/06/12/defining-data-librarian-call-comments/</guid>
      <description>Tiffani Conner, Paula Lackie and Jen Darragh are working on the handouts for an ALA poster session and have found that defining &amp;ldquo;data&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;data librarian&amp;rdquo; clearly, in a concise manner, for a non-data audience is really hard. In addition, some of the sources they consulted (the Online Dictionary of Library and Information Science - ODLIS , Oxford English Dictionary ) were not adequate (ODLIS has data, data set, social science data set but the definitions are not that great).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metadata Musings from IASSIST 2006</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2006/05/25/metadata-musings-iassist-2006/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2006 11:54:42 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2006/05/25/metadata-musings-iassist-2006/</guid>
      <description>I will start with a disclaimer that I am not a metadata expert nor do I play one on TV but I have been spending a lot of time recently contemplating metadata issues. Granted they have been issues that deal with metadata in a time series world but it gave me an interesting frame of reference for attending several sessions on metadata-related issues. Here&amp;rsquo;s my thoughts:
After attending three and a half session exploring metadata issues, the one clear idea that has emerged is that there don&amp;rsquo;t seem to be any clear ideas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> New report on Eurostat and statistical integration</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2006/02/15/new-report-eurostat-and-statistical-integration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2006 11:39:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2006/02/15/new-report-eurostat-and-statistical-integration/</guid>
      <description>Title: Administering information: Eurostat and statistical integration
 The chapter examines developments and changes in the organization of numerical information in the EU, in particular the role of Eurostat, the statistical office of the European Commission. How and to what extent can we observe the emergence of a pan-European informational system?
 Full Text (PDF, 31 pages, 157.2 KB) http://www.arena.uio.no/publications/working-papers2005/papers/wp05_27.pdfTitle: Administering information: Eurostat and statistical integration
 Author: Ulf Sverdrup October 2005</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ESS wins prestigious Descartes prize</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2006/01/17/ess-wins-prestigious-descartes-prize/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2006 13:28:03 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2006/01/17/ess-wins-prestigious-descartes-prize/</guid>
      <description>The European Social Survey (ESS) has won the prestigious Descartes prize, awarded by the European Commission for &amp;ldquo;excellence in scientific research&amp;rdquo;. This is the first year that a social science project has won this prize. (from ESDS News)IASSIST-ers who attended the May 2005 conference in Edinburgh will remember the keynote speech by Roger Jowell, from the Centre for Comparative Social Surveys, City University, on &amp;lsquo;The Need for Rigour and Accessibility in Comparative Research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ICPSR to Participate in Project to Certify Digital Archives</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2005/09/15/icpsr-participate-project-certify-digital-archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2005 06:50:06 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2005/09/15/icpsr-participate-project-certify-digital-archives/</guid>
      <description>ICPSR will be taking part in the RLG-NARA Digital Repository Certification project to identify the criteria repositories must meet for reliably storing, migrating, and providing access to digital collections.ICPSR has been selected to serve as a &amp;ldquo;test subject&amp;rdquo; in the Center for Research Libraries (CRL) project to develop an audit checklist for certification of trusted digital repositories. Funded by the Mellon Foundation, this project builds on the work of a Task Force consisting of members from the Research Libraries Group (RLG) and the U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Practice of User Registration to Access Data</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2005/09/14/practice-user-registration-access-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2005 22:40:37 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2005/09/14/practice-user-registration-access-data/</guid>
      <description>I am writing to address an issue that is coming up at UCLA with increasing frequency. More and more data distributors (agencies, archives, individuals) require a user to &amp;ldquo;register&amp;rdquo; before downloading data from a web site. These registrations take many forms and there is a continuum in terms of levels of detail and responsibility assigned to the user. It makes it hard for me to be of service to users when each study requires every individual to perform the registration task.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data versus Conventional Wisdom: A Book Review</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2005/08/16/data-versus-conventional-wisdom-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2005 11:22:59 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2005/08/16/data-versus-conventional-wisdom-book-review/</guid>
      <description>Freakonomics by Steven Levitt and Stephen Dubner provides an economist&amp;rsquo;s analysis of some social issues not normally associated with economics, such as, the causes of crime, the impact of parenting on child development, and the power of information in combating racial discrimination. This review identifies four common themes running throughout the book and offers a critical assessment of the strenghts and weaknesses of this book from one data librarian&amp;rsquo;s perspective.Following the suggestion of two IASSIST friends, I added Freakonomics: A Rogue Economist Explores the Hidden Side of Everything by Steven Levitt and Stephan Dubner to my vacation reading list, although I must admit that this was the only non-mystery that I read this summer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST Members Participate in Social Science Week</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2005/06/27/iassist-members-participate-social-science-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2005 09:04:45 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2005/06/27/iassist-members-participate-social-science-week/</guid>
      <description>The ESRC Social Science Week was celebrated from June 20-24, 2005 in the UK. As part of the event, several specialists were invited to write articles about how the Internet has changed the ways in which research is done in the social sciences.
Three IASSIST members were the contributing authors on Wednesday, June 22nd, which had a focus on access to data. Alastair Allan wrote about e-government information and its challenges; Robin Rice addressed issues of access and the uses of open access publishing and digital repositories; and Melanie Wright described the many changes in delivering data using the Internet and this impact on data services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Report on Access to Scientific Research Data</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2005/06/21/report-access-scientific-research-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2005 00:32:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2005/06/21/report-access-scientific-research-data/</guid>
      <description>The final report of the Canadian National Consultation on Access to Scientific Research Data has just been released containing eighteen recommendations to improve open access to research data in Canada. While some of these recommendations are unique to the Canadian context, others share a close relationship with the recommendations of the International Council for Science report, Scientific Data and Information. Supported by the National Research Council of Canada, a task force was established in June 2004 to provide advice about improving access to scientific research data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Postmodern Values that Threaten National Data Archives</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2005/06/15/postmodern-values-threaten-national-data-archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2005 21:47:03 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2005/06/15/postmodern-values-threaten-national-data-archives/</guid>
      <description>Two sessions at the Edinburgh conference helped formulate in my mind some concerns that I have about the future of data archives. Together, the plenary session in which John Curtice described his research about postmodern values and Session G3 on Transforming Data Archives unified for me (i) ideas about anti-institutional values expressed in postmodernism and (ii) current organizational threats to data archives.
I have been troubled by the struggles we have confronted in Canada to establish a national institution to preserve data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discovering a Profession: the accidental data librarian</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2005/06/14/discovering-profession-accidental-data-librarian/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2005 12:28:24 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2005/06/14/discovering-profession-accidental-data-librarian/</guid>
      <description>A session at the Edinburgh conference addressed a topic that arose earlier in the year on the IASSIST email discussion list about how people prepare and enter the profession of data librarianship. In general, is there a profession of data librarianship?An interesting question was presented on the IASSIST email discussion list earlier this year asking how one becomes a data librarian. Several people replied by relating personal accounts about their entry into this profession.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to the IASSIST Communiqué</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2005/06/07/welcome-iassist-communiqu%C3%A9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2005 17:48:58 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2005/06/07/welcome-iassist-communiqu%C3%A9/</guid>
      <description>The IASSIST Communiqué is a place for discussions and news about all aspects of research data and the professionals responsible for collecting, preserving and providing access to such data. As such, this site welcomes comments on issues that promote preservation and access to data as well as material about best practices in data archiving and data services. While the content of this site does not necessarily represent official positions of IASSIST, we hope that the ideas in these discussions will provoke further debate and will eventually lead to positive outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>