<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sample plans on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </title>
    <link>https://talatera.github.io/tags/sample-plans/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sample plans on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 May 2011 07:52:03 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://talatera.github.io/tags/sample-plans/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Association of Research Libraries (ARL): The National Science Foundation (NSF) Data Sharing Policy: Resources for Data Management Planning</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/05/04/association-research-libraries-arl-national-science-foundation-nsf-data-sharing-policy-res/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2011 07:52:03 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/05/04/association-research-libraries-arl-national-science-foundation-nsf-data-sharing-policy-res/</guid>
      <description>The ARL NSF Resources for Data Management Planning pulls together resources for research libraries to support their researchers in complying with the NSF Data Sharing Policy. This portal represents a variety of sites containing examples, data management tools, and data repositories. Professionals can participate in ARL&amp;rsquo;s Group on Data Sharing Support.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yale University Office of Digital Assets and Infrastructure (ODAI): Data Management</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/30/yale-university-office-digital-assets-and-infrastructure-odai-data-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2011 00:37:58 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/30/yale-university-office-digital-assets-and-infrastructure-odai-data-management/</guid>
      <description>Yale University ODAI: Data Management provides researchers with reasons for, and resources to, manage their research data. Includes real case example data management plans from National Science Foundation (NSF) grant applications made by Yale University researchers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>University of Michigan Library: Research Data Management and Publishing Support</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/30/university-michigan-library-research-data-management-and-publishing-support/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2011 00:35:44 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/30/university-michigan-library-research-data-management-and-publishing-support/</guid>
      <description>University of Michigan Library: Research Data Management and Publishing Support contains resources for writing a data management plan, understanding and managing data, and using data in research. Its page on National Science Foundation (NSF) Data Management Plans provides guidance for preparing data management plans in compliance with NSF requirements for researchers, grant administrators and support staff. Contains real-case examples from various U.S. universities of actual submitted plans, as well as links to templates and tutorials.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataONE: Data Management Plans</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/30/dataone-data-management-plans/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2011 00:24:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/30/dataone-data-management-plans/</guid>
      <description>The DataONE Data Management Plans site describes the purpose of data management plans, with an outline plan and an example from environmental sciences. Information includes an overview of data management checklists currently in use across various organisations and support services, indicating common and unique topics across checklists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rural Economy and Land Use Programme (Relu): Data Management Planning</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/30/rural-economy-and-land-use-programme-relu-data-management-planning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2011 00:22:45 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/30/rural-economy-and-land-use-programme-relu-data-management-planning/</guid>
      <description>Relu&amp;rsquo;s Data Management Planning site has data management planning guidance, template and real-case examples of data management plans from the UK-based cross-disciplinary Rural Economy and Land Use Programme (social, environmental and biological sciences). Relu has its own data management and sharing policy and all funded projects are required to prepare a data management plan when they begin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Australian National Data Service (ANDS): Guide to Data Management Planning </title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/30/australian-national-data-service-ands-guide-data-management-planning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2011 00:14:46 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/30/australian-national-data-service-ands-guide-data-management-planning/</guid>
      <description>The ANDS: Guide to Data Management Planning from the Australian National Data Service offers generic guidance on data management planning aimed at all disciplines of research. The guidance gives a checklist of topics to include in a plan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>University of Minnesota Libraries: Managing Your Data</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/25/university-minnesota-libraries-managing-your-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2011 13:52:27 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/25/university-minnesota-libraries-managing-your-data/</guid>
      <description>The University of Minnesota Libraries: Managing Your Data site examines the research data lifecycle and offers tools and solutions for creation, storage, analysis, dissemination, and preservation of data. Includes an extensive list of funding agency guidelines and links to example data management plans.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ICPSR: Guidelines for Effective Data Management Plans</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/25/icpsr-guidelines-effective-data-management-plans/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2011 11:44:16 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/25/icpsr-guidelines-effective-data-management-plans/</guid>
      <description>The ICPSR Guidelines for Effective Data Management Plans provide a framework for creating a plan (including recommended elements), a list of sample data management plans in a range of disciplines, a list of U.S. federal agency policies, and links to resources.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>