<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Staying current on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </title>
    <link>https://talatera.github.io/tags/staying-current/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Staying current on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 May 2014 08:37:18 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://talatera.github.io/tags/staying-current/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>e-Science Portal for New England Librarians: Research Data Management Links</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2014/05/13/e-science-portal-new-england-librarians-research-data-management-links/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2014 08:37:18 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2014/05/13/e-science-portal-new-england-librarians-research-data-management-links/</guid>
      <description>e-Science Portal for New England Librarians has been gathering comprehensive resources links to keep librarians updated about e-Science issues and library&amp;rsquo;s new roles and functions. There is a &amp;ldquo;Data Management&amp;rdquo; section of the portal gathering publications, guides, tools, and other resources falling under the following general data management topics:
 Data Management Planning Research Data Cycles Data Curation Metadata Data Repositories   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Curation Bibliography, 2012</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2012/05/29/data-curation-bibliography-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2012 10:15:47 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2012/05/29/data-curation-bibliography-2012/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Digital Scholarship has released the Research Data Curation Bibliography. It includes over 100 selected English-language articles and technical reports that are useful in understanding the curation of digital research data in academic and other research institutions.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Most sources have been published from 2000 through 2011; however, a limited number of earlier key sources are also included.&amp;rdquo;
View the Data Curation Bibliography.
A number of IASSIST members are cited in the bibliography.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Association of Research Libraries (ARL): The National Science Foundation (NSF) Data Sharing Policy: Resources for Data Management Planning</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/05/04/association-research-libraries-arl-national-science-foundation-nsf-data-sharing-policy-res/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2011 07:52:03 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/05/04/association-research-libraries-arl-national-science-foundation-nsf-data-sharing-policy-res/</guid>
      <description>The ARL NSF Resources for Data Management Planning pulls together resources for research libraries to support their researchers in complying with the NSF Data Sharing Policy. This portal represents a variety of sites containing examples, data management tools, and data repositories. Professionals can participate in ARL&amp;rsquo;s Group on Data Sharing Support.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JISC: Research Data Management Discussion List</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/25/jisc-research-data-management-discussion-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2011 13:57:19 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/25/jisc-research-data-management-discussion-list/</guid>
      <description>The JISC Research Data Management Discussion List provides an international, multi-disciplinary forum for discussing research data management issues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supporting Data Management Infrastructure for the Humanities (Sudamih): Project Outputs</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/25/supporting-data-management-infrastructure-humanities-sudamih-project-outputs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2011 13:37:54 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/25/supporting-data-management-infrastructure-humanities-sudamih-project-outputs/</guid>
      <description>The Sudamih Project Outputs contains presentations and training materials on data management. Includes a bibliography on data management (PDF) covering topics such as policy issues, data sharing, digital curation and preservation, repositories, metadata, and personal information management.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DATUM for Health: Research Data Management Training Search Engine</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/25/datum-health-research-data-management-training-search-engine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2011 13:19:32 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/25/datum-health-research-data-management-training-search-engine/</guid>
      <description>DATUM for Health&amp;rsquo;s Research Data Management Training Search Engine is a customised Google search engine that contains web items (sites and documents) identified in a tailored literature review. Sources cover: research data management training, other relevant training, and content that would be useful as course materials or background reading.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Curation Centre (DCC)</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/25/digital-curation-centre-dcc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2011 12:01:53 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/25/digital-curation-centre-dcc/</guid>
      <description>The Digital Curation Centre is a hub of expertise in curating digital research data. It sponsors events, projects, and fora for communication, and maintains an extensive set of online resources, including its Curation Reference Manual. Includes page on data management plans which outlines UK research funder data planning and sharing policies.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>