<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Research Data Management on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </title>
    <link>https://talatera.github.io/tags/research-data-management/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Research Data Management on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2016 05:18:11 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://talatera.github.io/tags/research-data-management/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>IQ 40:1 Now Available!</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2016/09/20/iq-401-now-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2016 05:18:11 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2016/09/20/iq-401-now-available/</guid>
      <description>Our World and all the Local Worlds Welcome to the first issue of Volume 40 of the IASSIST Quarterly (IQ 40:1, 2016). We present four papers in this issue. The first paper presents data from our very own world, extracted from papers published in the IQ through four decades. What is published in the IQ is often limited in geographical scope and in this issue the other three papers present investigations and project research carried out at New York University, Purdue University, and the Federal Reserve System.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST 2016 Program At-A-Glance, Part 2: Data infrastructure, data processing and research data management</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2016/05/06/iassist-2016-program-glance-part-2-data-infrastructure-data-processing-and-research-data-manage/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2016 07:13:42 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2016/05/06/iassist-2016-program-glance-part-2-data-infrastructure-data-processing-and-research-data-manage/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s another list of highlights from IASSIST2016 which is focusing on the data revolution. For previous highlights, see here.
Infrastructure  For those of you with an interest in technical infrastructure, the University of Applied Sciences HTW Chur will showcase an early protype MMRepo (1 June, 3F), whose function is to store qualitative and quantitative data into one big data repository.   The UK Data Service will present the following panel &amp;ldquo;The CESSDA Technical Framework - what is it and why is it needed?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Latest Issue of IQ Available!  Data Documentation Initiative - Results, Tools, and  Further Initiatives </title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2016/03/24/latest-issue-iq-available-data-documentation-initiative-results-tools-and-further-initiatives/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2016 07:09:42 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2016/03/24/latest-issue-iq-available-data-documentation-initiative-results-tools-and-further-initiatives/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to thethird issue of Volume 39 of the IASSIST Quarterly (IQ 39:3, 2015). This special issue is guest edited by Joachim Wackerow of GESIS &amp;ndash; Leibniz Institute for the Social Sciences in Germany and Mary Vardigan of ICPSR at the University of Michigan, USA. That sentence is a direct plagiarism from the editor&amp;rsquo;s notes of the recent double issue (IQ 38:4 &amp;amp; 39:1). We are very grateful for all the work Mary and Achim have carried out and are developing further in the continuing story of the Data Documentation Initiative (DDI), and for their efforts in presenting the work here in the ASSIST Quarterly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking Back/Moving Forward - Reflections on the First Ten Years of Open Repositories</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2015/07/03/reflections-on-first-ten-years-of-open-repositories/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2015 01:15:01 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2015/07/03/reflections-on-first-ten-years-of-open-repositories/</guid>
      <description>Open Repositories conference celebrated its first decade by having four full days of exciting workshops, keynotes, sessions, 24/7 talks, and development track and repository interest group sessions in Indianapolis, USA. All the fun took place in the second week of June. The OR2015 conference was themed &amp;ldquo;Looking Back/Moving Forward: Open Repositories at the Crossroads&amp;rdquo; and it brought over 400 repository developers and managers, librarians and library IT professionals, service providers and other experts to hot and humid Indy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Before anything else, preparation is the key to success.&#34; Notes from RDMF13: Preparing Data for Deposit</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2015/05/01/anything-else-preparation-key-success-notes-rdmf13-preparing-data-deposit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 08:59:18 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2015/05/01/anything-else-preparation-key-success-notes-rdmf13-preparing-data-deposit/</guid>
      <description>The Digital Curation Centre&amp;rsquo;s most recent Research Data Management Forum took place last week in London.
UK Data Service&amp;rsquo;s Louise Corti began the day with an overview of their acquisitions process. The Service (under various names) is almost 50 years old that gives it experience and perspective many institutions do not have. Lessons from those years include the importance of a collections development policy that&amp;rsquo;s allowed to evolve. The Archive evaluates on a basis of teaching and re-use for validation and replication.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring forward! The Jisc Research Data Spring programme</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2015/03/02/spring-forward-jisc-research-data-spring-programme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2015 07:04:10 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2015/03/02/spring-forward-jisc-research-data-spring-programme/</guid>
      <description>On 26/27 February, I attended Jisc Data Spring &amp;ldquo;Sandpit 1&amp;rdquo; in the English city of Birmingham. Data Spring is a funding programme supporting UK based projects in Research Data Management (RDM), and something of a successor to the successful Managing Research Data programmes (MRD) that did so much to get RDM training and tools underway in the UK&amp;rsquo;s education sector.
Unlike the traditional proposal-evaluation-funding model, Data Spring takes a more collaborative, interactive approach, splitting the programme into separate stages at which projects may no longer receive funding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A decade against decay: the 10th International Digital Curation Conference</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2015/02/17/decade-against-decay-10th-international-digital-curation-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2015 05:34:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2015/02/17/decade-against-decay-10th-international-digital-curation-conference/</guid>
      <description>The International Digital Curation Conference (IDCC) is now ten years old. On the evidence of its most recent conference, is in rude health and growing fast.
IDCC is the first time IASSIST decided to formally support another organisational conference. I think it was a wise investment given the quality of plenaries, presentations, posters, and discussions.
DCC already has available a number of blogs covering the substance of sessions, including an excellent summary by IASSIST web editor, Robin Rice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hallelujah and praise the LARD! The first London Area Research Data group meeting</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2014/11/10/hallelujah-and-praise-lard-first-london-area-research-data-group-meeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2014 05:22:34 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2014/11/10/hallelujah-and-praise-lard-first-london-area-research-data-group-meeting/</guid>
      <description>LARD is London Area Research Data and this was its inaugural meeting, informally bringing together various people from London based institutions (and as far away as Reading) who are charged in some way with Research Data Management (RDM) - be it research support or repository work.
These are my notes, which lack attribution partly because I couldn&amp;rsquo;t remember where every person was from, and also it wasn&amp;rsquo;t clear if the meeting was on or off the record.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST SIGDMC Annual Report 2013-2014</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2014/05/30/iassist-sigdmc-annual-report-2013-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2014 09:57:31 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2014/05/30/iassist-sigdmc-annual-report-2013-2014/</guid>
      <description>By Carol Perry &amp;amp; Stefan Kramer, co-chairs Last updated: 2014-05-29 by CP
  The major activity of the Data Management &amp;amp; Curation Interest Group (SIGDMC) in the last year was the conceptualization, organization, submission, and offering of the June 2, 2014, morning workshop Data Management &amp;amp; Curation: Lessons from Government, Academia, and Research. It features seven invited presenters, and session and breakout group moderators from the SIGDMC membership, which also provided input on the breakout group topics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Data Management Issues Across Environments</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2014/05/29/research-data-management-issues-across-environments/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2014 07:19:01 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2014/05/29/research-data-management-issues-across-environments/</guid>
      <description>Lots of conversations going on these days in different venues where people are asking many of the same questions: how do we teach researchers about data management with limited staff, and what data management services should we offer? How do we find sustainable ways to manage data that leverage the efforts of many different repositories, those in government, institutions and disciplinary ones? How do we coalesce standard practice and reasonable but effective policies at at least the national level and preferably on a global scale?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST Africa Regional Report 2013-2014</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2014/05/16/iassist-africa-regional-report-2013-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2014 06:26:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2014/05/16/iassist-africa-regional-report-2013-2014/</guid>
      <description>Freeing African Data Two regional developments have the potential to get African government data into the public domain. Putting their disaggregated data out there can benefit African governance through ensuring transparency and allowing feedback from policy analysis to support better government planning. The World Bank&amp;rsquo;s Central microdata catalog has been around since 2012 and continues to expand its listing of data sources. This is currently the only comprehensive online source for microdata produced by African official data producers, as a listing of country datasets is not available on most African government websites.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feedback on Data Storage</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2014/02/06/feedback-data-storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2014 13:35:13 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2014/02/06/feedback-data-storage/</guid>
      <description>I posted the following question to the listserv:
&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m in the early days of exploring what I and our library can do for our faculty and grad students. In my case I&amp;rsquo;m particularity interested in the social sciences.
It seems there are three main choices:
  ICPSR(or other domain-specific site)
  Dataverse with my own school&amp;rsquo;s branding
  Local, campus funded storage through an Institutional Repository or something else that can handle larger amounts of data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>re3data.org and OpenAIRE sign MoU during Open Access Week; new re3data.org features</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/11/13/re3dataorg-and-openaire-sign-mou-during-open-access-week-new-re3dataorg-features/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2013 15:06:16 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/11/13/re3dataorg-and-openaire-sign-mou-during-open-access-week-new-re3dataorg-features/</guid>
      <description>Last month, OpenAIRE (Open Access Infrastructure for Research in Europe) and re3data.org signed a Memorandum of Agreement to &amp;ldquo;work jointly to facilitate research data registration, discovery, access and re-use&amp;rdquo; in support of open science. OpenAIRE is an infrastructure for open access that works to track and measure research output (originally designed to monitor EU funding activities). re3data.org is an online listing of research data repositories.
re3data.org and OpenAIRE will exchange metadata in order for OpenAIRE to &amp;ldquo;integrate data repositories indexed in the re3data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Registration for the Data Information Literacy Symposium is now open</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/05/22/registration-data-information-literacy-symposium-now-open/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2013 04:46:58 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/05/22/registration-data-information-literacy-symposium-now-open/</guid>
      <description>Please join us for the Data Information Literacy Symposium at Purdue University in West Lafayette, IN, on September 23rd, and 24th 2013. Program: This symposium will explore roles for practicing librarians in teaching competencies in data management and curation to graduate students. With support from the Institute of Museum and Library Services, librarians from Purdue University, Cornell University, the University of Minnesota and the University of Oregon have investigated this topic through developing and implementing &amp;ldquo;data information literacy&amp;rdquo; (DIL) instruction programs for graduate students in a range of science and engineering disciplines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST Fellows 2013</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/05/06/iassist-fellows-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2013 19:38:07 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/05/06/iassist-fellows-2013/</guid>
      <description>** **
The IASSIST Fellows Committee is glad to announce through this post the six recipients of the 2013 IASSIST Fellowship award. We are extremely excited to have such a diverse and interesting group with different backgrounds and experience and encourage IASSISTers to welcome them at our conference in Cologne, Germany.
Please find below their names, countries and brief bios:
**Chifundo Kanjala (Tanzania) **
Chifundo currently works as a Data Manager and data documentalist for an HIV research group called ALPHA network based at London School of Hygiene and Tropical Medicine&amp;rsquo;s department of Population Health, Chifundo spends most of his time in Mwanza, Tanzania but do travel from time around Southern and Eastern Africa to work with colleagues in the ALPHA network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSISTers and librarians are doin&#39; it for themselves</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/04/02/iassisters-and-librarians-are-doin-it-themselves/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 11:37:29 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/04/02/iassisters-and-librarians-are-doin-it-themselves/</guid>
      <description>Hey IASSISTers (gents, pardon for the video pun - couldnt&amp;rsquo; resist),
Are librarians at your institutions struggling to get up to speed with research data management (RDM)? If they&amp;rsquo;re not, they probably should be. Library organisations are publishing reports and issuing recommendations left and right, such as the LIBER (Association of European Research Libraries) 2012 report, &amp;ldquo;Ten Recommendations for Libraries to Get Started with Research Data Management&amp;rdquo; (PDF). Just last week Nature published an article highlighting what the Great and the Good are doing in this area: Publishing Frontiers: The Library Reboot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update from COSSA: Changes to the Common Rule: The Implications for the Social and Behavioral Sciences</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/03/25/update-cossa-changes-common-rule-implications-social-and-behavioral-sciences/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 14:34:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/03/25/update-cossa-changes-common-rule-implications-social-and-behavioral-sciences/</guid>
      <description>This is from the COSSA Newsletter ([Consortium of Social Science Associations).]{.st} March 25, 2013 Volume 32, Issue 6 Regarding a workshop on proposed changes to the Common Rule. Readers of these blog entries will recall that these proposed changes would require that data identitified in social science research would be required to meet HIPPA standards; potentially rendering many public datasets unuseful for research purposes.
A link to the webcast is here: http://sites.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some reflections on research data confidentiality, privacy, and curation by Limor Peer</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/03/07/some-reflections-research-data-confidentiality-privacy-and-curation-limor-peer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2013 11:43:38 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/03/07/some-reflections-research-data-confidentiality-privacy-and-curation-limor-peer/</guid>
      <description>Some reflections on research data confidentiality, privacy, and curation
Limor Peer
Maintaining research subjects&amp;rsquo; confidentiality is an essential feature of the scientific research enterprise. It also presents special challenges to the data curation process. Does the effort to open access to research data complicate these challenges?
A few reasons why I think it does: More data are discoverable and could be used to re-identify previously de-identified datasets; systems are increasingly interoperable, potentially bridging what may have been insular academic data with other data and information sources; growing pressure to open data may weaken some of the safeguards previously put in place; and some data are inherently identifiable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>North American DDI Conference April 2013</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/01/23/north-american-ddi-conference-april-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 14:30:08 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/01/23/north-american-ddi-conference-april-2013/</guid>
      <description>Registration is now open for NADDI 2013 (http://www.ipsr.ku.edu/naddi/). The North American Data Documentation Initiative Conference (NADDI) is an opportunity for those using DDI and those interested in learning more about it to come together and learn from each other. Patterned after the successful European DDI conference (EDDI), NADDI 2013 will be a two day conference with invited and contributed presentations. This conference should be of interest to both researchers and data professionals in the social sciences and other disciplines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Denton Declaration: An Open Data Manifesto</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/01/02/denton-declaration-open-data-manifesto/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2013 08:46:40 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/01/02/denton-declaration-open-data-manifesto/</guid>
      <description>On May 22, 2012 at the University of North Texas (UNT), a group of technologists, librarians, scholars, researchers, university administrators, and other stakeholders gathered to discuss and articulate best practices and emerging trends in research data management. This declaration bridges the converging interests of these stakeholders and promotes collaboration, transparency, and accountability across organizational and disciplinary boundaries. Declarations that emerged included the following:
 Open access to research data is critical for advancing science, scholarship, and society.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>