<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tools and Apps on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </title>
    <link>https://talatera.github.io/tags/tools-and-apps/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tools and Apps on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2014 08:43:56 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://talatera.github.io/tags/tools-and-apps/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistical Associates Publishing</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2014/06/16/statistical-associates-publishing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2014 08:43:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2014/06/16/statistical-associates-publishing/</guid>
      <description>Statistical Associates Publishing is a website that offers guides focused primarily on correctly executing various statistical techniques. The guides are short and provide screenshots and step-by-step instructions for for some of the major commercial statistical packages. One can buy the books - each at very low prices $5USD or less per book from Amazon - or request a free copy from the publisher with some reasonable restrictions on use.
I should note that since I don&amp;rsquo;t spend much time doing statistics myself, I feel a bit unqualified to attest to the quality of the materials.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Informal Review of Thomson-Reuters Data Citation Index</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2014/04/16/informal-review-thomson-reuters-data-citation-index/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2014 10:34:55 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2014/04/16/informal-review-thomson-reuters-data-citation-index/</guid>
      <description>The Thomson-Reuters Data Citation Index (DCI) has been up and running for just over a year. The University of Minnesota (UMN) had a trial of the database when the DCI first launched, but because so little of the database was populated at that time, it was hard to assess it completely. We felt that after a year, it would be worthwhile to revisit it. The initial annual subscrption prices were significant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DDI-XSLT -transform you DDI to XHTML, MARC, PDF</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/07/04/ddi-xslt-transform-you-ddi-xhtml-marc-pdf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2013 03:08:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/07/04/ddi-xslt-transform-you-ddi-xhtml-marc-pdf/</guid>
      <description>With DDI-XSLT you can tranform your DDI-lifeccle XML to other formats including:
 DDI 1.2.2 (nesstar) XHTML MARC-XML Datacite metadata PDF codebooks  Demo site for transformations Google code page</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The R Guide to ESDS Large-Scale Government Surveys</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2012/06/15/r-guide-esds-large-scale-government-surveys/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2012 03:47:07 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2012/06/15/r-guide-esds-large-scale-government-surveys/</guid>
      <description>ESDS Government has produced a new guide, The R Guide to ESDS Large-Scale Government Surveys. The aim of this guide is to provide an introduction to analysing large scale government surveys with the help of the R statistical software package. The guide focuses on providing step-by-step examples of common operations most users carry out in the course of their research: how to open data sets, do basic data manipulation operations, produce simple descriptive statistics or weighted contingency tables.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Podcast about &#34;Numeric data services and sources for the general reference librarian&#34; by Lynda Kellam &amp; Katharin Peter</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/10/06/podcast-about-numeric-data-services-and-sources-general-reference-librarian-lynda-kellam-k/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2011 09:35:16 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/10/06/podcast-about-numeric-data-services-and-sources-general-reference-librarian-lynda-kellam-k/</guid>
      <description>Lynda Kellam &amp;amp; Katharin Peter, two IASSIST members, recently published their book on how to be a data librarian:
Kellam, L. M., &amp;amp; Peter, K. (2011). Numeric data services and sources for the general reference librarian. Oxford: Chandos Publishing. Earlier this summer, Lynda discussed the book, data, data literacy and instruction with the folks at &amp;ldquo;Adventures in Library Instruction&amp;rdquo;.
Highly recommended!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>US Department of Labor Tools for Application Development</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/07/18/us-department-labor-tools-application-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2011 07:39:58 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/07/18/us-department-labor-tools-application-development/</guid>
      <description>From the US Department of Labor&amp;rsquo;s developer.dol.gov website comes an initial set of datasets and mobile SDKs to support the creation of 3rd party interfaces for Department of Labor data.
To use the data, you need to go to https://webapps.dol.gov/developer to register and get keys for the data. In the initial offering are  DOL FORM Dataset DOL FAQ Dataset DOL MSPA Dataset  DOL Safety &amp;amp; Health Dataset (Chemical Exposure Health Data)  BLS 2010 Occupation Employment Statistics Dataset  DOL Compliance-OSHA Dataset  DOL Compliance-WHD Dataset  DOL Agency Dataset  Geography Dataset   The Department of Labor has also released SDKs for all of the major mobile platforms:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geospatial Data Preservation Resource Center</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/06/21/geospatial-data-preservation-resource-center/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2011 07:53:59 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/06/21/geospatial-data-preservation-resource-center/</guid>
      <description>A new Web site, the Geospatial Data Preservation Resource Center, aims to help those responsible for producing and managing geospatial data learn about the latest approaches and tools available to facilitate long-term geospatial data preservation and access. The Web site provides descriptions and links for a variety of relevant resources, including education and training modules, useful tools and software, information on policies and standards for preserving geospatial data, and examples of successful preservation and associated benefits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>World Bank Results At A Glance - iPhone/iPad/iPod Touch</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/20/world-bank-results-glance-iphoneipadipod-touch/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2011 13:47:50 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/20/world-bank-results-glance-iphoneipadipod-touch/</guid>
      <description>The World Bank has developed an iPhone/iPad/etc application called &amp;ldquo;World Bank Results at a Glance&amp;quot;. These results are indicators related to either UN Millenium Development Goals (where the World Bank has partnered with the UN) or outcomes from exclusively World Bank projects.
The application has 450 indicators for 85 countries. Users can
 Search and browse over 450 results profiles by country name or coordinates more than 30 topics over 300 keywords, including &amp;ldquo;roads,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;food security,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;job creation,&amp;rdquo; and more Millennium Development Goals Save and share stories View a graphic timeline of key World Bank results and milestones Read relevant background about the World Bank&amp;rsquo;s results initiatives See Frequently Asked Questions (FAQs) about the Bank itself, shedding light on the modern workings of the institution Gain access to multiple PDFs in multiple languages related to quick results facts, country statistics, and background on the Bank&amp;rsquo;s initiatives, all exportable to iBooks View project images and videos  This tool joins three other World Bank applications which cover indicators (DataFinder), nformation (InfoFinder) and doing business around the world (Doing Business at a Glance).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>United States National Center for Education Statistics DataLab</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2010/08/02/united-states-national-center-education-statistics-datalab/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2010 09:36:52 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2010/08/02/united-states-national-center-education-statistics-datalab/</guid>
      <description>The National Center for Education Statistics&amp;rsquo; (NCES) Datalab, introduced earlier this year by the United States Department of Education, provides a user-friendly entry to NCES data. The home page, linked above, links to
 QuickStats for users of summary data needing quick tables or charts (requires click-through agreement to terms of use) PowerStats for users of microdata needing to run linear and logistic regressions (requires free user registration) Library for users looking for prepared summary tables Links to the Restricted-Use Data Procedures Manual  NCES also promises to soon make available tables already created via the QuickStats and PowerStats tools which would be potentially the most powerful aspect of the Datalab.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OECD Factbook 2010 for iPhone</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2010/08/02/oecd-factbook-2010-iphone/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2010 09:24:13 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2010/08/02/oecd-factbook-2010-iphone/</guid>
      <description>The OECD has created an iPhone app for the OECD Factbook. From the site &amp;ldquo;The OECD Factbook App presents 100 economic indicators in a format specially designed for your iPhone. Now, wherever you are, you have easy access to a comprehensive statistical picture of the world&amp;rsquo;s major economies from the most reliable source: OECD.
The OECD Factbook is organised around 12 themes such as population and migration, macroeconomic trends, and globalization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualize It! with IMF Data Mapper</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2010/05/02/visualize-it-imf-data-mapper/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2010 14:58:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2010/05/02/visualize-it-imf-data-mapper/</guid>
      <description>The IMF Data Mapper lets you visualize data from some of the IMF&amp;rsquo;s major sources, includingWorld Economic Outlook, Balance of Payment Statistics, Government Finance Statistics, AFR Regional Economic Outlook, and Joint IMF-OECD Statistics. You can choose from around 80 different indicators, such as GDP, inflation rate or unemployment rate. You can display data for specific countries, regions, or analytical groups, such as the Euro area or emerging and developing economies.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>