<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>IASSIST Conferences on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </title>
    <link>https://talatera.github.io/tags/iassist-conferences/</link>
    <description>Recent content in IASSIST Conferences on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 07:24:51 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://talatera.github.io/tags/iassist-conferences/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>New to IASSIST or Willing to Mentor Someone New?</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2018/05/15/new-iassist-or-willing-mentor-someone-new-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 07:24:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2018/05/15/new-iassist-or-willing-mentor-someone-new-0/</guid>
      <description>New to IASSIST or Willing to Mentor Someone New?
 Please sign up by Thursday, May 17. Conference contact assignments for IASSIST will be emailed by the end of the day Monday, May 21.
  Please fill out in Google forms: https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLScyW2B9m8o5-6Z0D0FPdsTcqkOpUDk_w_u4WwuyIpDWgjAQJQ/viewform Looking forward to the best IASSIST ever! Bobray Bordelon bordelon@Princeton.edu IASSIST 2018 Mentor Coordinator</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST &amp; CARTO 2018 CALL FOR PROPOSALS</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2017/10/23/iassist-carto-2018-call-proposals-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 08:33:46 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2017/10/23/iassist-carto-2018-call-proposals-0/</guid>
      <description>Conference website: http://www.library.mcgill.ca/iassistcarto2018/
Conference hashtag: #iassistcarto
The 44th annual conference of the International Association for Social Science Information Services and Technology (IASSIST) will be jointly held with the 52nd annual conference of the Association of Canadian Map Libraries and Archives (ACMLA-ACACC) in Montréal, Québec, Canada from May 29-June 1, 2018.
Once Upon a Data Point: Sustaining our Data Storytellers
In many ways, researchers are data storytellers: they create compelling data-supported narratives for examining both historical and current social phenomena and for facilitating social change and reconciliation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New to IASSIST or Willing to Mentor Someone New? (IASSIST 2017 Conference)</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2017/05/08/new-iassist-or-willing-mentor-someone-new-iassist-2017-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 09:19:24 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2017/05/08/new-iassist-or-willing-mentor-someone-new-iassist-2017-conference/</guid>
      <description>New to IASSIST or Willing to Mentor Someone New?
We are excited to have new members in IASSIST. IASSIST is a home for data services professionals across many disciplines: librarians, data archivists, open data proponents, data support staff, etc. For some, it is an organization where you don&amp;rsquo;t have to explain what you do because our members already understand. We get metadata, data support, data access issues, database challenges, the challenge of replication and so much more!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST&#39;s Statement in Response to President’s Executive Order on Visas and Immigration</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2017/02/13/iassists-statement-response-presidents-executive-order-visas-and-immigration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2017 12:00:31 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2017/02/13/iassists-statement-response-presidents-executive-order-visas-and-immigration/</guid>
      <description>February 13, 2017
Statement of the International Association for Social Science Information Services and Technology (IASSIST at http://iassistdata.org) in response to President Trump&amp;rsquo;s January 27 Executive Order on Visas and Immigration, titled &amp;ldquo;PROTECTING THE NATION FROM FOREIGN TERRORIST ENTRY INTO THE UNITED STATES&amp;rdquo;.
The recent executive order on visas and immigration issued on January 27th by US President Trump is of grave concern to IASSIST as an organization. IASSIST, the International Association for Social Science Information Services and Technology, is an international organization of professionals working in and with information technology, libraries, data services and research &amp;amp; higher education to support open science, advocate for responsible data management and use, build a broader community surrounding research data, and encourage the development of data professionals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST 2017 Call for Proposals Now Open!</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2016/10/17/iassist-2017-call-proposals-now-open/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2016 05:40:20 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2016/10/17/iassist-2017-call-proposals-now-open/</guid>
      <description>We are delighted to announce the call for proposals for the IASSIST 2017 Conference.  IASSIST 2017 CALL FOR PROPOSALS Data in the Middle: The common language of research The 43rd annual conference of the International Association for Social Science Information Services and Technology (IASSIST) will be held in Lawrence, Kansas from May 23-26, 2017. #iassist17
Many issues around data (sources, strategies, and tools) are similar across disciplines. While IASSIST has its roots in social science data, it has also welcomed discussions over the years of other disciplines&amp;rsquo; issues as they relate to data, data management, and support of users.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST 2016 Program At-A-Glance, Part 2: Data infrastructure, data processing and research data management</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2016/05/06/iassist-2016-program-glance-part-2-data-infrastructure-data-processing-and-research-data-manage/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2016 07:13:42 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2016/05/06/iassist-2016-program-glance-part-2-data-infrastructure-data-processing-and-research-data-manage/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s another list of highlights from IASSIST2016 which is focusing on the data revolution. For previous highlights, see here.
Infrastructure  For those of you with an interest in technical infrastructure, the University of Applied Sciences HTW Chur will showcase an early protype MMRepo (1 June, 3F), whose function is to store qualitative and quantitative data into one big data repository.   The UK Data Service will present the following panel &amp;ldquo;The CESSDA Technical Framework - what is it and why is it needed?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interested in the “data revolution” and what it means for research? Here’s why you should attend IASSIST2016</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2016/05/03/interested-in-the-data-revolution-and-what-it-means-for-research-heres-why-you-should-attend-iassist2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2016 02:15:18 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2016/05/03/interested-in-the-data-revolution-and-what-it-means-for-research-heres-why-you-should-attend-iassist2016/</guid>
      <description>Part 1: Data sharing, new data sources and data protection IASSIST is an international organisation of information technology and data services professionals which aims to provide support to research and teaching in the social sciences. It has over 300 members ranging from data archive staff and librarians to statistical agencies, government departments and non-profit organisations.
The theme of this year&amp;rsquo;s conference is &amp;ldquo;Embracing the &amp;lsquo;data revolution&amp;rsquo;: opportunities and challenges for research&amp;rdquo; and it is the 42nd of its kind, taking place every year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST 2014 Conference Submission Deadline EXTENDED to December 20</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/12/10/iassist-2014-conference-submission-deadline-extended-december-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2013 09:27:54 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/12/10/iassist-2014-conference-submission-deadline-extended-december-20/</guid>
      <description>By popular request (and due to the tight holiday schedule this year), the IASSIST 2014 Conference Programme Committee has extended the conference submission deadline!
Submissions for all formats are now due December 20, 2013.
Thank you for all of your submissions to date, we look forward to the review.
Please let us know if you have any questions - email.
Best,
[](mailto:iassist40@gmail.com%3EIASSIST%2040%3C/a%3E%3Cspan%20style=)
Program Chairs
Jen Green Johan Fihn Chuck Humphrey</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST 2014 Call for Papers</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/11/14/iassist-2014-call-papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2013 11:12:10 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/11/14/iassist-2014-call-papers/</guid>
      <description>ALIGNING DATA AND RESEARCH INFRASTRUCTURE IASSIST 2014 Annual Conference Call for Paper and Session Proposals This year&amp;rsquo;s conference theme touches upon the international and interdisciplinary requirements of aligning data and research infrastructure. The 2013 OECD Global Science Forum report on New Data for Understanding the Human Condition identifies key challenges for international data collaboration that beg for new solutions. Among these challenges is the mounting pressure for new forms of social science data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST 2013 - Early bird registration rates until April 30!</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/04/18/iassist-2013-early-bird-registration-rates-until-april-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2013 13:38:58 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/04/18/iassist-2013-early-bird-registration-rates-until-april-30/</guid>
      <description>GESIS &amp;ndash; Leibniz Institute for the Social Sciences is proud to host the IASSIST 2013 Conference at Maternushaus in Cologne, Germany from May 28-31. The IASSIST 2013 theme is Data Innovation: Increasing Accessibility, Visibility and Sustainability. In line with the theme, the IASSIST Program is streamed into three tracks this year: Research Data Management, Data Developers and Tools and Data Public Services. Presentations cover topics such as standards and processes in data management, metadata extensions and tools, data citation practices, sensitive data and much more!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>40 years of IASSIST Conferences: Toronto to host IASSIST 2014</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/01/18/40-years-iassist-conferences-toronto-host-iassist-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2013 06:33:52 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/01/18/40-years-iassist-conferences-toronto-host-iassist-2014/</guid>
      <description>IASSIST Members,
I&amp;rsquo;m pleased to announce that IASSIST&amp;rsquo;s 40th anniversary conference in 2014 has been awarded to the city where it all started - Toronto, Canada!
Come join us to celebrate June 3-6, 2014, where local hosts from Ryerson University, the University of Toronto, and York University are looking forward to quoting Tourism Toronto&amp;rsquo;s greeting of &amp;ldquo;Welcome to Toronto! We&amp;rsquo;ve been expecting you!&amp;rdquo;
Meanwhile, our friends at GESIS - Leibniz Institute for the Social Sciences are gearing up to host IASSIST 2013 in Cologne, Germany from May 28 &amp;ndash;31.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST Fellows Application Form 2013</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2012/12/04/iassist-fellows-application-form-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2012 04:03:25 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2012/12/04/iassist-fellows-application-form-2013/</guid>
      <description>The IASSIST Fellows Program is pleased to announce that it is now accepting applications for financial support to attend the IASSIST 2013 conference in Cologne [http://www.iassist2013.org/], from data professionals who are developing, supporting and managing data infrastructures at their home institutions.
It should be noted that funding is not intended to cover the entire cost of attending the conference and that the applicant&amp;rsquo;s home institution must provide some level of financial support to supplement an IASSIST Fellow award.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Accepting Proposals for IASSIST 2013</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2012/11/01/now-accepting-proposals-iassist-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 08:14:09 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2012/11/01/now-accepting-proposals-iassist-2013/</guid>
      <description>IASSIST 2013 will be hosted by GESIS &amp;ndash; Leibniz Institute for the Social Sciences at Maternushaus in Cologne, Germany from May 28-31.
The Conference Website can be accessed here: http://www.iassist2013.org/iassist-2013-home/
As announced previously, the theme of this year&amp;rsquo;s conference is Data Innovation: Increasing Accessibility, Visibility and Sustainability
This theme reflects recent efforts across the globe by the largest government agencies down to the smaller independent research units to make data (be it survey, administrative, geospatial, or scientific) more open, accessible and understandable for all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>- Friday posting - </title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2012/09/07/friday-posting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2012 15:46:40 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2012/09/07/friday-posting/</guid>
      <description>One of the highlights of the after hours hanging out during IASSIST conferences is getting to play some pool and make geeky data jokes you don&amp;rsquo;t have to explain to anyone. For you pool-playing enthusiasts, I sharethis YouTube of a potential future IASSIST conference goer .. (note, none of us can play anywhere near the level of this 5 yr old.) Happy Weekend everyone! </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Videos from the  IASSIST 2011 Plenaries </title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/06/24/videos-iassist-2011-plenaries/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2011 09:21:28 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/06/24/videos-iassist-2011-plenaries/</guid>
      <description>Hello - for those who were not able to attend IASSIST 2011 and for those asking to have access to video presentations, the two videos of the Plenaries from IASSIST 2011 are now available for viewing:
Research Data Infrastructure: Are the Social Sciences on Main Street or a Side Road?   Chuck Humphrey - Data Library Coordinator, University of Alberta   Chuck Humphrey is passionate about data and has been examining research data infrastructure with a global perspective.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Look for Past Conferences Web Pages</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/02/28/new-look-past-conferences-web-pages/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 11:47:58 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/02/28/new-look-past-conferences-web-pages/</guid>
      <description>We are pleased to present the new layout for the Past Conferences section of the website. Follow the [presentations] links for 2009 and 2010 to see the new layout. Past conference pages from 2000 to 2008 will be converted in the weeks to come. All presentations since 2000 have now been preserved in pdf format to ensure future access to the files.
Thanks go out to the webteam for their hard work in making this possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Torture, Numbers, and Digital Tape</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/02/02/torture-numbers-and-digital-tape/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2011 07:02:15 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/02/02/torture-numbers-and-digital-tape/</guid>
      <description>The IASSIST Quarterly (IQ) volume 33 number 3 is now on the web:
[http://iassistdata.org/iq/issue/33/3]
With this issue concentrating on quantitative investigations and the use of statistics, I came to think of the Mark Twain citation &amp;ldquo;There are three kinds of lies: lies, damned lies, and statistics.&amp;rdquo; With the violent title of the first article (see below), the article on numbers and statistics, and the report from a national statistics agency, the &amp;ldquo;Torture,Numbers, and Digital Tape&amp;rdquo; title surfaced.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Special IQ: Moving Research Data Into and Out of Institutional Repositories</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2009/05/12/special-iq-moving-research-data-and-out-institutional-repositories/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2009 14:42:09 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2009/05/12/special-iq-moving-research-data-and-out-institutional-repositories/</guid>
      <description>The IASSIST Quarterly IQ Vol. 31 issue 3&amp;amp;4 is now available on the web:
http://iassistdata.org/publications/iq/iqvol31.html
This issue will only be available on the web. There will be no printed version mailed out to the membership.
This double issue is the work of the authors and their articles are introduced below. We are presenting an integrated double issue of high quality. We should also give a special thanks to the editors of the issue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Registration for the IASSIST 2009 is open</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2009/02/24/registration-iassist-2009-open/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2009 10:03:01 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2009/02/24/registration-iassist-2009-open/</guid>
      <description>Tervetuloa Tampereelle, Welcome to Tampere!
Registration for the 2009 IASSIST conference is now officially open. On the conference web site there is more information on registration, accommodations and excursions.
The Early Bird rate is valid until March 24, 2009. Please note that a deposit of one night for accommodation should be paid together with the registration fees. Cancellations (conference attendance, hotels, tours) on or before April 24 will receive a refund minus the administrative fees.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>new IQ</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2008/08/15/new-iq-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2008 13:07:45 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2008/08/15/new-iq-0/</guid>
      <description>The IASSIST Quarterly (IQ Vol. 31 issue 1 - 2007) is now available on the web:
http://iassistdata.org/publications/iq/iqvol31.html
Welcome to the first issue of the IASSIST Quarterly, vol. 31. We have passed the 34th IASSIST conference, also known as the Stanford IASSIST 2008 conference - best ever. However, the IASSIST Quarterly vol. 31 is known also as the 2007 volume. Yes, we are behind our schedule; but at least we are consistently so.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST 2008 Accommodations and Registration Reminder</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2008/04/22/iassist-2008-accommodations-and-registration-reminder/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2008 14:11:34 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2008/04/22/iassist-2008-accommodations-and-registration-reminder/</guid>
      <description>Happy Earth Day to everyone!!
Hope your day is filled with loads of celebratory reducing, renewing, and recycling.
Registration for this year&amp;rsquo;s IASSIST Conference (May 27-30): &amp;ldquo;Technology of Data: Collection, Communication, Access and Preservation&amp;rdquo; is proceeding at a rumbling pace, and the five conference hotels have been filling with eager California-bound IASSISTers.
However, if you still have not made your arrangements for this year&amp;rsquo;s conference, please consider doing so. Early registration ends soon (May 2), and of more immediate concern, the conference hotels will begin dropping our room blocks (and guaranteed conference rates) beginning this Friday, April 25.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upcoming ODaF meetings in Europe and US</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2008/02/22/upcoming-odaf-meetings-europe-and-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2008 14:30:15 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2008/02/22/upcoming-odaf-meetings-europe-and-us/</guid>
      <description>The Open Data Foundation is pleased to announce that an ODaF Europe 2008 meeting will take place at the UK Data Archive on April 14-15. This regional event is open to all members as well as individuals and agencies interested to learn more about ODaF or to share ideas. For further information and registration, see http://www.opendatafoundation.org/events/odaf_europe_2008.php
Looking into the future, we currently anticipate holding a US regional meeting on Oct 2-3 at the Sun Microsystems headquarters in Manhattan, NY and our Annual Meeting in Washington DC in December.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST 2008 - Call for Papers! </title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2007/10/29/iassist-2008-call-papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2007 13:21:34 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2007/10/29/iassist-2008-call-papers/</guid>
      <description>Technology of Data: Collection, Communication, Access and Preservation The 34th International Association for Social Science Information Services and Technology (IASSIST) annual conference will be held at the Stanford University, Palo Alto, California, USA, May 27-30, 2008. This year&amp;rsquo;s conference, Technology of Data: Collection, Communication, Access and Preservation, examines the role of technology and tools in various aspects of the data life cycle.
The theme of this conference addresses how technology can affect aspects of data stewardship throughout the data lifecycle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The IASSIST 2007 song!</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2007/05/25/iassist-2007-song/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2007 15:47:31 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2007/05/25/iassist-2007-song/</guid>
      <description>Here it is: music by Leonard Cohen, lyrics by Melanie Wright and company. Now you can sing along to the YouTube video.
Open Data
We made our way to Montreal Where everybody knows f&amp;amp;*% all And no one&amp;rsquo;s gonna tell you &amp;ldquo;see you later.&amp;rdquo; Admin committee steaming hot Went on and on &amp;lsquo;til we asked what Does all this have to do with Open Data?
Chorus: Open Data, Open Data, IASSISTERs / here to cheer / Open Data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It was the best IASSIST ever!</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2007/05/22/it-was-best-iassist-ever/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2007 16:14:31 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2007/05/22/it-was-best-iassist-ever/</guid>
      <description>Until next year of course!
This year&amp;rsquo;s conference is done and Anastassia, Susan, and the wonderful Local arrangement folks at McGill are probably breathing a sigh of relief! Lots of informations was presented and some of it was absorbed! More will likely be reviewed over coming weeks preceded by the usual &amp;ldquo;Now I know I saw a presentation about this at IASSIST&amp;hellip;.&amp;rdquo;
If you were one of those fine presenters, please don&amp;rsquo;t forget to submit a paper to the IQ (instructions for doing so are on the IASSIST website).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Session D3:  views from near a plug....</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2007/05/18/session-d3-views-near-plug/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2007 01:54:41 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2007/05/18/session-d3-views-near-plug/</guid>
      <description>Your trusty blogger attended Data Access Questions: Open and Shut (session D3). She assumed that, as an august member of the blogging press, she would be afforded a primo seat. But no, she again found herself sitting on the floor in the corner, next to another fake potted palm! Thank heavens the session was moved to a neighboring room&amp;mdash;larger and with a microphone. Obviously, a popular session on the challenges of working with data agreements from the perspectives of acquisition and user support.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology befuddles session C3</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2007/05/16/technology-befuddles-session-c3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2007 23:07:44 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2007/05/16/technology-befuddles-session-c3/</guid>
      <description>So now that I remember my blog password, I have lots to say. I want to extend my congratulations and kudos to my fellow session participants in C3 (New Discovery Tools: Thinking Outside the Catalogue) where we managed to kill 3 laptops and still do 4 outstanding presentations. The room was too hot and too crowded but the attendees were patient, enthusiastic and even provided some tech support!!
Paul Bern was the lucky presenter - the laptop didn&amp;rsquo;t reallly crash until he was done explaining how to make Google work better for us and help us to help other folks find data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Modest Set of Proposals</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2007/05/16/modest-set-proposals/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2007 18:18:48 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2007/05/16/modest-set-proposals/</guid>
      <description>The conference is on and I&amp;rsquo;m hoping to see lots of blog entries from the interesting sessions today. I&amp;rsquo;m expecting some details on session A1 from another contributor but&amp;hellip;. I&amp;rsquo;ve been asked by Kristin Partlo to pass along the proposals she and Rachael Barlow outlined at the end of their presentation for further comment. So here they are! This part of the session was on social bookmarking using sites such as del.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Waxing Lyrical about IASSIST 2006</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2006/06/08/waxing-lyrical-about-iassist-2006/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2006 16:04:55 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2006/06/08/waxing-lyrical-about-iassist-2006/</guid>
      <description>Melanie Wright and her doo-wop partners, Jen Green and Joanne Juhnke, treated us to this year&amp;rsquo;s song at the wrap up session. These fine phrases should be set to the tune of &amp;ldquo;My Girl&amp;rdquo;
There was sunshine after weeks of rain When the IASSISTers to Ann Arbor came Why have we come so far? What can drag us from the bar? Data (data) talkin&amp;rsquo; &amp;lsquo;bout data (data)
GIS, SDA and Atlas-TI Data lifecycles, and of course DDI in the Reading Room we made some noise and ogled gorgeous jazz band boys and data (data) always talkin&amp;rsquo; &amp;lsquo;bout data (data)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conceptualizing the Digital Life Cycle</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2006/06/01/conceptualizing-digital-life-cycle/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2006 20:49:41 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2006/06/01/conceptualizing-digital-life-cycle/</guid>
      <description>The Digital Life Cycle was mentioned many times during the IASSIST 2006 conference. Reaction toward this concept was varied. Some were unsure they liked this idea claiming that the life cycle was a confusing or imperfect metaphor. Others applied a very exact meaning to the concept associating it to the stages through which information passes within a system or large process. The Session that I chaired on Institutional Repositories and Social Science Data: Supporting the Data Life Cycle (B1) provided different visual representations of the digital life cycle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog the Conference!</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2006/05/25/blog-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2006 16:33:49 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2006/05/25/blog-conference/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the 2006 IASSIST Conference in Ann Arbor! For those who can&amp;rsquo;t join in the fun, we (the Pubs committee and the Admin Committee) have decided it&amp;rsquo;s a good idea for us to blog the conference! (See San&amp;rsquo;s fine example below.) Use this post to comment with your thoughts on a session that really got you thinking. And, (IASSIST members only): become an editor if you would like to post more frequently - contact San.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metadata Musings from IASSIST 2006</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2006/05/25/metadata-musings-iassist-2006/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2006 11:54:42 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2006/05/25/metadata-musings-iassist-2006/</guid>
      <description>I will start with a disclaimer that I am not a metadata expert nor do I play one on TV but I have been spending a lot of time recently contemplating metadata issues. Granted they have been issues that deal with metadata in a time series world but it gave me an interesting frame of reference for attending several sessions on metadata-related issues. Here&amp;rsquo;s my thoughts:
After attending three and a half session exploring metadata issues, the one clear idea that has emerged is that there don&amp;rsquo;t seem to be any clear ideas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Data Surfaces at the ALA Annual Meeting</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2006/05/16/open-data-surfaces-ala-annual-meeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2006 18:32:42 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2006/05/16/open-data-surfaces-ala-annual-meeting/</guid>
      <description>On May 11, 2006, the following announcement was made about an upcoming forum at the American Library Association annual meeting that will address issues related to Open Data.
 During the past several years, Open Data has become a field of urgent interest to researchers, scholars, and librarians. With the amount of scientific data doubling every year, issues surrounding the access, use, and curation of data sets are increasing in importance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Issue of the IQ is available on the web.</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2006/05/03/new-issue-iq-available-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2006 12:02:20 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2006/05/03/new-issue-iq-available-web/</guid>
      <description>A new issue of the IASSIST Quarterly (IQ Vol. 29 issue 2)is now available on the web:
We are pleased to present this second issue of the IASSIST Quarterly vol. 29. The issue contains three articles from the IASSIST conference in Edinburgh in May 2005. This is a second posting of this information as the original posting got lost in cyberspace.
At the session called &amp;ldquo;Using National Data&amp;rdquo; the paper on &amp;ldquo;Economic data as snapshots in time&amp;rdquo; was presented by Katrina Stierholz from the Federal Reserve Bank of St.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Papers from First E-Social-Science Conference Online</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2005/08/29/papers-first-e-social-science-conference-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2005 11:10:44 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2005/08/29/papers-first-e-social-science-conference-online/</guid>
      <description>The papers from the first conference on e-social science, which was held in late June of 2005 in Manchester, England, are now online.
-Contributed by Jim Jacobs</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CODATA meeting notes</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2005/08/03/codata-meeting-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2005 16:10:18 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2005/08/03/codata-meeting-notes/</guid>
      <description>The US National Committee for CODATA and its subgroup on Permanent Access to Scientific Data met on July 13 and 14 at the National Academies in Washington, D.C. I [Gretchen Gano] was invited to participate as a guest. Below are links, a background on the committee, and some meeting highlights from my perspective with proposed follow-on IASSIST activities. I will forward a list of the proposed activities to the conference-planning list!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ernie Boyko Begins First Term as Incoming President</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2005/06/13/ernie-boyko-begins-first-term-incoming-president/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2005 22:59:01 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2005/06/13/ernie-boyko-begins-first-term-incoming-president/</guid>
      <description>Ernie Boyko began his first term as the incoming President of IASSIST in Edinburgh. A little less than a year since his retirement with Statistics Canada, Ernie Boyko took the reigns of IASSIST as their new President. Having retired at the end of June 2004, Ernie has kept himself busy in the world of data as a VP with Nesstar Americas Inc. He has also remained active as an external adviser with the Data Liberation Initiative&amp;rsquo;s (DLI) External Advisory Committee and as an instructor in the DLI training programme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Green Completes Her Presidency Still Smiling</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2005/06/13/ann-green-completes-her-presidency-still-smiling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2005 18:24:54 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2005/06/13/ann-green-completes-her-presidency-still-smiling/</guid>
      <description>Ann Green completed her second term as President of IASSIST during the conference in Edinburgh.
A long-standing member of IASSIST, Ann served as Vice-President from 1997 to 2001 before serving as President from 2001 to 2005. She has been a excellent leader achieving many accomplishments during her tenure. She brought in a new strategic planning process into 2003, which resulted in a Strategic Plan released in May 2004. This Plan is now being integrated into the directions of our Standing Committees and Action Groups.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A bonnie IASSIST in Edinburgh</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2005/06/09/bonnie-iassist-edinburgh-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2005 16:30:09 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2005/06/09/bonnie-iassist-edinburgh-0/</guid>
      <description>IASSIST 2005, hosted in Edinburgh from May 24-27, was a rousing success with over 200 participants attending over the four days of conference and workshops. There were many highlights, including a record number of presentations, an earth-shattering reception at Our Dynamic Earth, a joyful conference banquet and ceilidh at the Roxburghe Hotel, a maze of outstanding posters and demonstrations, two thought-provoking plenary sessions and a new conference wrap-up song by Melanie.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>