<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tools, Apps, Technology on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </title>
    <link>https://talatera.github.io/tags/tools-apps-technology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tools, Apps, Technology on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 10:03:28 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://talatera.github.io/tags/tools-apps-technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>but how do i *do* qualitative research? bridging the gap between qualitative researchers and methods resources--part 4</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2017/08/07/how-do-i-do-qualitative-research-bridging-gap-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 10:03:28 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2017/08/07/how-do-i-do-qualitative-research-bridging-gap-4/</guid>
      <description>Last week Mandy shared ideas about how librarians and other data-support professionals can act as connectors, crusaders and collaborators on campus in order to better provide and develop qualitative research teaching resources. This week we want to build on Mandy&amp;rsquo;s suggestions by looking a bit more broadly at how librarians and other data-support professionals can help build community around qualitative research at their institutions.
As qualitative research methods are often not the dominant methodologies used in departments and institutions, qualitative researchers may not have a strong support network and may lack colleagues to consult with or learn from.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>But How Do I *Do* Qualitative Research? Bridging the Gap between Qualitative Researchers and Methods Resources--PART 3</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2017/07/31/how-do-i-do-qualitative-research-bridging-gap-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 06:53:37 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2017/07/31/how-do-i-do-qualitative-research-bridging-gap-3/</guid>
      <description>Connectors, Crusaders, and Collaborators Jill&amp;rsquo;s post from last week detailed ways we data-support professionals can connect researchers to library collections and other information sources for bridging the qualitative methods gap. I&amp;rsquo;d like to offer more ideas for how we can act not only as connectors but also as crusaders and collaborators on our campuses specifically in the realm of providing and developing qualitative-research teaching resources. Because we work with researchers across campus and in various capacities, data-support professionals are often more aware of methods gaps than are the academic departments we support.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>But How Do I *Do* Qualitative Research? Bridging the Gap between Qualitative Researchers and Methods Resources--PART 2</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2017/07/23/how-do-i-do-qualitative-research-bridging-gap-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2017 21:20:53 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2017/07/23/how-do-i-do-qualitative-research-bridging-gap-2/</guid>
      <description>Mandy kicked off our 4-part blog series last week with an inaugural post that provided background and context for this project, which centers around a specific challenge faced by many qualitative researchers: lack of qualitative methods training. This post offers some concrete ideas to data-support professionals on how to leverage library collections and other information sources that direct researchers to secondary and tertiary sources on qualitative methods to address this issue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>But How Do I *Do* Qualitative Research? Bridging the Gap between Qualitative Researchers and Methods Resources--PART 1</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2017/07/17/how-do-i-do-qualitative-research-bridging-gap-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2017 09:37:14 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2017/07/17/how-do-i-do-qualitative-research-bridging-gap-1/</guid>
      <description>The IASSIST Qualitative Social Science &amp;amp; Humanities Data Interest Group (QSSHDIG) was created in October 2016, its central purpose: to foster conversations regarding the needs of researchers who generate qualitative data, and what types of services librarians and other information professionals can develop to support these researchers in managing their data/source materials throughout the research lifecycle.
This four-post blog series engages in one particular conversation: challenges researchers face in terms of a lack of qualitative methods training, and strategies for how data-support professionals can address these challenges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST 2016 Program At-A-Glance, Part 2: Data infrastructure, data processing and research data management</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2016/05/06/iassist-2016-program-glance-part-2-data-infrastructure-data-processing-and-research-data-manage/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2016 07:13:42 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2016/05/06/iassist-2016-program-glance-part-2-data-infrastructure-data-processing-and-research-data-manage/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s another list of highlights from IASSIST2016 which is focusing on the data revolution. For previous highlights, see here.
Infrastructure  For those of you with an interest in technical infrastructure, the University of Applied Sciences HTW Chur will showcase an early protype MMRepo (1 June, 3F), whose function is to store qualitative and quantitative data into one big data repository.   The UK Data Service will present the following panel &amp;ldquo;The CESSDA Technical Framework - what is it and why is it needed?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interested in the “data revolution” and what it means for research? Here’s why you should attend IASSIST2016</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2016/05/03/interested-in-the-data-revolution-and-what-it-means-for-research-heres-why-you-should-attend-iassist2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2016 02:15:18 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2016/05/03/interested-in-the-data-revolution-and-what-it-means-for-research-heres-why-you-should-attend-iassist2016/</guid>
      <description>Part 1: Data sharing, new data sources and data protection IASSIST is an international organisation of information technology and data services professionals which aims to provide support to research and teaching in the social sciences. It has over 300 members ranging from data archive staff and librarians to statistical agencies, government departments and non-profit organisations.
The theme of this year&amp;rsquo;s conference is &amp;ldquo;Embracing the &amp;lsquo;data revolution&amp;rsquo;: opportunities and challenges for research&amp;rdquo; and it is the 42nd of its kind, taking place every year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Latest Issue of IQ Available!  Data Documentation Initiative - Results, Tools, and  Further Initiatives </title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2016/03/24/latest-issue-iq-available-data-documentation-initiative-results-tools-and-further-initiatives/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2016 07:09:42 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2016/03/24/latest-issue-iq-available-data-documentation-initiative-results-tools-and-further-initiatives/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to thethird issue of Volume 39 of the IASSIST Quarterly (IQ 39:3, 2015). This special issue is guest edited by Joachim Wackerow of GESIS &amp;ndash; Leibniz Institute for the Social Sciences in Germany and Mary Vardigan of ICPSR at the University of Michigan, USA. That sentence is a direct plagiarism from the editor&amp;rsquo;s notes of the recent double issue (IQ 38:4 &amp;amp; 39:1). We are very grateful for all the work Mary and Achim have carried out and are developing further in the continuing story of the Data Documentation Initiative (DDI), and for their efforts in presenting the work here in the ASSIST Quarterly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking Back/Moving Forward - Reflections on the First Ten Years of Open Repositories</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2015/07/03/reflections-on-first-ten-years-of-open-repositories/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2015 01:15:01 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2015/07/03/reflections-on-first-ten-years-of-open-repositories/</guid>
      <description>Open Repositories conference celebrated its first decade by having four full days of exciting workshops, keynotes, sessions, 24/7 talks, and development track and repository interest group sessions in Indianapolis, USA. All the fun took place in the second week of June. The OR2015 conference was themed &amp;ldquo;Looking Back/Moving Forward: Open Repositories at the Crossroads&amp;rdquo; and it brought over 400 repository developers and managers, librarians and library IT professionals, service providers and other experts to hot and humid Indy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Visualization Support Roles</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2014/07/22/data-visualization-support-roles/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2014 13:31:24 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2014/07/22/data-visualization-support-roles/</guid>
      <description>Hello IASSISTers,
Since our last entry, the Data Visualization Working Group (DVIG) has been connecting through email to gather information and share knowledge about data visualization tools, best practices, teaching, and events of interest. A major theme of conversation has been open source programming frameworks like R statistical packages to conduct visualization. Many other non-programming tools have also been discussed and shared. The question of tools is not an easy one, and there are a lot out there!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the Release of the CRDCN Dataset Builder</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/10/01/announcing-release-crdcn-dataset-builder/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 11:05:11 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/10/01/announcing-release-crdcn-dataset-builder/</guid>
      <description>CRDCN Database Builder Splash Screen   The Canadian Research Data Centre Network (CRDCN) is pleased to announce the release of the CRDCN Dataset Builder.
In collaboration with Statistics Canada and Metadata Technology North America, the Dataset Builder allows researchers working (or intending to work) in a Canadian RDC the ability to browse, search for and select variables in the Statistics Canada surveys currently housed in the RDCs. Utilizing DDI Lifecycle metadata, the Dataset Builder allows researchers to find and select variables, as well as produce SAS, SPSS or Stata syntax to help read in and format the variables, and produce customized documentation (Layout and Codebooks) for the dataset they create using the app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OR2013:  Open Repositories Confront Research Data</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/07/19/or2013-open-repositories-confront-research-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2013 14:38:23 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/07/19/or2013-open-repositories-confront-research-data/</guid>
      <description>Open Repositories 2013 was hosted by the University of Prince Edward Island from July 8-12. A strong research data stream ran throughout this conference, which was attended by over 300 participants from around the globe. To my delight, many IASSISTers were in attendance, including the current IASSIST President and four Past-Presidents! Rarely do such sightings happen outside an IASSIST conference.
  IASSIST Five Presidents by Limor Peer   This was my first Open Repositories conference and after the cool reception that research data received at the SPARC IR meetings in Baltimore a few years ago, I was unsure how data would be treated at this conference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the IASSIST Data Visualization Interest Group (DVIG!)</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/03/31/introducing-iassist-data-visualization-interest-group-dvig/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 11:51:27 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/03/31/introducing-iassist-data-visualization-interest-group-dvig/</guid>
      <description>Hello fellow IASSISTer&amp;rsquo;s
 With the upcoming 2013 Conference nearing, we thought it very fitting to introduce you all to the newly created IASSIST Data Visualization Interest Group. Formed over the winter and now spring of 2013, this group brings together over 46 IASSIST members from across the world (literally across-the-world! check out the map of our locations), who are all interested in data visualization. We hope to share a range of skills and information around tools, best practice visualization, and discuss innovative representations of data, statistics, and information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some reflections on research data confidentiality, privacy, and curation by Limor Peer</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/03/07/some-reflections-research-data-confidentiality-privacy-and-curation-limor-peer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2013 11:43:38 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/03/07/some-reflections-research-data-confidentiality-privacy-and-curation-limor-peer/</guid>
      <description>Some reflections on research data confidentiality, privacy, and curation
Limor Peer
Maintaining research subjects&amp;rsquo; confidentiality is an essential feature of the scientific research enterprise. It also presents special challenges to the data curation process. Does the effort to open access to research data complicate these challenges?
A few reasons why I think it does: More data are discoverable and could be used to re-identify previously de-identified datasets; systems are increasingly interoperable, potentially bridging what may have been insular academic data with other data and information sources; growing pressure to open data may weaken some of the safeguards previously put in place; and some data are inherently identifiable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In search of:  Best practice for code repositories?</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/03/05/search-best-practice-code-repositories/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2013 12:45:39 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/03/05/search-best-practice-code-repositories/</guid>
      <description>I was asked by a colleague about organized efforts within the economics community to develop or support repositories of code for research. Her experience was with the astrophysics world which apparently has several and she was wondering what could be learned from another academic community. So I asked a non-random sample of technical economists with whom I work, and then expanded the question to cover all of social sciences and posed the question to the IASSIST community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST Quarterly (2011: Fall)</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2012/01/31/iassist-quarterly-2011-fall/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2012 08:32:04 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2012/01/31/iassist-quarterly-2011-fall/</guid>
      <description>Sharing data and building information With this issue (volume 35-3, 2011) of the IASSIST Quarterly (IQ) we return to the regular format of a collection of articles not within the same specialist subject area as we have seen in recent special issues of IQ. Naturally the three articles presented here are related to the IQ subject area in general, as in: assisting research with data, acquiring data from research, and making good use of the user community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>86 helpful tools for the data professional PLUS 45 bonus tools</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/10/29/86-helpful-tools-data-professional-plus-45-bonus-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2011 17:04:17 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/10/29/86-helpful-tools-data-professional-plus-45-bonus-tools/</guid>
      <description>I have been working on this (mostly) annotated collection of tools and articles that I believe would be of help to both the data dabbler and professional. If you are a data scientist, data analyst or data dummy, chances are there is something in here for you. I included a list of tools, such as programming languages and web-based utilities, [data mining]{.zem_slink} resources, some prominent organizations in the field, repositories where you can play with data, events you may want to attend and important articles you should take a look at.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 significant visualisation developments</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/07/07/10-significant-visualisation-developments/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2011 08:49:43 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/07/07/10-significant-visualisation-developments/</guid>
      <description>Interesting collection of visualization developments:
 10 significant visualisation developments: January to June 2011 Visualising Data (July 7th, 2011)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sensitive data and the US Patriot Act</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/06/30/sensitive-data-and-us-patriot-act/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2011 09:06:11 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/06/30/sensitive-data-and-us-patriot-act/</guid>
      <description>The series of articles below might be of interest to some of you planning or working with sensitive data in the cloud.
Microsoft admits Patriot Act can access EU-based cloud data
[](http://www.zdnet.com/blog/igeneration/microsoft-admits-patriot-act-can-access-eu-based-cloud-data/11225)See also ZDNet&amp;rsquo;s Patriot Act series:
 ZDNet&amp;rsquo;s USA PATRIOT Act series Summary Part 1: USA PATRIOT Act and the controversy of Canada Part 2: Safe Harbor: Why EU data needs &amp;lsquo;protecting&amp;rsquo; from U.S. law Part 3: How the USA PATRIOT Act can be used to access EU data Part 4: USA PATRIOT Act: The myth of a secure European cloud  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST Quarterly (IQ) volume 34-2 now on the web</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/05/17/iassist-quarterly-iq-volume-34-2-now-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2011 09:02:31 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/05/17/iassist-quarterly-iq-volume-34-2-now-web/</guid>
      <description>The new issue of the IASSIST Quarterly is now available on the web. This is the volume 34 (number 2, 2010).
 http://iassistdata.org/iq/issue/34/2
The layout has changed. We hope you&amp;rsquo;ll enjoy the new style presented. It seems to be a more modern format and more suited for the PDF presentation on the web. Walter Piovesan &amp;ndash; our publication officer &amp;ndash; had a biking accident. To show that nothing is so bad that it is not good for something Walter used his recovery time to redesign the IQ.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wrangle, Refine, and Represent (Data Visualization Tools from the CAR Conference)</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/03/16/wrangle-refine-and-represent-data-visualization-tools-car-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2011 08:54:10 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/03/16/wrangle-refine-and-represent-data-visualization-tools-car-conference/</guid>
      <description>I wanted to share a blog post from our local Data and GIS blog that may be of interest to the IASSIST community. Each of the tools varies in it&amp;rsquo;s focus and applicability for data work- but they might be helpful for various data tasks focusing on cleaning and representing data online.
http://blogs.library.duke.edu/data/2011/03/14/wrangle-refine-and-represent/
On a slightly related note, I was very impressed with the CAR (Computer Assisted Reporting) Conference and the IRE (Investigative Reporters and Editors Group).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBE 2020 white papers available</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/02/04/sbe-2020-white-papers-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2011 00:14:24 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/02/04/sbe-2020-white-papers-available/</guid>
      <description>The Directorate for the Social, Behavioral, and Economic Sciences of the National Science Foundation (NSF/SBE) has released today a collection of white papers contributed under the &amp;ldquo;SBE 2020: Future Research in the Social, Behavioral &amp;amp; Economic Sciences&amp;rdquo; initiative. Authors were asked to outline grand challenge questions that are both foundational and transformative. For information, please visit: http://www.nsf.gov/sbe/sbe_2020/index.cfm
[](http://www.nsf.gov/sbe/sbe_2020/index.cfm){.moz-txt-link-freetext}The Open Data Foundation contributed to the following:
Maximizing the Potential of Data: Modern IT Tools, Best Practices, and Metadata Standards for SBE Sciences Pascal Heus (pascal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST Twitter Account!</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2010/09/23/iassist-twitter-account/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2010 12:37:30 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2010/09/23/iassist-twitter-account/</guid>
      <description>Your friendly web editors have some news about the IASSIST web presence!
We&amp;rsquo;re happy to report that we now have an official organizational Twitter account: [http://twitter.com/iassistdata]{.s1}. We hope to use this account to facilitate additional communication among IASSIST members. Ways to view this Twitter account:
 [http://www.iassistdata.org/]{.s1} - Does not require Twitter account follow [http://twitter.com/iassistdata]{.s1} (and we&amp;rsquo;ll follow you in return) subscribe to the RSS feed of [http://twitter.com/iassistdata]{.s1} at http://twitter.com/statuses/user_timeline/156331061.rss - Does not require Twitter account  Each of these views will include posts by [http://twitter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Islandora</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2010/06/16/islandora/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2010 07:17:16 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2010/06/16/islandora/</guid>
      <description>I am just attending CANHEIT and saw a presentation on http://islandora.ca . I thought this was a really neat project and I really like their appliance approach to distributing this. In a way I thought what they are building touched on some of the vision presented by Pascal at http://ciser.cornell.edu/IASSIST/program/d3.shtm .</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>