<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital Repositories on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </title>
    <link>https://talatera.github.io/tags/digital-repositories/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Digital Repositories on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 13:42:54 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://talatera.github.io/tags/digital-repositories/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The International Workshop on Social Science Data Archives, held in Taiwan, sponsored by IASSIST</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2017/11/01/international-social-science-data-archives-workshop-taiwan/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 13:42:54 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2017/11/01/international-social-science-data-archives-workshop-taiwan/</guid>
      <description>The International Workshop on Social Science Data Archives, sponsored by IASSIST, was held on September 15 in Conference Room II, Research Center for Humanities and Social Science (RCHSS), Academia Sinica, Taipei, Taiwan. The invited speakers included Prof. Dr. Christof Wolf from GESIS &amp;ndash; Leibniz-Institute for the Social Sciences, Dr. Yukio Maeda and Dr. Kaoru Sato from Social Science Japan Data Archive (SSJDA), University of Tokyo, and Dr. Won-ho Park, Dr. Seokho Kim from Korea Social Science Data Archive (KOSSDA), Seoul National University.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IQ 40:1 Now Available!</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2016/09/20/iq-401-now-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2016 05:18:11 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2016/09/20/iq-401-now-available/</guid>
      <description>Our World and all the Local Worlds Welcome to the first issue of Volume 40 of the IASSIST Quarterly (IQ 40:1, 2016). We present four papers in this issue. The first paper presents data from our very own world, extracted from papers published in the IQ through four decades. What is published in the IQ is often limited in geographical scope and in this issue the other three papers present investigations and project research carried out at New York University, Purdue University, and the Federal Reserve System.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking Back/Moving Forward - Reflections on the First Ten Years of Open Repositories</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2015/07/03/reflections-on-first-ten-years-of-open-repositories/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2015 01:15:01 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2015/07/03/reflections-on-first-ten-years-of-open-repositories/</guid>
      <description>Open Repositories conference celebrated its first decade by having four full days of exciting workshops, keynotes, sessions, 24/7 talks, and development track and repository interest group sessions in Indianapolis, USA. All the fun took place in the second week of June. The OR2015 conference was themed &amp;ldquo;Looking Back/Moving Forward: Open Repositories at the Crossroads&amp;rdquo; and it brought over 400 repository developers and managers, librarians and library IT professionals, service providers and other experts to hot and humid Indy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A decade against decay: the 10th International Digital Curation Conference</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2015/02/17/decade-against-decay-10th-international-digital-curation-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2015 05:34:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2015/02/17/decade-against-decay-10th-international-digital-curation-conference/</guid>
      <description>The International Digital Curation Conference (IDCC) is now ten years old. On the evidence of its most recent conference, is in rude health and growing fast.
IDCC is the first time IASSIST decided to formally support another organisational conference. I think it was a wise investment given the quality of plenaries, presentations, posters, and discussions.
DCC already has available a number of blogs covering the substance of sessions, including an excellent summary by IASSIST web editor, Robin Rice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feedback on Data Storage</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2014/02/06/feedback-data-storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2014 13:35:13 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2014/02/06/feedback-data-storage/</guid>
      <description>I posted the following question to the listserv:
&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m in the early days of exploring what I and our library can do for our faculty and grad students. In my case I&amp;rsquo;m particularity interested in the social sciences.
It seems there are three main choices:
  ICPSR(or other domain-specific site)
  Dataverse with my own school&amp;rsquo;s branding
  Local, campus funded storage through an Institutional Repository or something else that can handle larger amounts of data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>White Paper Urges New Approaches to Assure Access to Scientific Data </title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/12/23/white-paper-urges-new-approaches-assure-access-scientific-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2013 06:15:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/12/23/white-paper-urges-new-approaches-assure-access-scientific-data/</guid>
      <description>Press release posted on behalf of Mark Thompson-Kolar, ICPSR.
12/12/2013: (Ann Arbor, MI)&amp;mdash;More than two dozen data repositories serving the social, natural, and physical sciences today released a white paper recommending new approaches to funding sharing and preservation of scientific data. The document emphasizes the need for sustainable funding of domain repositories&amp;mdash;data archives with ties to specific scientific communities.
&amp;ldquo;Sustaining Domain Repositories for Digital Data: A White Paper,&amp;rdquo; is an outcome of a meeting convened June 24-25, 2013, in Ann Arbor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>re3data.org and OpenAIRE sign MoU during Open Access Week; new re3data.org features</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/11/13/re3dataorg-and-openaire-sign-mou-during-open-access-week-new-re3dataorg-features/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2013 15:06:16 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/11/13/re3dataorg-and-openaire-sign-mou-during-open-access-week-new-re3dataorg-features/</guid>
      <description>Last month, OpenAIRE (Open Access Infrastructure for Research in Europe) and re3data.org signed a Memorandum of Agreement to &amp;ldquo;work jointly to facilitate research data registration, discovery, access and re-use&amp;rdquo; in support of open science. OpenAIRE is an infrastructure for open access that works to track and measure research output (originally designed to monitor EU funding activities). re3data.org is an online listing of research data repositories.
re3data.org and OpenAIRE will exchange metadata in order for OpenAIRE to &amp;ldquo;integrate data repositories indexed in the re3data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Role of Data Repositories in Reproducible Research</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/07/25/role-data-repositories-reproducible-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2013 10:36:04 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/07/25/role-data-repositories-reproducible-research/</guid>
      <description>Cross posted from ISPS Lux et Data Blog
These questions were on my mind as I was preparing to present a poster at the Open Repositories 2013 conference in Charlottetown, PEI earlier this month. The annual conference brings the digital repositories community together with stakeholders, such as researchers, librarians, publishers and others to address issues pertaining to &amp;ldquo;the entire lifecycle of information.&amp;rdquo; The conference theme this year, &amp;ldquo;Use, Reuse, Reproduce,&amp;rdquo; could not have been more relevant to the ISPS Data Archive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OR2013:  Open Repositories Confront Research Data</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/07/19/or2013-open-repositories-confront-research-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2013 14:38:23 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/07/19/or2013-open-repositories-confront-research-data/</guid>
      <description>Open Repositories 2013 was hosted by the University of Prince Edward Island from July 8-12. A strong research data stream ran throughout this conference, which was attended by over 300 participants from around the globe. To my delight, many IASSISTers were in attendance, including the current IASSIST President and four Past-Presidents! Rarely do such sightings happen outside an IASSIST conference.
  IASSIST Five Presidents by Limor Peer   This was my first Open Repositories conference and after the cool reception that research data received at the SPARC IR meetings in Baltimore a few years ago, I was unsure how data would be treated at this conference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In search of:  Best practice for code repositories?</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/03/05/search-best-practice-code-repositories/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2013 12:45:39 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/03/05/search-best-practice-code-repositories/</guid>
      <description>I was asked by a colleague about organized efforts within the economics community to develop or support repositories of code for research. Her experience was with the astrophysics world which apparently has several and she was wondering what could be learned from another academic community. So I asked a non-random sample of technical economists with whom I work, and then expanded the question to cover all of social sciences and posed the question to the IASSIST community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data-related blog posts coming out of Open Repositories 2012 conference</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2012/09/19/data-related-blog-posts-coming-out-open-repositories-2012-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2012 11:02:17 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2012/09/19/data-related-blog-posts-coming-out-open-repositories-2012-conference/</guid>
      <description>[]{.image-right}I &amp;lsquo;d been meaning to write an IASSIST blog post about OR 2012, hosted by the University of Edinburgh&amp;rsquo;s Host Organising Committee led by Co-Chair and IASSISTer Stuart Macdonald in July, because it had such good DATA content.
Fortunately Simon Hodson, the UK&amp;rsquo;s JISC Managing Research Data Programme Manager, has provided this introduction and has allowed me to post it here, with further links to his analytic blog posts, and even those contain further links to OTHER blog posts talking about OR2012 and data!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Special IQ: Moving Research Data Into and Out of Institutional Repositories</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2009/05/12/special-iq-moving-research-data-and-out-institutional-repositories/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2009 14:42:09 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2009/05/12/special-iq-moving-research-data-and-out-institutional-repositories/</guid>
      <description>The IASSIST Quarterly IQ Vol. 31 issue 3&amp;amp;4 is now available on the web:
http://iassistdata.org/publications/iq/iqvol31.html
This issue will only be available on the web. There will be no printed version mailed out to the membership.
This double issue is the work of the authors and their articles are introduced below. We are presenting an integrated double issue of high quality. We should also give a special thanks to the editors of the issue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data curation, institutional repositories and e-Research</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2008/02/22/data-curation-institutional-repositories-and-e-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2008 14:35:20 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2008/02/22/data-curation-institutional-repositories-and-e-research/</guid>
      <description>Luis Martinez-Uribe, Digital Repositories Research Co-ordinator, is based at the Oxford e-Research Centre and will be conducting a scoping study to capture researcher&amp;rsquo;s needs for repository services to manage, curate, preserve and disseminate research data generated in Oxford.
A new blog (http://oxdrrc.blogspot.com/) has been set-up to record the progress of the project while disseminating outputs and information about relevant activities. If you are interested in following the progress of this project you can subscribe to the RSS feed (http://oxdrrc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DDI, institutional repositories, and numeric data mashups</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2008/02/01/ddi-institutional-repositories-and-numeric-data-mashups/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2008 14:23:47 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2008/02/01/ddi-institutional-repositories-and-numeric-data-mashups/</guid>
      <description>Announcing new deliverables from the DISC-UK DataShare project:
 DISC-UK DataShare: Web 2.0 Data Visualisation Tools, by Stuart Macdonald.   The Data Documentation Initiative (DDI) and Institutional Repositories, by Luis Martinez.  Both briefing papers can be retrieved from http://www.disc-uk.org/deliverables.html .
There is also a new &amp;ldquo;Collective Intelligence&amp;rdquo; page with a tag cloud to links from our social bookmarks of reports, websites, and blogs related to the project themes. http://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DISC-UK DataShare Project for Institutional Data Repositories</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2007/10/12/disc-uk-datashare-project-institutional-data-repositories/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2007 12:44:30 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2007/10/12/disc-uk-datashare-project-institutional-data-repositories/</guid>
      <description>As part of the JISC-funded DISC-UK DataShare project{.moz-txt-link-freetext} in the UK, a State-of-the-Art Review has been written, marking out the current scene on data sharing at the beginning of the project. While the report is UK-focused, it may be of wider interest, and has a very thorough bibliography.
DISC-UK is a UK consortium of data support professionals working in departments and academic libraries in universities (Data Information Specialists Committee-United Kingdom). The project is about DISC-UK members (all of whom are also IASSIST members) working with academics and institutional repository managers at the four partner institutions - London School of Economics and the Universities of Edinburgh, Oxford and Southampton - to provide exemplars for sharing research data within institutional repositories (based on EPrints.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assessment of UKDA and The National Archive (UK)  Compliance with OAIS and METS Standards</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2005/09/28/assessment-ukda-and-national-archive-uk-compliance-oais-and-mets-standards/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2005 09:10:41 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2005/09/28/assessment-ukda-and-national-archive-uk-compliance-oais-and-mets-standards/</guid>
      <description>Interesting report applying the Open Archival Information System (OAIS) model and the Metadata Encoding and Transmission Standard (METS) to the UK Data Archive; a very useful convergence of preservation strategies and articulation of what the model means for data and disciplinary focused digital repositories/archives.Email from the Digital Preservation Department at the UK National Archives:
 In conjunction with the UK Data Archive, The National Archives have released a report comparing their preservation practices to the leading internationally recognised standard for digital archives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ICPSR to Participate in Project to Certify Digital Archives</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2005/09/15/icpsr-participate-project-certify-digital-archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2005 06:50:06 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2005/09/15/icpsr-participate-project-certify-digital-archives/</guid>
      <description>ICPSR will be taking part in the RLG-NARA Digital Repository Certification project to identify the criteria repositories must meet for reliably storing, migrating, and providing access to digital collections.ICPSR has been selected to serve as a &amp;ldquo;test subject&amp;rdquo; in the Center for Research Libraries (CRL) project to develop an audit checklist for certification of trusted digital repositories. Funded by the Mellon Foundation, this project builds on the work of a Task Force consisting of members from the Research Libraries Group (RLG) and the U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Practice of User Registration to Access Data</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2005/09/14/practice-user-registration-access-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2005 22:40:37 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2005/09/14/practice-user-registration-access-data/</guid>
      <description>I am writing to address an issue that is coming up at UCLA with increasing frequency. More and more data distributors (agencies, archives, individuals) require a user to &amp;ldquo;register&amp;rdquo; before downloading data from a web site. These registrations take many forms and there is a continuum in terms of levels of detail and responsibility assigned to the user. It makes it hard for me to be of service to users when each study requires every individual to perform the registration task.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>