<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Exemplars on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </title>
    <link>https://talatera.github.io/tags/exemplars/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Exemplars on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2015 11:31:36 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://talatera.github.io/tags/exemplars/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Data Information Literacy (DIL) Case Studies Directory</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2015/11/06/data-information-literacy-dil-case-studies-directory/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2015 11:31:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2015/11/06/data-information-literacy-dil-case-studies-directory/</guid>
      <description>The Data Information Literacy (DIL) Case Studies Directory is a repository of teaching cases and material on research data management. DIL case studies are available for re-use under a CC-BY license and information on how to cite a case study is provided. Recent Case Studies include:
Engineering / Faculty / Sapp Nelson / Purdue University / 2015 [Megan R. Sapp Nelson]{.auth}
Electrical and Computer Engineering/ Undergraduates/ Carlson &amp;amp; SappNelson/ Purdue University/ 2012 photobanda.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LIBER: Research Data Management Case Studies</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2015/10/26/liber-research-data-management-case-studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2015 13:17:16 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2015/10/26/liber-research-data-management-case-studies/</guid>
      <description>In June 2014, the Scholarly Communication and Research Infrastructures Steering Committee of Association of European Rsearch Libraries (LIBER) published 11 case studies on Research Data Management. The case studies are hosted by or with strong involvement of libraries in research data management. These studies describe policies and strategies that pave the way for the creation, institutional integration and the running of support services and underlying infrastructures. In addition, challenges and lessons learned are described, and ways-forward outlined.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNC Data Stewardship Report</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2012/04/04/unc-data-stewardship-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2012 10:08:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2012/04/04/unc-data-stewardship-report/</guid>
      <description>In the spring of 2011, the UNC-Chapel Provost formed the Task Force on the Stewardship of Digital Research Data and charged its members with exploring the implications of data management for the University and making recommendations for University policy. The Task Force investigated the data management landscape through research in the literature, conversations with faculty and staff, and an in-depth faculty survey designed and administered by the Odum Institute. The resulting report was submitted to administrators in mid-February 2012 with recommendations for university policies and procedures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UK Data Archive: Create and Manage Data</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/30/uk-data-archive-create-and-manage-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2011 00:50:17 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/30/uk-data-archive-create-and-manage-data/</guid>
      <description>UK Data Archive: Create and Manage Data provides best practice guidance for researchers on creating and managing data. Guidance covers data management and sharing planning, consent and ethics in data sharing, data ownership and copyright, documenting data, formatting data, storing data, data security and data management strategies for large-scale research investments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataONE: Data Management Plans</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/30/dataone-data-management-plans/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2011 00:24:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/30/dataone-data-management-plans/</guid>
      <description>The DataONE Data Management Plans site describes the purpose of data management plans, with an outline plan and an example from environmental sciences. Information includes an overview of data management checklists currently in use across various organisations and support services, indicating common and unique topics across checklists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rural Economy and Land Use Programme (Relu): Data Management Planning</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/30/rural-economy-and-land-use-programme-relu-data-management-planning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2011 00:22:45 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/30/rural-economy-and-land-use-programme-relu-data-management-planning/</guid>
      <description>Relu&amp;rsquo;s Data Management Planning site has data management planning guidance, template and real-case examples of data management plans from the UK-based cross-disciplinary Rural Economy and Land Use Programme (social, environmental and biological sciences). Relu has its own data management and sharing policy and all funded projects are required to prepare a data management plan when they begin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ICPSR: Digital Preservation Management</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/27/icpsr-digital-preservation-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2011 08:03:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/27/icpsr-digital-preservation-management/</guid>
      <description>The ICPSR Digital Preservation Management site provides a listing of ICPSR-based workshops and tutorials on Digital Preservation Management*. Digital Preservation Management: Implementing Short-Term Strategies for Long-Term Solutions*, is an online tutorial developed for the Digital Preservation Management workshop, developed and maintained by Cornell University Library, 2003-2006; extended and maintained by ICPSR, 2007-on. This tutorial is available in English, French, and Italian.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ICPSR: Guide to Social Science Data Preparation and Archiving</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/25/icpsr-guide-social-science-data-preparation-and-archiving/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2011 11:56:27 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/25/icpsr-guide-social-science-data-preparation-and-archiving/</guid>
      <description>The ICPSR Guide to Social Science Data Preparation and Archiving (PDF) guides researchers through best practices in preparing their research data for sharing. Chapters cover activities to be undertaken at various stages throughout the research lifecycle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ICPSR: Guidelines for Effective Data Management Plans</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/25/icpsr-guidelines-effective-data-management-plans/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2011 11:44:16 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/25/icpsr-guidelines-effective-data-management-plans/</guid>
      <description>The ICPSR Guidelines for Effective Data Management Plans provide a framework for creating a plan (including recommended elements), a list of sample data management plans in a range of disciplines, a list of U.S. federal agency policies, and links to resources.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>