<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sustainability on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </title>
    <link>https://talatera.github.io/tags/sustainability/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sustainability on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2011 01:03:47 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://talatera.github.io/tags/sustainability/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>UK Data Archive: Managing and Sharing Data: Best Practice for Researchers</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/30/uk-data-archive-managing-and-sharing-data-best-practice-researchers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2011 01:03:47 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/30/uk-data-archive-managing-and-sharing-data-best-practice-researchers/</guid>
      <description>The UK Data Archive&amp;rsquo;s guide Managing and Sharing Data: Best Practice for Researchers (PDF) provides guidance to support researchers in producing high quality research data that can be shared and re-used beyond the primary research. The guidance covers:
 Why and how to share research data Data management planning and costing Documenting data Formatting data Storing data and data security Ethics and consent for data sharing and re-use Data copyright Data management strategies for large investments  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UK Data Archive: Research Data Management Costing Tool</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/30/uk-data-archive-research-data-management-costing-tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2011 00:42:40 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/30/uk-data-archive-research-data-management-costing-tool/</guid>
      <description>UK Data Archive&amp;rsquo;s Research Data Management Costing Tool (PDF) is an activity-based data management costing tool for researchers in the social sciences developed by the UK Data Archive. This tool can be used when preparing research applications or data management plans to estimate the additional costs above standard research procedures and practices that are needed to make research data shareable beyond the primary research team. Background information on how the costing tool was developed is available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Seal of Approval</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/25/data-seal-approval/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2011 12:07:21 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/25/data-seal-approval/</guid>
      <description>The Data Seal of Approval is a certification for data repositories who have demonstrated that they can ensure that in the future, deposited research data can still be processed in a high-quality and reliable manner, without entailing new thresholds, regulations, or high costs.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>