<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>IASSIST Regions on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </title>
    <link>https://talatera.github.io/tags/iassist-regions/</link>
    <description>Recent content in IASSIST Regions on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2017 12:00:31 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://talatera.github.io/tags/iassist-regions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST&#39;s Statement in Response to President’s Executive Order on Visas and Immigration</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2017/02/13/iassists-statement-response-presidents-executive-order-visas-and-immigration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2017 12:00:31 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2017/02/13/iassists-statement-response-presidents-executive-order-visas-and-immigration/</guid>
      <description>February 13, 2017
Statement of the International Association for Social Science Information Services and Technology (IASSIST at http://iassistdata.org) in response to President Trump&amp;rsquo;s January 27 Executive Order on Visas and Immigration, titled &amp;ldquo;PROTECTING THE NATION FROM FOREIGN TERRORIST ENTRY INTO THE UNITED STATES&amp;rdquo;.
The recent executive order on visas and immigration issued on January 27th by US President Trump is of grave concern to IASSIST as an organization. IASSIST, the International Association for Social Science Information Services and Technology, is an international organization of professionals working in and with information technology, libraries, data services and research &amp;amp; higher education to support open science, advocate for responsible data management and use, build a broader community surrounding research data, and encourage the development of data professionals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST will be at RDAP!</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2016/04/27/iassist-will-be-rdap/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 12:59:30 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2016/04/27/iassist-will-be-rdap/</guid>
      <description>For those of you attending the RDAP Summit next week in Atlanta, GA, USA, be sure to keep an eye out for IASSIST. We are a sponsoring organization&amp;mdash;check out the advance thank you blog post from RDAP.
Our VP, Jen Green, will be on the scene with promoting IASSIST at the poster session. Be sure to stop by to say &amp;ldquo;hi&amp;rdquo; and pick up your very own IASSIST logo button. Looking forward to hearing the report back from RDAP!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST election results, 2015</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2015/04/17/iassist-election-results-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2015 06:46:52 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2015/04/17/iassist-election-results-2015/</guid>
      <description>Hello IASSISTers!
Here are the official results of the 2015 IASSIST elections. There was a 61% voter turnout. The winning candidates are:
President: Tuomas Alaterä
Vice President: Jen Green
Secretary: Ryan Womack
Africa Regional Secretary: Lynn Woolfrey
Asia-Pacific Regional Secretary: Sam Spencer
Canada Regional Secretary: Carol Perry
Europe Regional Secretary: David Schiller
USA Regional Secretary: San Cannon
AC Member, Canada: Berenica Vejvoda
AC Members, Europe: Oliver Watteler and Arne Wolters</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chronology of data library and data centres</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2014/11/20/chronology-data-library-and-data-centres/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2014 10:01:41 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2014/11/20/chronology-data-library-and-data-centres/</guid>
      <description>A few days ago I asked on the IASSIST mailing list for some help in order to find out dates of creation of data libraries, data centres and such services. It was overwhelming to receive answers from colleagues from everywhere with dates and some other useful information about the establishment of local data support and national services.
  Newton, author of Chronology of Kingdoms   There is a wealth of information in this community around these issues and with the increasing importance of data services we need to make sure we collect and make this information accessible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST Fellows 2013</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/05/06/iassist-fellows-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2013 19:38:07 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/05/06/iassist-fellows-2013/</guid>
      <description>** **
The IASSIST Fellows Committee is glad to announce through this post the six recipients of the 2013 IASSIST Fellowship award. We are extremely excited to have such a diverse and interesting group with different backgrounds and experience and encourage IASSISTers to welcome them at our conference in Cologne, Germany.
Please find below their names, countries and brief bios:
**Chifundo Kanjala (Tanzania) **
Chifundo currently works as a Data Manager and data documentalist for an HIV research group called ALPHA network based at London School of Hygiene and Tropical Medicine&amp;rsquo;s department of Population Health, Chifundo spends most of his time in Mwanza, Tanzania but do travel from time around Southern and Eastern Africa to work with colleagues in the ALPHA network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST Latin Engagement Action Group </title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/11/03/iassist-latin-engagement-action-group/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2011 06:56:25 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/11/03/iassist-latin-engagement-action-group/</guid>
      <description>The Latin Engagement Action Group have come up with a number of outreach activities aimed at supporting data professionals from Spanish and Portuguese speaking educational institutions, namely:
1. Research Data Management Webinars (complete with IASSIST contribution) for Spanish/Portuguese data specialists (http://www.recolecta.net/buscador/webminars.jsp)
Stuart Macdonald and Luis Martínez-Uribe in collaboration with Alicia López Medina (UNED, Spain), the Spanish Agency of Science and Technology (FECYT) and the network of Spanish repositories RECOLECTA have organised a programme of webinars in 3 strands starting in October to discuss RDM issues:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST Election Results</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/05/iassist-election-results/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2011 10:00:22 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/05/iassist-election-results/</guid>
      <description>[Posted on behalf of Ernie Boyko]
Dear IASSIST Members
I am pleased to announce the results of the 2011 IASSIST election.
 The members of the IASSIST Administrative Committee and their terms are as follows:
President: Bill Block (2011-2013)
Vice- President: Tuomas J. Alaterä (2011-2013)
 Regional Secretaries for the period 2011-2013
 Africa: Lynn Woolfrey (2011-2013)
 Asia/Pacific Samuel Spencer (2011-2013)
 Canada Marilyn Andrews (2011-2013)
 Europe Iris Alfredsson (2011-2013)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>