<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>New Jobs on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </title>
    <link>https://talatera.github.io/tags/new-jobs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in New Jobs on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 05:26:09 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://talatera.github.io/tags/new-jobs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Opening for a Collections &amp; Research Librarian for Agricultural &amp; Environmental Sciences at NCSU</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2019/03/29/opening-collections-research-librarian-agricultural-environmental-sciences-ncsu/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 05:26:09 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2019/03/29/opening-collections-research-librarian-agricultural-environmental-sciences-ncsu/</guid>
      <description>NC State University Libraries is seeking a talented individual for the position of Collections &amp;amp; Research Librarian for Agricultural &amp;amp; Environmental Sciences. The ideal candidate for this position will be an individual who has the ability to engage deeply with agricultural and environmental sciences researchers and students at all levels. This position will be primarily responsible for leading collaborative collection management in agricultural and environmental sciences and, in collaboration with our team, providing expert services for faculty, staff, and students across the research life cycle including information discovery, data curation, visualization, research computing, and scholarly communication.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sr. Policy Analyst for European data policy issues (Brussels)</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2016/06/06/sr-policy-analyst-european-data-policy-issues-brussels/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2016 06:25:17 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2016/06/06/sr-policy-analyst-european-data-policy-issues-brussels/</guid>
      <description>Senior Policy Analyst The Center for Data Innovation, a Washington, DC-based non-profit, non-partisan public policy think tank, is recruiting a senior policy analyst to join its team as a full-time consultant to focus on European data policy issues. The position will be based in Brussels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Scholarship Librarian Opening at Kansas City Fed </title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2016/03/11/digital-scholarship-librarian-opening-kansas-city-fed/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2016 15:32:03 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2016/03/11/digital-scholarship-librarian-opening-kansas-city-fed/</guid>
      <description>Please see the announcement below for a new position created here in the Center for the Advancement of Data and Research in Economics at the Federal Reserve Bank of Kansas City . It will be part of the content support team that works with our technology specialists to support, enhance and advance data or computationally intensive research in economics. This position reports to me and has supervisory responsibility for our library staff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Viz Position at  UNC at Chapel Hill</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2016/01/13/data-viz-position-unc-chapel-hill/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2016 10:49:55 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2016/01/13/data-viz-position-unc-chapel-hill/</guid>
      <description>Please see the announcement below for a new position created here in the Libraries at UNC at Chapel Hill. It will be based in our Digital Research Services Department (you&amp;rsquo;d get to work with me and a bunch of other great people!) supporting the mission of our Research Hub in Davis Library. Note that there is a requirement for an advanced degree, but a master&amp;rsquo;s or PhD in a related subject field is admissible in place of a library degree.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social Sciences Librarian </title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2012/09/25/social-sciences-librarian/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2012 12:41:12 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2012/09/25/social-sciences-librarian/</guid>
      <description>Position: Social Sciences Librarian Available: January 1, 2013
The University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill seeks a creative, enthusiastic, and collaborative Social Sciences Librarian to join the Davis Library Research and Instructional Services Department as the Subject Librarian for the departments of Sociology and Political Science. The Social Sciences Librarian will apply state of the art technology to reference and research work, innovative outreach, evolving collection development, and dynamic data services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DDI/Java developer @ Metadata Technology</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/10/03/ddijava-developer-metadata-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2011 13:26:14 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/10/03/ddijava-developer-metadata-technology/</guid>
      <description>Metadata Technology North America is looking for full-time Java developers with strong background in XML and web service technologies. We are seeking entry level programmers as well as a more senior individual that can potentially operate as both a Java developer and project manager. Individuals must be able to work independently and posses the ability to adapt existing knowledge to new applications and technologies.
Our company focus is on providing solutions for the management of socio-economic and health statistical data and metadata, leveraging the Data Documentation Initiative (DDI), the Statistical Data and Metadata Exchange (SDMX), and related XML specifications.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>