<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>External Events on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </title>
    <link>https://talatera.github.io/tags/external-events/</link>
    <description>Recent content in External Events on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 11:28:17 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://talatera.github.io/tags/external-events/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrating Data Literacy into Library and Information Science (LIS) Curriculum</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2020/01/16/integrating-data-literacy-library-and-information-science-lis-curriculum/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 11:28:17 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2020/01/16/integrating-data-literacy-library-and-information-science-lis-curriculum/</guid>
      <description>IASSIST&amp;rsquo;s Africa Regional Secretary Ms. Winny Nekesa Akullo and Prof. Constant Obura-Okello report on a data workshop at Makerere University, Kampala.
If you&amp;rsquo;re looking to orginise a similar regional or national data event, the IASSIST 2020 Event Sponsorship Proposals call is open until 26 January 2020.
IASSIST&amp;rsquo;s Membership Committee&amp;rsquo;s event sponsorship program recently sponsored a one day workshop on Integrating Data Literacy into Library and Information Science (LIS) Curriculum. The workshop aimed at bringing academicians in the field of library and information science to discuss how data literacy can be integrated in the LIS curriculum so as to have trained library professionals who are able to provide data literacy skills to their patrons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Report from &#34;Workshop on Data Literacy for Researchers in Social Sciences, Administrators and Policy-Makers&#34;, Chandigarh, India.</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2019/12/16/report-workshop-data-literacy-researchers-social-sciences-administrators-and-policy-makers-chan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 09:34:43 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2019/12/16/report-workshop-data-literacy-researchers-social-sciences-administrators-and-policy-makers-chan/</guid>
      <description>Data Literacy is a skill needed for researchers and social scientists in the digital age to get the most out of massive data available to us in the digital era today. This was highlighted by Prof. I.V. Malhan, Former Dean, Academics of Central University of Himachal Pradesh, Dharamshala while inaugurating a &amp;lsquo;Workshop on Data Literacy for Researchers in Social Sciences, Administrators and Policy-Makers&amp;rsquo; held at MG State Institute of Public Administration, Punjab (MGSIPA) at Chandigarh (India).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DPC2018 Conference Report</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2018/12/18/dpc2018-conference-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 12:52:41 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2018/12/18/dpc2018-conference-report/</guid>
      <description>By Adetoun Oyelude, University of Ibadan
From Saturday 1st September 2018 when one of the participants from Uganda arrived in Nigeria, the Digital Preservation Conference started on a high note. The preparations for the Monday Opening Ceremony took place on Sunday 2nd with the Ugandan participant joining at the venue in preparing the Hall and other ancillaries concerning the conference. **Day 1: **The Opening Ceremony conference commenced at 11.45am on Monday, 3rd September 2018.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Workshop at the National Library of Australia, sponsored by IASSIST</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2017/12/15/data-workshop-national-library-australia-sponsored-iassist/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2017 09:08:15 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2017/12/15/data-workshop-national-library-australia-sponsored-iassist/</guid>
      <description>Posted on behalf of Jade Koekoe
In February I won sponsorship money from IASSIST for a Data Workshop I had in mind. On the 18 November this year I saw my idea come to life. This Data Workshop was aimed at Library student and newgrads and was held in the Ferguson Room of the National Library of Australia. 26 people attended and there were five speakers from industries adjacent to librarianship.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST Call for Event Sponsorship Proposals</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2017/01/03/iassist-call-event-sponsorship-proposals/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2017 09:20:40 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2017/01/03/iassist-call-event-sponsorship-proposals/</guid>
      <description>The IASSIST Liaison and Organizational Sponsorship Task Force is seeking proposals for sponsorships of regional or local events during calendar year 2017. The goal of these sponsorships is to support local networks of data professionals and data-related activities across the globe in order to help support IASSISTers activities throughout the year and increase awareness of the value of IASSIST membership.
Events should be a gathering of data professionals from multiple institutions and may vary in size and scope from workshops, symposia, conferences, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST sponsors IFLA 2016 Knowledge Management conference</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2016/10/21/iassist-sponsors-ifla-2016-knowledge-management-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2016 08:27:34 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2016/10/21/iassist-sponsors-ifla-2016-knowledge-management-conference/</guid>
      <description>IASSIST proudly sponsored a full-day conference about knowledge management (KM) on August 12, 2016 in Cincinnati, Ohio, USA at the University of Cincinnati. The theme of the conference was Sharing Practices and Actions for Making Best Use of Organizational Knowledge in Libraries.The conference took place as part of the International Federation of Library Associations&amp;rsquo; (IFLA) annual conference held this year in Columbus, Ohio, USA.
The KM conference featured two keynote speakers: Valerie Forrestal, author of the 2015 book Knowledge Management in Libraries, and Jay Liebowitz, whose most recent book Successes and Failures of Knowledge Management was published just this year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST will be at RDAP!</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2016/04/27/iassist-will-be-rdap/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 12:59:30 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2016/04/27/iassist-will-be-rdap/</guid>
      <description>For those of you attending the RDAP Summit next week in Atlanta, GA, USA, be sure to keep an eye out for IASSIST. We are a sponsoring organization&amp;mdash;check out the advance thank you blog post from RDAP.
Our VP, Jen Green, will be on the scene with promoting IASSIST at the poster session. Be sure to stop by to say &amp;ldquo;hi&amp;rdquo; and pick up your very own IASSIST logo button. Looking forward to hearing the report back from RDAP!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International Digital Curation Conference 2016 (IDCC16)</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2016/03/07/international-digital-curation-conference-2016-idcc16-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2016 04:05:45 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2016/03/07/international-digital-curation-conference-2016-idcc16-0/</guid>
      <description>The International Digital Curation Conference 2016 was in Amsterdam between 23-24 February.
IASSIST was again a sponsor, and presented a poster on IASSIST members&amp;rsquo; activities. In addition, plenty of familiar faces were present including our current IASSIST president and three former ones.
This year&amp;rsquo;s conference was the eleventh IDCC and took the title of &amp;ldquo;Visible data, invisible infrastructure&amp;rdquo;. This asks what can we do to make the hard work of preserving data and making it and keeping it usable as easy as possible for researchers to use and as unobtrusive as possible in their work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking Back/Moving Forward - Reflections on the First Ten Years of Open Repositories</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2015/07/03/reflections-on-first-ten-years-of-open-repositories/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2015 01:15:01 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2015/07/03/reflections-on-first-ten-years-of-open-repositories/</guid>
      <description>Open Repositories conference celebrated its first decade by having four full days of exciting workshops, keynotes, sessions, 24/7 talks, and development track and repository interest group sessions in Indianapolis, USA. All the fun took place in the second week of June. The OR2015 conference was themed &amp;ldquo;Looking Back/Moving Forward: Open Repositories at the Crossroads&amp;rdquo; and it brought over 400 repository developers and managers, librarians and library IT professionals, service providers and other experts to hot and humid Indy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A decade against decay: the 10th International Digital Curation Conference</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2015/02/17/decade-against-decay-10th-international-digital-curation-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2015 05:34:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2015/02/17/decade-against-decay-10th-international-digital-curation-conference/</guid>
      <description>The International Digital Curation Conference (IDCC) is now ten years old. On the evidence of its most recent conference, is in rude health and growing fast.
IDCC is the first time IASSIST decided to formally support another organisational conference. I think it was a wise investment given the quality of plenaries, presentations, posters, and discussions.
DCC already has available a number of blogs covering the substance of sessions, including an excellent summary by IASSIST web editor, Robin Rice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Registration for the Data Information Literacy Symposium is now open</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/05/22/registration-data-information-literacy-symposium-now-open/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2013 04:46:58 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/05/22/registration-data-information-literacy-symposium-now-open/</guid>
      <description>Please join us for the Data Information Literacy Symposium at Purdue University in West Lafayette, IN, on September 23rd, and 24th 2013. Program: This symposium will explore roles for practicing librarians in teaching competencies in data management and curation to graduate students. With support from the Institute of Museum and Library Services, librarians from Purdue University, Cornell University, the University of Minnesota and the University of Oregon have investigated this topic through developing and implementing &amp;ldquo;data information literacy&amp;rdquo; (DIL) instruction programs for graduate students in a range of science and engineering disciplines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ICPSR Webinar on working with IRB&#39;s</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2012/11/26/icpsr-webinar-working-irbs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2012 15:23:52 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2012/11/26/icpsr-webinar-working-irbs/</guid>
      <description>For those of you who follow the IASSIST Interest Group on Human Subjects Review Committees and Privacy and Confidentiality in Research, you might be interested in this webinar:
Amy Pienta and Kaye Marz of ICPSR&amp;rsquo;s National Addiction and HIV Data Archive Program will present a webinar on Nov. 28 titled &amp;ldquo;Navigating Your IRB to Share Research Data.&amp;rdquo;
They will share guidelines for working with Institutional Review Boards to release data that may contain sensitive information, such as studies on substance abuse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data-related blog posts coming out of Open Repositories 2012 conference</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2012/09/19/data-related-blog-posts-coming-out-open-repositories-2012-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2012 11:02:17 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2012/09/19/data-related-blog-posts-coming-out-open-repositories-2012-conference/</guid>
      <description>[]{.image-right}I &amp;lsquo;d been meaning to write an IASSIST blog post about OR 2012, hosted by the University of Edinburgh&amp;rsquo;s Host Organising Committee led by Co-Chair and IASSISTer Stuart Macdonald in July, because it had such good DATA content.
Fortunately Simon Hodson, the UK&amp;rsquo;s JISC Managing Research Data Programme Manager, has provided this introduction and has allowed me to post it here, with further links to his analytic blog posts, and even those contain further links to OTHER blog posts talking about OR2012 and data!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A list of upcoming Big Data conferences</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2012/08/25/list-upcoming-big-data-conferences/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Aug 2012 10:38:55 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2012/08/25/list-upcoming-big-data-conferences/</guid>
      <description>check out AnalyticBridge (a social network for analytic professionals) Here is a reposting their list of upcoming conferences.
Conferences Discussions - AnalyticBridge{.rss-title}
 Sentiment Analysis Symposium, October 29-30, San Francisco{.rss-item} Beyond Hadoop: next generation of big data analytics - August 22{.rss-item} SFBay ACM - Data Mining Hackathon on Big Data on August 18{.rss-item} Data Mining: Failure to Launch ( Live Predictive Analytics Web Event 8/15 &amp;amp; 9/6 ){.rss-item} Predictive Analytics &amp;amp; Data Mining Vendor-Neutral Courses [ Wash, DC - Sept | Las Vegas - Dec ]{.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Discussion Group at ALA Annual</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2012/06/29/data-discussion-group-ala-annual/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2012 13:47:45 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2012/06/29/data-discussion-group-ala-annual/</guid>
      <description>A number of U.S. IASSISTers were at the recent American Library Association Annual Conference in Anaheim, California. This years program (finally!) featured a number of data related topics, including the third meeting of the Association of College &amp;amp; Research Libraries Numeric and Geospatial Data Interest Group (DIG). Our discussion covered topics such as content management systems, data hosting, collection development for small data, and changing professional roles. A full report of the meeting is available at http://connect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workshop on Persistent Identifiers for Social Science Data</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/02/11/workshop-persistent-identifiers-social-science-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2011 05:54:27 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/02/11/workshop-persistent-identifiers-social-science-data/</guid>
      <description>The IDSC of IZA in Bonn, Germany, along with GESIS and the RatSWD, sponsored a workshop on Persistent Identifiers in the Social Sciences held February 1-2 in Bonn. The presentations are now online at:
http://www.iza.org/conference_files/PeIdSS2011/viewProgram?conf_id=2013</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SPARC Digital Repositories meeting includes session on open data</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2010/11/10/sparc-digital-repositories-meeting-includes-session-open-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2010 06:41:49 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2010/11/10/sparc-digital-repositories-meeting-includes-session-open-data/</guid>
      <description>Kathleen Shearer of the Canadian Association of Research Libraries organized and chaired a panel on Open Data was held at the SPARC Digital Repositories meeting on November 8, 2010. IASSIST members Gail Steinhart and Chuck Humphrey were two of the three members on this panel. Kevin Ashley, Director of the Digital Curation Centre (DCC), was the third. It has been two years since this group last met and the attendance was said to have doubled between meetings (looked like there were around 150 people present.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>