<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Canada on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </title>
    <link>https://talatera.github.io/tags/canada/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Canada on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2014 10:01:41 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://talatera.github.io/tags/canada/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Chronology of data library and data centres</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2014/11/20/chronology-data-library-and-data-centres/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2014 10:01:41 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2014/11/20/chronology-data-library-and-data-centres/</guid>
      <description>A few days ago I asked on the IASSIST mailing list for some help in order to find out dates of creation of data libraries, data centres and such services. It was overwhelming to receive answers from colleagues from everywhere with dates and some other useful information about the establishment of local data support and national services.
  Newton, author of Chronology of Kingdoms   There is a wealth of information in this community around these issues and with the increasing importance of data services we need to make sure we collect and make this information accessible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the Release of the CRDCN Dataset Builder</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/10/01/announcing-release-crdcn-dataset-builder/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 11:05:11 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/10/01/announcing-release-crdcn-dataset-builder/</guid>
      <description>CRDCN Database Builder Splash Screen   The Canadian Research Data Centre Network (CRDCN) is pleased to announce the release of the CRDCN Dataset Builder.
In collaboration with Statistics Canada and Metadata Technology North America, the Dataset Builder allows researchers working (or intending to work) in a Canadian RDC the ability to browse, search for and select variables in the Statistics Canada surveys currently housed in the RDCs. Utilizing DDI Lifecycle metadata, the Dataset Builder allows researchers to find and select variables, as well as produce SAS, SPSS or Stata syntax to help read in and format the variables, and produce customized documentation (Layout and Codebooks) for the dataset they create using the app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New IASSIST Quarterly now available!</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/05/16/new-iassist-quarterly-now-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2013 05:56:15 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/05/16/new-iassist-quarterly-now-available/</guid>
      <description>Editor notes: Data bring maps, archive brings data, and accreditation brings research
This issue (volume 36-1, 2012) of the IASSIST Quarterly (IQ) is the first of the 2012 issues. This editorial is written in March 2013 when many IASSIST people have received acceptance for their papers at the upcoming conference IASSIST 2013 in Cologne. I am certain there will be many interesting presentations at the conference. However, presenters can reach a greater audience by having their paper published in forthcoming issues of the IQ.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST Fellows 2013</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/05/06/iassist-fellows-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2013 19:38:07 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/05/06/iassist-fellows-2013/</guid>
      <description>** **
The IASSIST Fellows Committee is glad to announce through this post the six recipients of the 2013 IASSIST Fellowship award. We are extremely excited to have such a diverse and interesting group with different backgrounds and experience and encourage IASSISTers to welcome them at our conference in Cologne, Germany.
Please find below their names, countries and brief bios:
**Chifundo Kanjala (Tanzania) **
Chifundo currently works as a Data Manager and data documentalist for an HIV research group called ALPHA network based at London School of Hygiene and Tropical Medicine&amp;rsquo;s department of Population Health, Chifundo spends most of his time in Mwanza, Tanzania but do travel from time around Southern and Eastern Africa to work with colleagues in the ALPHA network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>North American DDI Conference April 2013</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/01/23/north-american-ddi-conference-april-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 14:30:08 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/01/23/north-american-ddi-conference-april-2013/</guid>
      <description>Registration is now open for NADDI 2013 (http://www.ipsr.ku.edu/naddi/). The North American Data Documentation Initiative Conference (NADDI) is an opportunity for those using DDI and those interested in learning more about it to come together and learn from each other. Patterned after the successful European DDI conference (EDDI), NADDI 2013 will be a two day conference with invited and contributed presentations. This conference should be of interest to both researchers and data professionals in the social sciences and other disciplines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>40 years of IASSIST Conferences: Toronto to host IASSIST 2014</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/01/18/40-years-iassist-conferences-toronto-host-iassist-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2013 06:33:52 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/01/18/40-years-iassist-conferences-toronto-host-iassist-2014/</guid>
      <description>IASSIST Members,
I&amp;rsquo;m pleased to announce that IASSIST&amp;rsquo;s 40th anniversary conference in 2014 has been awarded to the city where it all started - Toronto, Canada!
Come join us to celebrate June 3-6, 2014, where local hosts from Ryerson University, the University of Toronto, and York University are looking forward to quoting Tourism Toronto&amp;rsquo;s greeting of &amp;ldquo;Welcome to Toronto! We&amp;rsquo;ve been expecting you!&amp;rdquo;
Meanwhile, our friends at GESIS - Leibniz Institute for the Social Sciences are gearing up to host IASSIST 2013 in Cologne, Germany from May 28 &amp;ndash;31.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data can be cool</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/10/06/data-can-be-cool/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2011 09:46:59 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/10/06/data-can-be-cool/</guid>
      <description>As I prepare to leave Guelph there are lots of things I will miss - but what I will maybe miss most is the Data Resource Centre and the creative people who work there. If you link to the picasa album below you will see some awesome posters they have made to showcase services and bring people into the world of Data and GIS. The images on some of the posters are really powerful&amp;hellip;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Torture, Numbers, and Digital Tape</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/02/02/torture-numbers-and-digital-tape/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2011 07:02:15 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/02/02/torture-numbers-and-digital-tape/</guid>
      <description>The IASSIST Quarterly (IQ) volume 33 number 3 is now on the web:
[http://iassistdata.org/iq/issue/33/3]
With this issue concentrating on quantitative investigations and the use of statistics, I came to think of the Mark Twain citation &amp;ldquo;There are three kinds of lies: lies, damned lies, and statistics.&amp;rdquo; With the violent title of the first article (see below), the article on numbers and statistics, and the report from a national statistics agency, the &amp;ldquo;Torture,Numbers, and Digital Tape&amp;rdquo; title surfaced.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SPARC Digital Repositories meeting includes session on open data</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2010/11/10/sparc-digital-repositories-meeting-includes-session-open-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2010 06:41:49 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2010/11/10/sparc-digital-repositories-meeting-includes-session-open-data/</guid>
      <description>Kathleen Shearer of the Canadian Association of Research Libraries organized and chaired a panel on Open Data was held at the SPARC Digital Repositories meeting on November 8, 2010. IASSIST members Gail Steinhart and Chuck Humphrey were two of the three members on this panel. Kevin Ashley, Director of the Digital Curation Centre (DCC), was the third. It has been two years since this group last met and the attendance was said to have doubled between meetings (looked like there were around 150 people present.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More on the Canadian Long Form Census</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2010/10/06/more-canadian-long-form-census/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2010 12:51:50 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2010/10/06/more-canadian-long-form-census/</guid>
      <description>This is a truly fascinating set of events unfurling in Canada. I thought I would add a bit (in too many words) for those of you who don&amp;rsquo;t have the pleasure of Canadian media outlets. J
Parliament recently resumed and there have been a number of significant issues, like abolishing the LONG Gun Registry, G8/G20 spending and a new Governor General who happens to be a former University President. Still, the LONG form census continues to make headlines &amp;ndash; do you notice a theme around abolishing programs with the word LONG in them?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST letter to Canadian Government on loss of 2011 Census long form</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2010/10/05/iassist-letter-canadian-government-loss-2011-census-long-form/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2010 13:44:28 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2010/10/05/iassist-letter-canadian-government-loss-2011-census-long-form/</guid>
      <description>Industry Canada Office of the Honourable Tony Clement Minister of Industry C.D. Howe Building 235 Queen Street Ottawa, ON K1A 0H5 25 July 2010
Dear Minister Clement
We write on behalf of the International Association of Social Science Information Services and Technology. IASSIST is an international organization of professionals working in and with information technology and data services to support research and teaching in the social sciences. Its 300 members are from a variety of workplaces, including data archives, statistical agencies, research centers, libraries, academic departments, government departments, and non-profit organizations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CAPDU - Canadian Census</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2010/07/16/capdu-canadian-census/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2010 13:22:20 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2010/07/16/capdu-canadian-census/</guid>
      <description>More info on what the response has been in Canada is available here: http://capdu.wordpress.com/ Very interesting to watch this unfold if you are interested in data or interested in how these community responses develop. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canadian census - no more long form</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2010/06/30/canadian-census-no-more-long-form/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2010 06:45:52 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2010/06/30/canadian-census-no-more-long-form/</guid>
      <description>It appears that the Federal Government has decided to no longer have the mandatory long form in the upcoming census (2011). This is the list of detailed questions filled out by about 20% of households. It will be replaced with another voluntary survey. This has many potential implications, especially for those using the census &amp;lsquo;longitudinally&amp;rsquo;. It may have some positive spinoffs, since the replacement has a potentially larger sample size. The disturbing part is that we are not aware of any consultation with the research community.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>