<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>IASSIST 2009 on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </title>
    <link>https://talatera.github.io/tags/iassist-2009/</link>
    <description>Recent content in IASSIST 2009 on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2011 07:02:15 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://talatera.github.io/tags/iassist-2009/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Torture, Numbers, and Digital Tape</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/02/02/torture-numbers-and-digital-tape/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2011 07:02:15 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/02/02/torture-numbers-and-digital-tape/</guid>
      <description>The IASSIST Quarterly (IQ) volume 33 number 3 is now on the web:
[http://iassistdata.org/iq/issue/33/3]
With this issue concentrating on quantitative investigations and the use of statistics, I came to think of the Mark Twain citation &amp;ldquo;There are three kinds of lies: lies, damned lies, and statistics.&amp;rdquo; With the violent title of the first article (see below), the article on numbers and statistics, and the report from a national statistics agency, the &amp;ldquo;Torture,Numbers, and Digital Tape&amp;rdquo; title surfaced.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conference webcasts and presentations online!</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2009/06/09/conference-webcasts-and-presentations-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2009 12:40:46 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2009/06/09/conference-webcasts-and-presentations-online/</guid>
      <description>A week has passed since IASSIST 2009. I hope most of you have made it safely back home by now - and are ready to refresh the memories by watching the conference webcasts and viewing presentations. Webcasts of all three plenaries and Thursday and Friday&amp;rsquo;s concurrent sessions in the Small Auditorium are now available. We didn&amp;rsquo;t have cameras available during the Wednesday sessions, so no videos of these presentations, sorry! But most of the presentations are already online - a few are still missing either because we didn&amp;rsquo;t have them or we are waiting for an updated version.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST 2009 Tweets!</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2009/03/03/iassist-2009-tweets/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2009 10:51:23 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2009/03/03/iassist-2009-tweets/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ve created a Twitter feed for conference info, updates and impressions. See it at http://twitter.com/IASSIST2009 or there&amp;rsquo;s a link on the program page.
Before the conference, it will be mostly logistic and planning information. At the conference, IASSISTers will be tweeting about the conference itself: comments, suggestions, updates, and other twitter-friendly information. We&amp;rsquo;ve got a few volunteer tweeters but more are always welcome.
If you are interested in tweeting from the conference, contact Tuomas Alatera who will set you up with a HootSuite account so you can help us Twitter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Registration for the IASSIST 2009 is open</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2009/02/24/registration-iassist-2009-open/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2009 10:03:01 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2009/02/24/registration-iassist-2009-open/</guid>
      <description>Tervetuloa Tampereelle, Welcome to Tampere!
Registration for the 2009 IASSIST conference is now officially open. On the conference web site there is more information on registration, accommodations and excursions.
The Early Bird rate is valid until March 24, 2009. Please note that a deposit of one night for accommodation should be paid together with the registration fees. Cancellations (conference attendance, hotels, tours) on or before April 24 will receive a refund minus the administrative fees.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>