<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>United States on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </title>
    <link>https://talatera.github.io/tags/united-states/</link>
    <description>Recent content in United States on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2016 08:27:34 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://talatera.github.io/tags/united-states/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST sponsors IFLA 2016 Knowledge Management conference</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2016/10/21/iassist-sponsors-ifla-2016-knowledge-management-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2016 08:27:34 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2016/10/21/iassist-sponsors-ifla-2016-knowledge-management-conference/</guid>
      <description>IASSIST proudly sponsored a full-day conference about knowledge management (KM) on August 12, 2016 in Cincinnati, Ohio, USA at the University of Cincinnati. The theme of the conference was Sharing Practices and Actions for Making Best Use of Organizational Knowledge in Libraries.The conference took place as part of the International Federation of Library Associations&amp;rsquo; (IFLA) annual conference held this year in Columbus, Ohio, USA.
The KM conference featured two keynote speakers: Valerie Forrestal, author of the 2015 book Knowledge Management in Libraries, and Jay Liebowitz, whose most recent book Successes and Failures of Knowledge Management was published just this year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST will be at RDAP!</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2016/04/27/iassist-will-be-rdap/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 12:59:30 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2016/04/27/iassist-will-be-rdap/</guid>
      <description>For those of you attending the RDAP Summit next week in Atlanta, GA, USA, be sure to keep an eye out for IASSIST. We are a sponsoring organization&amp;mdash;check out the advance thank you blog post from RDAP.
Our VP, Jen Green, will be on the scene with promoting IASSIST at the poster session. Be sure to stop by to say &amp;ldquo;hi&amp;rdquo; and pick up your very own IASSIST logo button. Looking forward to hearing the report back from RDAP!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“You can’t have a democratic society, without having a good data base.”</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2015/04/09/you-cant-have-a-democratic-society-without-having-a-good-data-base/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2015 09:49:43 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2015/04/09/you-cant-have-a-democratic-society-without-having-a-good-data-base/</guid>
      <description>Janet L. Norwood, former US Bureau of Labor Statistics commissioner, dies On the passing of this iconic defender of the neutrality of public data, I am struck how important Janet Norwood was to establishing a sound path for data advocacy as well as reminded of how necessary it is to have continuous education about this topic. In fact, swimming in ready-access to data as we are today, it&amp;rsquo;s especially important that we, as data professionals, remain alert to and defend a couple of aphorisms:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chronology of data library and data centres</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2014/11/20/chronology-data-library-and-data-centres/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2014 10:01:41 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2014/11/20/chronology-data-library-and-data-centres/</guid>
      <description>A few days ago I asked on the IASSIST mailing list for some help in order to find out dates of creation of data libraries, data centres and such services. It was overwhelming to receive answers from colleagues from everywhere with dates and some other useful information about the establishment of local data support and national services.
  Newton, author of Chronology of Kingdoms   There is a wealth of information in this community around these issues and with the increasing importance of data services we need to make sure we collect and make this information accessible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scientific Data Repositories Issue Call for Change on Funding Models for Data Archives </title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/09/27/scientific-data-repositories-issue-call-change-funding-models-data-archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2013 10:22:17 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/09/27/scientific-data-repositories-issue-call-change-funding-models-data-archives/</guid>
      <description>For Immediate Release September 16, 2013 Contact: Mark Thompson-Kolar, 734-615-7904 mdmtk@umich.edu
(Ann Arbor, MI) &amp;mdash; Representatives of 25 organizations that archive scientific data today released a Call for Action urging the creation of sustainable funding streams for domain repositories &amp;mdash; data archives with close ties to scientific communities.
The document was developed after a meeting of data repositories across the social and natural sciences June 24-25, 2013, in Ann Arbor. The meeting was organized by the Inter-university Consortium for Political and Social Research (ICPSR) at the University of Michigan and supported by the Alfred P.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Congratulations to Dan Tsang and Wendy Watkins!</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/08/16/congratulations-dan-tsang-and-wendy-watkins/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2013 09:40:19 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/08/16/congratulations-dan-tsang-and-wendy-watkins/</guid>
      <description>As some of you may know, Dan Tsang and Wendy Watkins have been named the 2013 ICSPR Flanagan Award winners for distinguished service as an ICPSR OR, http://www.icpsr.umich.edu/icpsrweb/ICPSR/support/announcements/2013/07/icpsr-announces-2013-warren-e-miller
UC-Irvine recognizes Dan here, http://www.lib.uci.edu//features/spotlights/dt-award.html Perhaps a Canadian colleague has a similar link for Wendy.
Congratulations to both Dan and Wendy!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST Fellows 2013</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/05/06/iassist-fellows-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2013 19:38:07 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/05/06/iassist-fellows-2013/</guid>
      <description>** **
The IASSIST Fellows Committee is glad to announce through this post the six recipients of the 2013 IASSIST Fellowship award. We are extremely excited to have such a diverse and interesting group with different backgrounds and experience and encourage IASSISTers to welcome them at our conference in Cologne, Germany.
Please find below their names, countries and brief bios:
**Chifundo Kanjala (Tanzania) **
Chifundo currently works as a Data Manager and data documentalist for an HIV research group called ALPHA network based at London School of Hygiene and Tropical Medicine&amp;rsquo;s department of Population Health, Chifundo spends most of his time in Mwanza, Tanzania but do travel from time around Southern and Eastern Africa to work with colleagues in the ALPHA network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update from COSSA: Changes to the Common Rule: The Implications for the Social and Behavioral Sciences</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/03/25/update-cossa-changes-common-rule-implications-social-and-behavioral-sciences/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 14:34:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/03/25/update-cossa-changes-common-rule-implications-social-and-behavioral-sciences/</guid>
      <description>This is from the COSSA Newsletter ([Consortium of Social Science Associations).]{.st} March 25, 2013 Volume 32, Issue 6 Regarding a workshop on proposed changes to the Common Rule. Readers of these blog entries will recall that these proposed changes would require that data identitified in social science research would be required to meet HIPPA standards; potentially rendering many public datasets unuseful for research purposes.
A link to the webcast is here: http://sites.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>North American DDI Conference April 2013</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/01/23/north-american-ddi-conference-april-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 14:30:08 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/01/23/north-american-ddi-conference-april-2013/</guid>
      <description>Registration is now open for NADDI 2013 (http://www.ipsr.ku.edu/naddi/). The North American Data Documentation Initiative Conference (NADDI) is an opportunity for those using DDI and those interested in learning more about it to come together and learn from each other. Patterned after the successful European DDI conference (EDDI), NADDI 2013 will be a two day conference with invited and contributed presentations. This conference should be of interest to both researchers and data professionals in the social sciences and other disciplines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social Sciences Librarian </title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2012/09/25/social-sciences-librarian/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2012 12:41:12 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2012/09/25/social-sciences-librarian/</guid>
      <description>Position: Social Sciences Librarian Available: January 1, 2013
The University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill seeks a creative, enthusiastic, and collaborative Social Sciences Librarian to join the Davis Library Research and Instructional Services Department as the Subject Librarian for the departments of Sociology and Political Science. The Social Sciences Librarian will apply state of the art technology to reference and research work, innovative outreach, evolving collection development, and dynamic data services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Council of Professional Associations on Federal Statistics (COPAFS) meeting notes</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/12/08/council-professional-associations-federal-statistics-copafs-meeting-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2011 14:07:27 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/12/08/council-professional-associations-federal-statistics-copafs-meeting-notes/</guid>
      <description>I was lucky enough to be able to sit in on the most recent COPAFS meeting in place of our regular liaison Judith Rowe. While the topics were very different than the issues I usually deal with at work, I found the presentations really interesting. Here&amp;rsquo;s an abridged version of my notes.
 News:
Ed Spar will be stepping down as Executive Director at the end of 2012. The board will be launching a search and will be engaging a search firm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stephen S. Clark Library for Maps, Government Information, and Data Services is open for business!</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/12/05/stephen-s-clark-library-maps-government-information-and-data-services-open-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2011 21:06:50 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/12/05/stephen-s-clark-library-maps-government-information-and-data-services-open-business/</guid>
      <description>Three cheers for Jen Green!!!  When not keeping IASSIST finances in check as the IASSIST Treasurer, Jennifer Green, director of the new Stephen S. Clark Library for Maps, Government Information, and Data Services, at the University of Michigan has been busy getting the library in shape for the recent opening day! Check out the announcement of the grand opening festivities in the Record Update (a publication of the Office of the Vice President for Communications at the University of Michigan) and don&amp;rsquo;t miss the brand new website of the Setphen S.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Access to Federally Funded Research</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/11/04/open-access-federally-funded-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2011 11:22:18 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/11/04/open-access-federally-funded-research/</guid>
      <description>Got something to say about &amp;ldquo;ensuring long-term stewardship and encouraging broad public access to unclassified digital data that result from federally funded scientific research&amp;rdquo;?
  The White House Office for Science and Technology Policy (OSTP) released two public consultations today, one on OA for data and one on OA for publications arising from publicly-funded research. Responses are due in early January. Please spread the word. Submit your own comments and/or work with colleagues to submit comments on behalf of your institution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ANES Announcement: The ANES 2012 Time Series Study</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/07/15/anes-announcement-anes-2012-time-series-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2011 08:05:47 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/07/15/anes-announcement-anes-2012-time-series-study/</guid>
      <description>On June 30, 2011, the American National Election Studies (ANES) began accepting proposals for questions to include on the ANES 2012 Time Series Study. Proposals may be submitted through the ANES Online Commons. The following describes the goals of this study and the opportunity to include questions on it.
About The ANES 2012 Time Series Study
The ANES&amp;rsquo;s core mission is to promote cutting-edge and broadly-collaborative research on American national elections.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roper Centre recognition</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/07/roper-centre-recognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2011 09:15:10 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/07/roper-centre-recognition/</guid>
      <description>To iassist:
It isn&amp;rsquo;t every day that an incoming university president envies data over basketball! Congratulations to our colleagues at the Roper Center for this well deserved recognition.
Susan Herbst, incoming President at the University of Connecticut: What about UConn drew you here?
&amp;ldquo;There are many aspects of UConn that attracted me, but the primary one is the spirit of the institution. Growing up in the Northeast, I knew many people who attended UConn and held a deep, abiding love of the University.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Torture, Numbers, and Digital Tape</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/02/02/torture-numbers-and-digital-tape/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2011 07:02:15 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/02/02/torture-numbers-and-digital-tape/</guid>
      <description>The IASSIST Quarterly (IQ) volume 33 number 3 is now on the web:
[http://iassistdata.org/iq/issue/33/3]
With this issue concentrating on quantitative investigations and the use of statistics, I came to think of the Mark Twain citation &amp;ldquo;There are three kinds of lies: lies, damned lies, and statistics.&amp;rdquo; With the violent title of the first article (see below), the article on numbers and statistics, and the report from a national statistics agency, the &amp;ldquo;Torture,Numbers, and Digital Tape&amp;rdquo; title surfaced.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SPARC Digital Repositories meeting includes session on open data</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2010/11/10/sparc-digital-repositories-meeting-includes-session-open-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2010 06:41:49 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2010/11/10/sparc-digital-repositories-meeting-includes-session-open-data/</guid>
      <description>Kathleen Shearer of the Canadian Association of Research Libraries organized and chaired a panel on Open Data was held at the SPARC Digital Repositories meeting on November 8, 2010. IASSIST members Gail Steinhart and Chuck Humphrey were two of the three members on this panel. Kevin Ashley, Director of the Digital Curation Centre (DCC), was the third. It has been two years since this group last met and the attendance was said to have doubled between meetings (looked like there were around 150 people present.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>E-Science and Data Support</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2010/08/25/e-science-and-data-support/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2010 13:32:15 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2010/08/25/e-science-and-data-support/</guid>
      <description>[[[E-Science and Data Support Services: A Study of Association of Research Libraries Member Institutions http://bit.ly/cKmaO6]{.entry-content}]{.status-content}]{.status-body} .
This was tweeted to our site last week, but in case you weren&amp;rsquo;t following the tweets, this is worth a read. There are quotes from IASSIST folks, and there is some interesting information in it, in terms of what people are doing. This may help shape what you are doing. It has been blogged and tweeted elsewhere and is now posted on the Educause site.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>