<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Metadata &amp; Standards on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </title>
    <link>https://talatera.github.io/tags/metadata-standards/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Metadata &amp; Standards on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 08:50:55 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://talatera.github.io/tags/metadata-standards/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST Quarterly (IQ) volume 40-2 is now on the website:  Revolution in the air</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2017/02/27/iassist-quarterly-iq-volume-40-2-now-website-revolution-air/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 08:50:55 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2017/02/27/iassist-quarterly-iq-volume-40-2-now-website-revolution-air/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the second issue of Volume 40 of the IASSIST Quarterly (IQ 40:2, 2016). We present three papers in this issue.
http://iassistdata.org/iq/issue/40/2
First, there are two papers on the Data Documentation Initiative that have their own special introduction. I want to express my respect and gratitude to Joachim Wackerow (GESIS - Leibniz Institute for the Social Sciences). Joachim (Achim) and Mary Vardigan (University of Michigan) have several times and for many years communicated to and advised the readers of the IASSIST Quarterly on the continuing development of the DDI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST 2016 Program At-A-Glance, Part 2: Data infrastructure, data processing and research data management</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2016/05/06/iassist-2016-program-glance-part-2-data-infrastructure-data-processing-and-research-data-manage/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2016 07:13:42 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2016/05/06/iassist-2016-program-glance-part-2-data-infrastructure-data-processing-and-research-data-manage/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s another list of highlights from IASSIST2016 which is focusing on the data revolution. For previous highlights, see here.
Infrastructure  For those of you with an interest in technical infrastructure, the University of Applied Sciences HTW Chur will showcase an early protype MMRepo (1 June, 3F), whose function is to store qualitative and quantitative data into one big data repository.   The UK Data Service will present the following panel &amp;ldquo;The CESSDA Technical Framework - what is it and why is it needed?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Latest Issue of IQ Available!  Data Documentation Initiative - Results, Tools, and  Further Initiatives </title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2016/03/24/latest-issue-iq-available-data-documentation-initiative-results-tools-and-further-initiatives/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2016 07:09:42 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2016/03/24/latest-issue-iq-available-data-documentation-initiative-results-tools-and-further-initiatives/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to thethird issue of Volume 39 of the IASSIST Quarterly (IQ 39:3, 2015). This special issue is guest edited by Joachim Wackerow of GESIS &amp;ndash; Leibniz Institute for the Social Sciences in Germany and Mary Vardigan of ICPSR at the University of Michigan, USA. That sentence is a direct plagiarism from the editor&amp;rsquo;s notes of the recent double issue (IQ 38:4 &amp;amp; 39:1). We are very grateful for all the work Mary and Achim have carried out and are developing further in the continuing story of the Data Documentation Initiative (DDI), and for their efforts in presenting the work here in the ASSIST Quarterly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IQ double issue 38(4)/39(1) is up, and so is vol 39(2)!</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2015/12/11/iq-double-issue-384391-and-so-vol-392/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2015 12:45:44 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2015/12/11/iq-double-issue-384391-and-so-vol-392/</guid>
      <description>Hi folks! A lovely gift for your reading pleasure over the holidays, we present two, yes, TWO issues of the IASSIST Quarterly. The first is the double issue, 38(4)/39(1) with guest editors, Joachim Wacherow of GESIS &amp;ndash; Leibniz Institute for the Social Sciences in Germany and Mary Vardigan of ICPSR at the University of Michigan, USA. This issue focuses on the Data Documentation Initiative (DDI) and how it makes meta-analysis possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>North American DDI Conference April 2013</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/01/23/north-american-ddi-conference-april-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 14:30:08 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/01/23/north-american-ddi-conference-april-2013/</guid>
      <description>Registration is now open for NADDI 2013 (http://www.ipsr.ku.edu/naddi/). The North American Data Documentation Initiative Conference (NADDI) is an opportunity for those using DDI and those interested in learning more about it to come together and learn from each other. Patterned after the successful European DDI conference (EDDI), NADDI 2013 will be a two day conference with invited and contributed presentations. This conference should be of interest to both researchers and data professionals in the social sciences and other disciplines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>86 helpful tools for the data professional PLUS 45 bonus tools</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/10/29/86-helpful-tools-data-professional-plus-45-bonus-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2011 17:04:17 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/10/29/86-helpful-tools-data-professional-plus-45-bonus-tools/</guid>
      <description>I have been working on this (mostly) annotated collection of tools and articles that I believe would be of help to both the data dabbler and professional. If you are a data scientist, data analyst or data dummy, chances are there is something in here for you. I included a list of tools, such as programming languages and web-based utilities, [data mining]{.zem_slink} resources, some prominent organizations in the field, repositories where you can play with data, events you may want to attend and important articles you should take a look at.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SBE 2020 white papers available</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/02/04/sbe-2020-white-papers-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2011 00:14:24 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/02/04/sbe-2020-white-papers-available/</guid>
      <description>The Directorate for the Social, Behavioral, and Economic Sciences of the National Science Foundation (NSF/SBE) has released today a collection of white papers contributed under the &amp;ldquo;SBE 2020: Future Research in the Social, Behavioral &amp;amp; Economic Sciences&amp;rdquo; initiative. Authors were asked to outline grand challenge questions that are both foundational and transformative. For information, please visit: http://www.nsf.gov/sbe/sbe_2020/index.cfm
[](http://www.nsf.gov/sbe/sbe_2020/index.cfm){.moz-txt-link-freetext}The Open Data Foundation contributed to the following:
Maximizing the Potential of Data: Modern IT Tools, Best Practices, and Metadata Standards for SBE Sciences Pascal Heus (pascal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Special Double Issue of IQ on Data Documentation Initiative</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2010/11/28/iq-ddi-special/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Nov 2010 10:44:46 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2010/11/28/iq-ddi-special/</guid>
      <description>Guest Editors Notes - Mary Vardigan and Joachim Wackerow Welcome to a special double issue of the IASSIST Quarterly featuring articles focused on the Data Documentation Initiative (DDI), a metadata standard for the social sciences. We are proud to present these six articles, which explore various projects related to DDI 3 and its enhanced features.
The articles draw on previous presentations and papers created in connection with the 2009 &amp;ldquo;Expert Workshop on Implementation of DDI3 &amp;ndash; Advanced Topics&amp;rdquo; held in Wadern, Germany; the 2009 European DDI Users Group (EDDI) meeting held in Bonn, Germany; and the IASSIST conferences held in Tampere, Finland (2009) and Ithaca, New York, USA (2010).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>