<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Conferences on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </title>
    <link>https://talatera.github.io/conferences/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Conferences on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://talatera.github.io/conferences/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Conference Code of Conduct</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/conferences/conference-code-of-conduct/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/conferences/conference-code-of-conduct/</guid>
      <description>The International Association for Social Science Information Services &amp;amp; Technology (IASSIST) holds its conferences to enable its members to share research on, and innovations in, the social sciences data lifecycle, to receive continuing education and to build professional networks.
To provide all participants – members and other attendees, speakers, exhibitors, staff and volunteers – the opportunity to benefit from the event, IASSIST is dedicated to a positive, safe and harassment-free conference experience in which diverse participants may learn, network and enjoy the company of colleagues in an environment of mutual human respect and regardless of gender, sexual orientation, gender identity, gender expression, disability, physical appearance, ethnicity, religion or other group identity or political beliefs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conferences</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/conferences/conferences/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/conferences/conferences/</guid>
      <description>Annual IASSIST Conference 46th Annual Conference IASSIST 2020 / 2021 Data By Design Gothenburg, Sweden, April 7–9, 2021 (was to be May 19–22, 2020)
Host institution: Swedish National Data Service (SND).
 More information  (March 20, 2020)
It is with heavy hearts that the IASSIST Executive, Local Arrangements, and Program committees announce that IASSIST 2020 will not happen. Given these unsettled times, the health and safety of our community is paramount.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guidelines for Hosting IASSIST Conferences</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/conferences/guidelines-for-hosting-iassist-conferences/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/conferences/guidelines-for-hosting-iassist-conferences/</guid>
      <description>Thinking about welcoming IASSIST to your institution? On this page you will find information on bidding to host an IASSIST Conference and organizing Conference program and local arrangements.
Scroll down for Conference Manuals - guides for those who are responsible of conference program planning or local arrangements.
The following guidelines have been prepared by the IASSIST Administrative Committee to assist those considering proposals to host an IASSIST Conference.
The IASSIST Conference is held annually and is hosted by IASSIST members, drawing upon some level of organisational support from their institution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST members only content</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/conferences/iassist-members-only-content/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/conferences/iassist-members-only-content/</guid>
      <description>Membership administration site (iassistdata.info) You can join, renew and manage your membership at iassistdata.info.
Your login is the email you used to register your membership.
 Membership directory - View the membership directory and edit your profile. Membership renewals - Renew your membership by viewing your profile and following the link in the Membership Details section. This is the most convenient way to renew if there isn&amp;rsquo;t a bundled conference registration and renewal payment available.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>