<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>IASSIST 2013 on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </title>
    <link>https://talatera.github.io/tags/iassist-2013/</link>
    <description>Recent content in IASSIST 2013 on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2013 08:46:58 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://talatera.github.io/tags/iassist-2013/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ich bin ein IASSISTer</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/06/06/ich-bin-ein-iassister/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2013 08:46:58 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/06/06/ich-bin-ein-iassister/</guid>
      <description>From 28-31 May, GESIS - Leibniz Institute for the Social Sciences hosted the 39th Annual Conference of the International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology, aka #iassist2013
IASSIST conferences provide an overview of what&amp;rsquo;s happening in information technology and data services and allow exchange of ideas between participants working in different backgrounds - from social science and humanities to information and computer science. The aim of this year&amp;rsquo;s event was to help us move closer to the dream of technical and organizational measures that make research data discoverable and accessible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST needs YOU to write a blog post about some aspect of the conference</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/06/04/iassist-needs-you-write-blog-post-about-some-aspect-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2013 10:10:18 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/06/04/iassist-needs-you-write-blog-post-about-some-aspect-conference/</guid>
      <description>I could say this is needed because the videos and wifi weren&amp;rsquo;t working, but in fact I&amp;rsquo;d be asking anyway.
Just think how helpful it is for members who could not be with us (and potential members) to get a snapshot of views about what happened. Serious, silly, short, verbose, objective, or ridiculously opinionated impressions of one session, the social events or overall are very welcome.
Turn your personal notes into a gift that keeps on giving.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST 2013 conference song</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/06/02/iassist-2013-conference-song/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2013 14:39:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/06/02/iassist-2013-conference-song/</guid>
      <description>Many thanks to Kate, Dan, and especially Melanie for this year&amp;rsquo;s bit of silliness. Thanks once again to Lynda Kellam for the video.
(Sung to the tune of &amp;ldquo;Lili Marlene&amp;rdquo; If anyone wonders, the connection of the melody with Cologne is that the composer, Norbert Schultze, once studied in Cologne.)
It&amp;rsquo;s 2013 IASSIST, and welcome to Cologne GESIS has endeavored to make us feel at home Data innovation was the theme And wifi problems made the scene We struggled to communicate Some tweets might turn up late</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST Fellows 2013</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/05/06/iassist-fellows-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2013 19:38:07 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/05/06/iassist-fellows-2013/</guid>
      <description>** **
The IASSIST Fellows Committee is glad to announce through this post the six recipients of the 2013 IASSIST Fellowship award. We are extremely excited to have such a diverse and interesting group with different backgrounds and experience and encourage IASSISTers to welcome them at our conference in Cologne, Germany.
Please find below their names, countries and brief bios:
**Chifundo Kanjala (Tanzania) **
Chifundo currently works as a Data Manager and data documentalist for an HIV research group called ALPHA network based at London School of Hygiene and Tropical Medicine&amp;rsquo;s department of Population Health, Chifundo spends most of his time in Mwanza, Tanzania but do travel from time around Southern and Eastern Africa to work with colleagues in the ALPHA network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST 2013 - Early bird registration rates until April 30!</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/04/18/iassist-2013-early-bird-registration-rates-until-april-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2013 13:38:58 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/04/18/iassist-2013-early-bird-registration-rates-until-april-30/</guid>
      <description>GESIS &amp;ndash; Leibniz Institute for the Social Sciences is proud to host the IASSIST 2013 Conference at Maternushaus in Cologne, Germany from May 28-31. The IASSIST 2013 theme is Data Innovation: Increasing Accessibility, Visibility and Sustainability. In line with the theme, the IASSIST Program is streamed into three tracks this year: Research Data Management, Data Developers and Tools and Data Public Services. Presentations cover topics such as standards and processes in data management, metadata extensions and tools, data citation practices, sensitive data and much more!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Become rich and famous: publish in the IQ!</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/04/02/become-rich-and-famous-publish-iq/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 10:22:46 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/04/02/become-rich-and-famous-publish-iq/</guid>
      <description>These days many IASSIST members have received acceptance for their papers to the upcoming conference IASSIST 2013 in Cologne. There will be many interesting presentations at the conference. The conference presentation is your chance to present a project you are involved in, to air your argumentation for special areas, and in general to add to the IASSIST knowledge bank.
Projects are typically focused on support of social science research but the IASSIST related support now takes many forms with the developments of technology and applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST 2013 Fellows update</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/03/20/iassist-2013-fellows-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 14:40:47 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/03/20/iassist-2013-fellows-update/</guid>
      <description>This year the IASSIST Fellows Committee received a grand total of 44 Fellows applications from a strong range of candidates from 28 countries around the globe:[ ]{.Apple-converted-space}[ ]{.Apple-converted-space}
  18 Asia   13 Africa
  7 Europe
  3 North America
  2 Latin America
  1 Australia
  Applications have been evaluated by the IASSIST Fellows Committee and offers have been made to a number of prospective Fellows to attend the annual conference in Cologne, Germany.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>