<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Archives and Service Providers on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </title>
    <link>https://talatera.github.io/tags/data-archives-and-service-providers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Archives and Service Providers on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 May 2016 02:15:18 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://talatera.github.io/tags/data-archives-and-service-providers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Interested in the “data revolution” and what it means for research? Here’s why you should attend IASSIST2016</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2016/05/03/interested-in-the-data-revolution-and-what-it-means-for-research-heres-why-you-should-attend-iassist2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2016 02:15:18 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2016/05/03/interested-in-the-data-revolution-and-what-it-means-for-research-heres-why-you-should-attend-iassist2016/</guid>
      <description>Part 1: Data sharing, new data sources and data protection IASSIST is an international organisation of information technology and data services professionals which aims to provide support to research and teaching in the social sciences. It has over 300 members ranging from data archive staff and librarians to statistical agencies, government departments and non-profit organisations.
The theme of this year&amp;rsquo;s conference is &amp;ldquo;Embracing the &amp;lsquo;data revolution&amp;rsquo;: opportunities and challenges for research&amp;rdquo; and it is the 42nd of its kind, taking place every year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A decade against decay: the 10th International Digital Curation Conference</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2015/02/17/decade-against-decay-10th-international-digital-curation-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2015 05:34:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2015/02/17/decade-against-decay-10th-international-digital-curation-conference/</guid>
      <description>The International Digital Curation Conference (IDCC) is now ten years old. On the evidence of its most recent conference, is in rude health and growing fast.
IDCC is the first time IASSIST decided to formally support another organisational conference. I think it was a wise investment given the quality of plenaries, presentations, posters, and discussions.
DCC already has available a number of blogs covering the substance of sessions, including an excellent summary by IASSIST web editor, Robin Rice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feedback on Data Storage</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2014/02/06/feedback-data-storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2014 13:35:13 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2014/02/06/feedback-data-storage/</guid>
      <description>I posted the following question to the listserv:
&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m in the early days of exploring what I and our library can do for our faculty and grad students. In my case I&amp;rsquo;m particularity interested in the social sciences.
It seems there are three main choices:
  ICPSR(or other domain-specific site)
  Dataverse with my own school&amp;rsquo;s branding
  Local, campus funded storage through an Institutional Repository or something else that can handle larger amounts of data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>White Paper Urges New Approaches to Assure Access to Scientific Data </title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/12/23/white-paper-urges-new-approaches-assure-access-scientific-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2013 06:15:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/12/23/white-paper-urges-new-approaches-assure-access-scientific-data/</guid>
      <description>Press release posted on behalf of Mark Thompson-Kolar, ICPSR.
12/12/2013: (Ann Arbor, MI)&amp;mdash;More than two dozen data repositories serving the social, natural, and physical sciences today released a white paper recommending new approaches to funding sharing and preservation of scientific data. The document emphasizes the need for sustainable funding of domain repositories&amp;mdash;data archives with ties to specific scientific communities.
&amp;ldquo;Sustaining Domain Repositories for Digital Data: A White Paper,&amp;rdquo; is an outcome of a meeting convened June 24-25, 2013, in Ann Arbor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scientific Data Repositories Issue Call for Change on Funding Models for Data Archives </title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/09/27/scientific-data-repositories-issue-call-change-funding-models-data-archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2013 10:22:17 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/09/27/scientific-data-repositories-issue-call-change-funding-models-data-archives/</guid>
      <description>For Immediate Release September 16, 2013 Contact: Mark Thompson-Kolar, 734-615-7904 mdmtk@umich.edu
(Ann Arbor, MI) &amp;mdash; Representatives of 25 organizations that archive scientific data today released a Call for Action urging the creation of sustainable funding streams for domain repositories &amp;mdash; data archives with close ties to scientific communities.
The document was developed after a meeting of data repositories across the social and natural sciences June 24-25, 2013, in Ann Arbor. The meeting was organized by the Inter-university Consortium for Political and Social Research (ICPSR) at the University of Michigan and supported by the Alfred P.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sharing data: good for science, good for you</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/08/26/sharing-data-good-science-good-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2013 08:43:44 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/08/26/sharing-data-good-science-good-you/</guid>
      <description>DANS has published a video to promote storing and sharing data within the research community. The video is available in Dutch and English, and shown on the DANS Youtube channel. The title of the English video is &amp;lsquo;Sharing data: good for science, good for you&amp;rsquo;:http://youtu.be/HJbo-OAaJ1I  &amp;ldquo;Scientific research produces data. The lifetime of these data varies greatly. Stored on a hard disk or USB stick they are likely to be lost in the near future together with the storage medium.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Latin American Open Data site!</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/05/27/new-latin-american-open-data-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2013 06:17:40 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/05/27/new-latin-american-open-data-site/</guid>
      <description>Miguel Paz writes:
 Poderomedia Foundation and PinLatam are launching OpenDataLatinoamerica.org, a regional data repository to free data and use it on Hackathons and other activities by HacksHackers chapters and other organizations.
We are doing this because the road to the future of news has been littered with lost datasets. A day or so after every hackathon and meeting where a group has come together to analyze, compare and understand a particular set of data, someone tries to remember where the successful files were stored.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New IASSIST Quarterly now available!</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/05/16/new-iassist-quarterly-now-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2013 05:56:15 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/05/16/new-iassist-quarterly-now-available/</guid>
      <description>Editor notes: Data bring maps, archive brings data, and accreditation brings research
This issue (volume 36-1, 2012) of the IASSIST Quarterly (IQ) is the first of the 2012 issues. This editorial is written in March 2013 when many IASSIST people have received acceptance for their papers at the upcoming conference IASSIST 2013 in Cologne. I am certain there will be many interesting presentations at the conference. However, presenters can reach a greater audience by having their paper published in forthcoming issues of the IQ.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST Fellows 2013</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/05/06/iassist-fellows-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2013 19:38:07 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/05/06/iassist-fellows-2013/</guid>
      <description>** **
The IASSIST Fellows Committee is glad to announce through this post the six recipients of the 2013 IASSIST Fellowship award. We are extremely excited to have such a diverse and interesting group with different backgrounds and experience and encourage IASSISTers to welcome them at our conference in Cologne, Germany.
Please find below their names, countries and brief bios:
**Chifundo Kanjala (Tanzania) **
Chifundo currently works as a Data Manager and data documentalist for an HIV research group called ALPHA network based at London School of Hygiene and Tropical Medicine&amp;rsquo;s department of Population Health, Chifundo spends most of his time in Mwanza, Tanzania but do travel from time around Southern and Eastern Africa to work with colleagues in the ALPHA network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Results of Data Management Plan Poll</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2012/03/20/results-data-management-plan-poll/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2012 13:00:05 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2012/03/20/results-data-management-plan-poll/</guid>
      <description>Those members who follow IASST-L may recall that about a month ago I launched an informal poll to find out whether or not your data management plan services include reading and reviewing draft plans. I had a total of 22 respondents with the following results:
Does your data management plan service include reading and reviewing draft plans?
 18% (4) - Yes, as a matter of policy. 36% (8) - Not a policy, but I have reviewed them in the past.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stephen S. Clark Library for Maps, Government Information, and Data Services is open for business!</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/12/05/stephen-s-clark-library-maps-government-information-and-data-services-open-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2011 21:06:50 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/12/05/stephen-s-clark-library-maps-government-information-and-data-services-open-business/</guid>
      <description>Three cheers for Jen Green!!!  When not keeping IASSIST finances in check as the IASSIST Treasurer, Jennifer Green, director of the new Stephen S. Clark Library for Maps, Government Information, and Data Services, at the University of Michigan has been busy getting the library in shape for the recent opening day! Check out the announcement of the grand opening festivities in the Record Update (a publication of the Office of the Vice President for Communications at the University of Michigan) and don&amp;rsquo;t miss the brand new website of the Setphen S.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST Quarterly (IQ) volume 34-2 now on the web</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/05/17/iassist-quarterly-iq-volume-34-2-now-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2011 09:02:31 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/05/17/iassist-quarterly-iq-volume-34-2-now-web/</guid>
      <description>The new issue of the IASSIST Quarterly is now available on the web. This is the volume 34 (number 2, 2010).
 http://iassistdata.org/iq/issue/34/2
The layout has changed. We hope you&amp;rsquo;ll enjoy the new style presented. It seems to be a more modern format and more suited for the PDF presentation on the web. Walter Piovesan &amp;ndash; our publication officer &amp;ndash; had a biking accident. To show that nothing is so bad that it is not good for something Walter used his recovery time to redesign the IQ.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Torture, Numbers, and Digital Tape</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/02/02/torture-numbers-and-digital-tape/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2011 07:02:15 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/02/02/torture-numbers-and-digital-tape/</guid>
      <description>The IASSIST Quarterly (IQ) volume 33 number 3 is now on the web:
[http://iassistdata.org/iq/issue/33/3]
With this issue concentrating on quantitative investigations and the use of statistics, I came to think of the Mark Twain citation &amp;ldquo;There are three kinds of lies: lies, damned lies, and statistics.&amp;rdquo; With the violent title of the first article (see below), the article on numbers and statistics, and the report from a national statistics agency, the &amp;ldquo;Torture,Numbers, and Digital Tape&amp;rdquo; title surfaced.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>