<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>IASSIST 2008 on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </title>
    <link>https://talatera.github.io/tags/iassist-2008/</link>
    <description>Recent content in IASSIST 2008 on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 May 2016 07:13:42 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://talatera.github.io/tags/iassist-2008/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST 2016 Program At-A-Glance, Part 2: Data infrastructure, data processing and research data management</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2016/05/06/iassist-2016-program-glance-part-2-data-infrastructure-data-processing-and-research-data-manage/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2016 07:13:42 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2016/05/06/iassist-2016-program-glance-part-2-data-infrastructure-data-processing-and-research-data-manage/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s another list of highlights from IASSIST2016 which is focusing on the data revolution. For previous highlights, see here.
Infrastructure  For those of you with an interest in technical infrastructure, the University of Applied Sciences HTW Chur will showcase an early protype MMRepo (1 June, 3F), whose function is to store qualitative and quantitative data into one big data repository.   The UK Data Service will present the following panel &amp;ldquo;The CESSDA Technical Framework - what is it and why is it needed?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Special IQ: Moving Research Data Into and Out of Institutional Repositories</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2009/05/12/special-iq-moving-research-data-and-out-institutional-repositories/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2009 14:42:09 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2009/05/12/special-iq-moving-research-data-and-out-institutional-repositories/</guid>
      <description>The IASSIST Quarterly IQ Vol. 31 issue 3&amp;amp;4 is now available on the web:
http://iassistdata.org/publications/iq/iqvol31.html
This issue will only be available on the web. There will be no printed version mailed out to the membership.
This double issue is the work of the authors and their articles are introduced below. We are presenting an integrated double issue of high quality. We should also give a special thanks to the editors of the issue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST &#39;08 Followup, Part 2:  Restricted Data</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2008/07/03/iassist-08-followup-part-2-restricted-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2008 13:16:04 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2008/07/03/iassist-08-followup-part-2-restricted-data/</guid>
      <description>Regardless of the institutional setting in which we work, more and more of us are having to address researcher access to restricted or confidential datasets. This post focuses on sessions at Stanford that covered this important topic&amp;ndash;or rather, group of topics because there are so many intersecting responsibilities to actually making such access a reality for our users.
Lisa Neider&amp;rsquo;s poster session focused on the practicalities of &amp;ldquo;Administering Restricted Data Contracts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>And so ends &#34;The Best IASSIST ever&#34;</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2008/06/02/and-so-ends-best-iassist-ever/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2008 08:49:44 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2008/06/02/and-so-ends-best-iassist-ever/</guid>
      <description>And another conference has passed. It&amp;rsquo;s so sad to think that it will be another year before we get together again but at least we can play virtually on our lists, this blog and maybe even in SecondLife! I&amp;rsquo;m still trying to round up more conference reports but in the meantime, here&amp;rsquo;s the official conference song lyrics. Sing to the tune of The Band&amp;rsquo;s song &amp;ldquo;The Weight&amp;rdquo;
In case the tune doesn&amp;rsquo;t come to mind immediately, here&amp;rsquo;s a clip on YouTube from the movie &amp;ldquo;The Last Waltz&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ready, Set, Go! IASSIST08 is in two worlds!</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2008/05/29/ready-set-go-iassist08-two-worlds/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2008 17:43:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2008/05/29/ready-set-go-iassist08-two-worlds/</guid>
      <description>So I had the best intentions to blog the conference but alas I was distracted - creating my SecondLife avatar to be able to participate virtually as well as in reality was far more interesting than I want to admit! My teenagers were appalled when they found out I was on Facebook
 what will they say when I tell them about SusieQue!  [](http://iassistblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2008/05/iassistsl_small.wmf) As a technology-oriented association hosting a technology-themed conference, it is maybe not surprising that we should experiment a bit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST 2008 Accommodations and Registration Reminder</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2008/04/22/iassist-2008-accommodations-and-registration-reminder/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2008 14:11:34 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2008/04/22/iassist-2008-accommodations-and-registration-reminder/</guid>
      <description>Happy Earth Day to everyone!!
Hope your day is filled with loads of celebratory reducing, renewing, and recycling.
Registration for this year&amp;rsquo;s IASSIST Conference (May 27-30): &amp;ldquo;Technology of Data: Collection, Communication, Access and Preservation&amp;rdquo; is proceeding at a rumbling pace, and the five conference hotels have been filling with eager California-bound IASSISTers.
However, if you still have not made your arrangements for this year&amp;rsquo;s conference, please consider doing so. Early registration ends soon (May 2), and of more immediate concern, the conference hotels will begin dropping our room blocks (and guaranteed conference rates) beginning this Friday, April 25.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST 2008 - Call for Papers! </title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2007/10/29/iassist-2008-call-papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2007 13:21:34 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2007/10/29/iassist-2008-call-papers/</guid>
      <description>Technology of Data: Collection, Communication, Access and Preservation The 34th International Association for Social Science Information Services and Technology (IASSIST) annual conference will be held at the Stanford University, Palo Alto, California, USA, May 27-30, 2008. This year&amp;rsquo;s conference, Technology of Data: Collection, Communication, Access and Preservation, examines the role of technology and tools in various aspects of the data life cycle.
The theme of this conference addresses how technology can affect aspects of data stewardship throughout the data lifecycle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It was the best IASSIST ever!</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2007/05/22/it-was-best-iassist-ever/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2007 16:14:31 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2007/05/22/it-was-best-iassist-ever/</guid>
      <description>Until next year of course!
This year&amp;rsquo;s conference is done and Anastassia, Susan, and the wonderful Local arrangement folks at McGill are probably breathing a sigh of relief! Lots of informations was presented and some of it was absorbed! More will likely be reviewed over coming weeks preceded by the usual &amp;ldquo;Now I know I saw a presentation about this at IASSIST&amp;hellip;.&amp;rdquo;
If you were one of those fine presenters, please don&amp;rsquo;t forget to submit a paper to the IQ (instructions for doing so are on the IASSIST website).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>