<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Communities on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </title>
    <link>https://talatera.github.io/community/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Communities on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 10:00:25 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://talatera.github.io/community/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Previous interest group resources</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/community/previous-interest-groups/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 10:00:25 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/community/previous-interest-groups/</guid>
      <description>Previous Interest Groups have produced resources that may be of use for the membership or the data community at-large.
Data Visualization Interest Group (DVIG) This group focused on promoting a greater understanding of data visualization &amp;ndash; its creation, uses, and importance in research, across disciplines. Data Visualization supports a means to make sense of data, through visual representation, and to communicate ideas and information effectively. Particular areas of focus and discussions included, but were not limited to the following: :</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Human Subjects Interest Group</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/community/human-subjects-interest-group/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2010 13:33:10 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/community/human-subjects-interest-group/</guid>
      <description>Interest Group on Human Subjects Review Committees and Privacy and Confidentiality in Research This group will focus on issues related to conducting research using human subjects in the social sciences. Particular areas of focus and discussion will include, but are not limited to the following:
 The role and function of the human subjects review board as social science research enters the digital age. The human subject review influences and effects on data management, dissemination, curation and preservation practices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST Special Interest Group on Data Citation (SIGDC) Charter</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/community/data-citation-ig/iassist-special-interest-group-data-citation-charter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/community/data-citation-ig/iassist-special-interest-group-data-citation-charter/</guid>
      <description>The Special Interest Group on Data Citation (SIGDC) of the International Association of Social Science Information Services and Technology (IASSIST) was created to promote awareness of data-related research and scholarship through data citation. Citing data supports the discovery and reuse of data, leading to better science through the validation of results. It also recognizes data as an essential part of the scientific record.
The SIGDC acknowledges the variety of audiences and stakeholders for whom data citation is important, including:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Special Interest Group on Data Citation</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/community/sigdc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/community/sigdc/</guid>
      <description>The IASSIST Special Interest Group on Data Citation (SIGDC) was created to promote awareness of data-related research and scholarship through data citation. Citing data supports the discovery and reuse of data, leading to better science through the validation of results. It also recognizes data as an essential part of the scientific record.
SIGDC co-chairs: Hailey Mooney &amp;amp; Elizabeth Moss
Past chairs: 2010-2012 Mary Vardigan &amp;amp; Michael Witt
You can learn more about the interest group and its formation by reading our charter.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>