<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>world bank on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </title>
    <link>https://talatera.github.io/tags/world-bank/</link>
    <description>Recent content in world bank on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2011 13:47:50 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://talatera.github.io/tags/world-bank/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>World Bank Results At A Glance - iPhone/iPad/iPod Touch</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/20/world-bank-results-glance-iphoneipadipod-touch/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2011 13:47:50 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/20/world-bank-results-glance-iphoneipadipod-touch/</guid>
      <description>The World Bank has developed an iPhone/iPad/etc application called &amp;ldquo;World Bank Results at a Glance&amp;quot;. These results are indicators related to either UN Millenium Development Goals (where the World Bank has partnered with the UN) or outcomes from exclusively World Bank projects.
The application has 450 indicators for 85 countries. Users can
 Search and browse over 450 results profiles by country name or coordinates more than 30 topics over 300 keywords, including &amp;ldquo;roads,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;food security,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;job creation,&amp;rdquo; and more Millennium Development Goals Save and share stories View a graphic timeline of key World Bank results and milestones Read relevant background about the World Bank&amp;rsquo;s results initiatives See Frequently Asked Questions (FAQs) about the Bank itself, shedding light on the modern workings of the institution Gain access to multiple PDFs in multiple languages related to quick results facts, country statistics, and background on the Bank&amp;rsquo;s initiatives, all exportable to iBooks View project images and videos  This tool joins three other World Bank applications which cover indicators (DataFinder), nformation (InfoFinder) and doing business around the world (Doing Business at a Glance).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>World Bank Launches New Data Website Rich with Features and Newly Free Data</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2010/05/02/world-bank-launches-new-data-website-rich-features-and-newly-free-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2010 16:11:34 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2010/05/02/world-bank-launches-new-data-website-rich-features-and-newly-free-data/</guid>
      <description>The World Bank has just launched a new Data website that is densely packed with newly free data and features for using the data which are appropriate to all levels of users.
Users may browse by country, topic, indicator or listing in the data catalog. The World Bank says that access is now freely available for over 2000 indicators from 1960-present. In comparison, the most recent version of World Development Indicators, a licensed version of their data sold to academic libraries, contained just over 900 indicators.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>