<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>IASSIST 2011 on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </title>
    <link>https://talatera.github.io/tags/iassist-2011/</link>
    <description>Recent content in IASSIST 2011 on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2011 09:21:28 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://talatera.github.io/tags/iassist-2011/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Videos from the  IASSIST 2011 Plenaries </title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/06/24/videos-iassist-2011-plenaries/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2011 09:21:28 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/06/24/videos-iassist-2011-plenaries/</guid>
      <description>Hello - for those who were not able to attend IASSIST 2011 and for those asking to have access to video presentations, the two videos of the Plenaries from IASSIST 2011 are now available for viewing:
Research Data Infrastructure: Are the Social Sciences on Main Street or a Side Road?   Chuck Humphrey - Data Library Coordinator, University of Alberta   Chuck Humphrey is passionate about data and has been examining research data infrastructure with a global perspective.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST SIGDC Meeting Held in Vancouver</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/06/22/iassist-sigdc-meeting-held-vancouver/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2011 05:24:34 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/06/22/iassist-sigdc-meeting-held-vancouver/</guid>
      <description>The IASSIST Special Interest Group on Data Citation (SIGDC) met in Vancouver on Wednesday, June 1, with 15 people in attendance. The group discussed ways in which IASSIST members could influence data citation standards and behavior. Suggestions were made to:
 Inventory the resources that the SIG maintains and knows about Create a set of simple slides to share with faculty and students; these might include guidelines on citation format with examples but would not endorse a certain format Create posters on data citation to hang in prominent places Contact bibliographic software companies to make sure they include data as a specific resource type Contact style guides &amp;ndash; APA, Chicago, MLA &amp;ndash; to ensure that they are providing appropriate citations for data and including DOIs Create a set of Web pages on this topic on the IASSIST site Contact Google Scholar with a list of issues related to data  Joachim Wackerow presented information on ways to make DOIs more machine-actionable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST 2011 conference song lyrics</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/06/06/iassist-2011-conference-song-lyrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2011 07:24:47 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/06/06/iassist-2011-conference-song-lyrics/</guid>
      <description>Sung to the tune of Bryan Adam&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Summer of &amp;lsquo;69&amp;rdquo; :
We all came to Vancouver in spring 2-0-1-1 IASSISTers gather together this is gonna be fun!
Day long Admin meeting Ann skyped in for Constitutional change and we kept it all to the schedule Now that was really strange
oh, and when the Canucks won, the cheering seemed to last forever and that really set the scene for the best IASSIST ever These are the best days of IASISST</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Early registration for IASSIST 2011 ends April 1st</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/03/17/early-registration-iassist-2011-ends-april-1st/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2011 16:38:22 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/03/17/early-registration-iassist-2011-ends-april-1st/</guid>
      <description>Early registration for IASSIST 2011 ends a week from today, Thursday March 31. Fees will increase on April 1 so take advantage of the reduced rate and register in the coming week.
http://www.rdl.sfu.ca/IASSIST/index.php/Register/
By registering early you save $50 for the full conference or $30 for a single day ($40 and $20 at student rates). The cancellation deadline is April 22.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Delta Vancouver Suites Hotel</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/03/11/delta-vancouver-suites-hotel/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2011 12:02:06 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/03/11/delta-vancouver-suites-hotel/</guid>
      <description>The Delta Vancouver Suites Hotel, our official conference hotel, has added a small number of rooms for us.
Call +1-604-689-8188 or 1-888-890-3222 (Toll Free)or email vancouversuite (When booking by phone, please quote block code &amp;ldquo;EH1105IASS&amp;rdquo; ).
More information is on the conference website.
Mary and Walter
Local Arrangements</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hotels for IASSIST 2011</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/03/03/hotels-iassist-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2011 17:13:04 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/03/03/hotels-iassist-2011/</guid>
      <description>We have learned that there will be a very large conference in Vancouver at the same time as ours (5,000 people!), resulting in a real rush for hotel bookings. Regrettably rooms are no longer available at the Delta, Ramada, Days Inn and Victorian Hotels nearby (although you might check later for cancellations).
Important! We encourage you to book as soon as possible, even before you have permission from your institution (you can always cancel if it turns out you can&amp;rsquo;t attend).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST 2011 Hotel booking</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/03/01/iassist-2011-hotel-booking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 09:11:34 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/03/01/iassist-2011-hotel-booking/</guid>
      <description>We encourage everyone planning to attend **IASSIST 2011 in Vancouver **to book hotel rooms as soon as possible. There are already room shortages due to other conferences that same week and a general pickup in tourism.
The Delta Vancouver Suites reported today that there are only two rooms left at the special $199 rate; rooms are still available in the Premier category at a rate of $224.00 per night per room and in the Deluxe category rate of $239.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Registration Open: IASSIST 2011 Conference</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/02/09/registration-open-iassist-2011-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2011 13:48:14 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/02/09/registration-open-iassist-2011-conference/</guid>
      <description>We are pleased to announce that registration is now open for the IASSIST 2011 Conference!
 IASSIST 2011 conference site: www.rdl.sfu.ca/IASSIST/ Conference e-mail address: iassistvancouver@gmail.com Conference Theme: ***Data Science Professionals: a Global Community of Sharing *** Date:* 31 May - 3 June 2011 Vancouver, British Columbia, Canada. *  This will be IASSIST&amp;rsquo;s 37th annual meeting, co-hosted by the Libraries of Simon Fraser University and the University of British Columbia. Join us in Vancouver : Bordered by the Coast Mountain Range and the Pacific Ocean, Vancouver is recognized as one of the world&amp;rsquo;s most liveable cities.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>