<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>IASSIST Strategy on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </title>
    <link>https://talatera.github.io/tags/iassist-strategy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in IASSIST Strategy on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 May 2016 07:13:42 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://talatera.github.io/tags/iassist-strategy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST 2016 Program At-A-Glance, Part 2: Data infrastructure, data processing and research data management</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2016/05/06/iassist-2016-program-glance-part-2-data-infrastructure-data-processing-and-research-data-manage/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2016 07:13:42 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2016/05/06/iassist-2016-program-glance-part-2-data-infrastructure-data-processing-and-research-data-manage/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s another list of highlights from IASSIST2016 which is focusing on the data revolution. For previous highlights, see here.
Infrastructure  For those of you with an interest in technical infrastructure, the University of Applied Sciences HTW Chur will showcase an early protype MMRepo (1 June, 3F), whose function is to store qualitative and quantitative data into one big data repository.   The UK Data Service will present the following panel &amp;ldquo;The CESSDA Technical Framework - what is it and why is it needed?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing IASSIST&#39;s 2010-2014 Strategic Plan</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/03/09/implementing-iassists-2010-2014-strategic-plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2011 12:49:21 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/03/09/implementing-iassists-2010-2014-strategic-plan/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Data are larger than the social sciences&amp;rdquo; and data concerns have grown beyond the traditional communities comprising IASSIST.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash;respondent to strategic plan survey (2009)
As preparations intensify for IASSIST 2011, I encourage IASSIST members to review the 2010-2014 Strategic Plan with its focus on Advocacy, Community, and Professional Development.
As IASSIST moves into the second year of the plan, the organization finds itself in an environment where data concerns have expanded to the point that many organizations have placed data curation, data sharing, and developing data literacy at the forefront of their agenda.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST new look website</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2010/05/26/iassist-new-look-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2010 10:05:18 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2010/05/26/iassist-new-look-website/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the new (May, 2010) IASSIST website, based on Drupal open source technology and hosted by LIS-host. The new logo and website artwork was commissioned by the Publications Chair, Walter Piovesan, and done by Josh Laidlaw, from British Columbia.
Harrison Dekker, from University of California-Berkeley, is our &amp;lsquo;drupal guru&amp;rsquo; who has done the lion&amp;rsquo;s share of the work, porting over the old content and setting up the new format.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>