<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Asia/Pacific on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </title>
    <link>https://talatera.github.io/tags/asia/pacific/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Asia/Pacific on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://talatera.github.io/tags/asia/pacific/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Mongolia and IASSIST: Building Connections</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2018/03/18/mongolia-and-iassist-building-connections/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2018 21:23:13 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2018/03/18/mongolia-and-iassist-building-connections/</guid>
      <description>Spring 2017
Mongolia is large and sparsely populated country, with nomadic traditions, but rapidly modernizing. As in any modern country, there is an important role for data to play in planning and development, and Mongolian data professionals are developing themselves to meet the challenge.
Last year in May 2017, Ryan Womack (currently serving as IASSIST Secretary) was invited to give a two-day workshop on **Topics in Data Science **at the National Statistics Office of Mongolia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Workshop at the National Library of Australia, sponsored by IASSIST</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2017/12/15/data-workshop-national-library-australia-sponsored-iassist/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2017 09:08:15 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2017/12/15/data-workshop-national-library-australia-sponsored-iassist/</guid>
      <description>Posted on behalf of Jade Koekoe
In February I won sponsorship money from IASSIST for a Data Workshop I had in mind. On the 18 November this year I saw my idea come to life. This Data Workshop was aimed at Library student and newgrads and was held in the Ferguson Room of the National Library of Australia. 26 people attended and there were five speakers from industries adjacent to librarianship.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The International Workshop on Social Science Data Archives, held in Taiwan, sponsored by IASSIST</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2017/11/01/international-social-science-data-archives-workshop-taiwan/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 13:42:54 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2017/11/01/international-social-science-data-archives-workshop-taiwan/</guid>
      <description>The International Workshop on Social Science Data Archives, sponsored by IASSIST, was held on September 15 in Conference Room II, Research Center for Humanities and Social Science (RCHSS), Academia Sinica, Taipei, Taiwan. The invited speakers included Prof. Dr. Christof Wolf from GESIS &amp;ndash; Leibniz-Institute for the Social Sciences, Dr. Yukio Maeda and Dr. Kaoru Sato from Social Science Japan Data Archive (SSJDA), University of Tokyo, and Dr. Won-ho Park, Dr. Seokho Kim from Korea Social Science Data Archive (KOSSDA), Seoul National University.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chronology of data library and data centres</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2014/11/20/chronology-data-library-and-data-centres/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2014 10:01:41 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2014/11/20/chronology-data-library-and-data-centres/</guid>
      <description>A few days ago I asked on the IASSIST mailing list for some help in order to find out dates of creation of data libraries, data centres and such services. It was overwhelming to receive answers from colleagues from everywhere with dates and some other useful information about the establishment of local data support and national services.
  Newton, author of Chronology of Kingdoms   There is a wealth of information in this community around these issues and with the increasing importance of data services we need to make sure we collect and make this information accessible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST Fellows 2014</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2014/04/10/iassist-fellows-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2014 08:05:34 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2014/04/10/iassist-fellows-2014/</guid>
      <description>The IASSIST Fellows Committee is glad to announce through this post the four recipients of the 2014 IASSIST Fellowship award. We are extremely excited to have such a diverse and interesting group with different backgrounds and experience and encourage IASSISTers to welcome them at our conference in Toronto, Canada. Please find below their names, countries and brief bios:
Antonin Benoit, Head Librarian at the African Institute for Economic Development and Planning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New IASSIST Quarterly now available!</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/05/16/new-iassist-quarterly-now-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2013 05:56:15 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/05/16/new-iassist-quarterly-now-available/</guid>
      <description>Editor notes: Data bring maps, archive brings data, and accreditation brings research
This issue (volume 36-1, 2012) of the IASSIST Quarterly (IQ) is the first of the 2012 issues. This editorial is written in March 2013 when many IASSIST people have received acceptance for their papers at the upcoming conference IASSIST 2013 in Cologne. I am certain there will be many interesting presentations at the conference. However, presenters can reach a greater audience by having their paper published in forthcoming issues of the IQ.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST Fellows 2013</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/05/06/iassist-fellows-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2013 19:38:07 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/05/06/iassist-fellows-2013/</guid>
      <description>** **
The IASSIST Fellows Committee is glad to announce through this post the six recipients of the 2013 IASSIST Fellowship award. We are extremely excited to have such a diverse and interesting group with different backgrounds and experience and encourage IASSISTers to welcome them at our conference in Cologne, Germany.
Please find below their names, countries and brief bios:
**Chifundo Kanjala (Tanzania) **
Chifundo currently works as a Data Manager and data documentalist for an HIV research group called ALPHA network based at London School of Hygiene and Tropical Medicine&amp;rsquo;s department of Population Health, Chifundo spends most of his time in Mwanza, Tanzania but do travel from time around Southern and Eastern Africa to work with colleagues in the ALPHA network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST 2012 Fellows Program</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2012/01/31/iassist-2012-fellows-program/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2012 13:32:09 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2012/01/31/iassist-2012-fellows-program/</guid>
      <description>The IASSIST Fellows Program is now accepting applications for financial support to attend the IASSIST 2012 conference in Washington [http://www.iassist2012.org/], from data professionals from countries with emerging economies who are developing and managing data infrastructures at their home institutions.
Please be aware that funding is not intended to cover the entire cost of attending the conference. The applicant&amp;rsquo;s home institution must provide some level of financial support to supplement the IASSIST Fellow award.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updated Guide on Data Citation Available</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/06/22/updated-guide-data-citation-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2011 05:17:49 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/06/22/updated-guide-data-citation-available/</guid>
      <description>The Australian National Data Service has updated its Guide on Data Citation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SPARC Digital Repositories meeting includes session on open data</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2010/11/10/sparc-digital-repositories-meeting-includes-session-open-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2010 06:41:49 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2010/11/10/sparc-digital-repositories-meeting-includes-session-open-data/</guid>
      <description>Kathleen Shearer of the Canadian Association of Research Libraries organized and chaired a panel on Open Data was held at the SPARC Digital Repositories meeting on November 8, 2010. IASSIST members Gail Steinhart and Chuck Humphrey were two of the three members on this panel. Kevin Ashley, Director of the Digital Curation Centre (DCC), was the third. It has been two years since this group last met and the attendance was said to have doubled between meetings (looked like there were around 150 people present.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>