<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Citation on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </title>
    <link>https://talatera.github.io/tags/data-citation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Citation on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2012 11:29:10 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://talatera.github.io/tags/data-citation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Citation Resources</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2012/11/27/data-citation-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2012 11:29:10 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2012/11/27/data-citation-resources/</guid>
      <description>The Special Interest Group on Data Citation (SIGDC) maintains a page of Data Citation Resources with lists of relevant workshops, blogs, papers, presentations, websites, and organizations. All IASSIST members are welcome to join SIGDC and can submit ideas for resources to add to the list via our Google Group email.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Citation Brochure published by the UK&#39;s Economic and Social Research Council</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2012/06/11/data-citation-brochure-published-uks-economic-and-social-research-council/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jun 2012 04:55:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2012/06/11/data-citation-brochure-published-uks-economic-and-social-research-council/</guid>
      <description>Just to let you all know that here at the Economic and Social Data Service in the UK we have been working with the ESRC on a brochure to encourage data citation amongst our social scientists and journal publishers.
In October 2011 we minted over 5000 DOIs for our ESDS Collection with Datacite, using a methodology we developed to deal with version changes to our data. You can view our Webinar that explains how we do this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST Publishes a Quick Guide to Data Citation</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2012/06/01/iassist-publishes-quick-guide-data-citation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 06:08:48 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2012/06/01/iassist-publishes-quick-guide-data-citation/</guid>
      <description>The IASSIST Special Interest Group on Data Citation is very pleased to announce the publication of its Quick Guide to Data Citation!
These professionally-printed guides, provided by IASSIST, will be available at the IASSIST 2012 conference; come by the SIGDC poster to pick up your complimentary copies!

http://iassistdata.org/file/blog/quick_guide_to_data_citation_high-res_printer-ready.pdf
Learn more about printing or downloading more copies at IASSIST Special Interest Group on Data Citation (SIGDC)
In other SIGDC news, Elizabeth Moss and Hailey Mooney will be taking over as co-chairs from Mary Vardigan and Michael Witt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workshop: Building a Culture of Research Data Citation</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/10/20/workshop-building-culture-research-data-citation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2011 11:21:09 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/10/20/workshop-building-culture-research-data-citation/</guid>
      <description>Building a Culture of Research Data Citation
Workshop at eResearch Australasia 2011
Thursday 10 November 2011: 9:00-12:30
http://conference.eresearch.edu.au/workshops/#8
The Australian National Data Service (ANDS) is currently developing a service called &amp;ldquo;Cite My Data&amp;rdquo; [1], which uses the international DataCite infrastructure [2] to support the citation of Australian research sector datasets. The DataCite infrastructure is built on the Digital Object Identifier (DOI) system [3]&amp;ndash;widely used for citation and tracking of scholarly publications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST SIGDC Meeting Held in Vancouver</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/06/22/iassist-sigdc-meeting-held-vancouver/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2011 05:24:34 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/06/22/iassist-sigdc-meeting-held-vancouver/</guid>
      <description>The IASSIST Special Interest Group on Data Citation (SIGDC) met in Vancouver on Wednesday, June 1, with 15 people in attendance. The group discussed ways in which IASSIST members could influence data citation standards and behavior. Suggestions were made to:
 Inventory the resources that the SIG maintains and knows about Create a set of simple slides to share with faculty and students; these might include guidelines on citation format with examples but would not endorse a certain format Create posters on data citation to hang in prominent places Contact bibliographic software companies to make sure they include data as a specific resource type Contact style guides &amp;ndash; APA, Chicago, MLA &amp;ndash; to ensure that they are providing appropriate citations for data and including DOIs Create a set of Web pages on this topic on the IASSIST site Contact Google Scholar with a list of issues related to data  Joachim Wackerow presented information on ways to make DOIs more machine-actionable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Citation Principles Workshop Held</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/06/22/data-citation-principles-workshop-held/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2011 05:14:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/06/22/data-citation-principles-workshop-held/</guid>
      <description>A workshop on Data Citation Principles sponsored by Harvard&amp;rsquo;s Institute for Quantitative Social Sciences (IQSS) was held May 16-17 in Cambridge, MA. Presentations and other materials from the workshop are now available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workshop on Persistent Identifiers for Social Science Data</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/02/11/workshop-persistent-identifiers-social-science-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2011 05:54:27 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/02/11/workshop-persistent-identifiers-social-science-data/</guid>
      <description>The IDSC of IZA in Bonn, Germany, along with GESIS and the RatSWD, sponsored a workshop on Persistent Identifiers in the Social Sciences held February 1-2 in Bonn. The presentations are now online at:
http://www.iza.org/conference_files/PeIdSS2011/viewProgram?conf_id=2013</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Special Interest Group on Data Citation (SIGDC) Formed</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2010/11/22/special-interest-group-data-citation-sigdc-formed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2010 11:33:05 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2010/11/22/special-interest-group-data-citation-sigdc-formed/</guid>
      <description>We are pleased to announce the creation of a new Special Interest Group on Data Citation (SIGDC) to promote awareness of data-related research and scholarship through data citation. The group is co-chaired by Mary Vardigan and Michael Witt.
Citing data supports the discovery and reuse of data, leading to better science through the validation of results. It also recognizes data as an essential part of the scientific record. SIGDC will share information about its work through the IASSIST list, the IQ, the IASSIST blog, and sessions at the IASSIST conference as well as other venues and meetings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conference webcasts and presentations online!</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2009/06/09/conference-webcasts-and-presentations-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2009 12:40:46 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2009/06/09/conference-webcasts-and-presentations-online/</guid>
      <description>A week has passed since IASSIST 2009. I hope most of you have made it safely back home by now - and are ready to refresh the memories by watching the conference webcasts and viewing presentations. Webcasts of all three plenaries and Thursday and Friday&amp;rsquo;s concurrent sessions in the Small Auditorium are now available. We didn&amp;rsquo;t have cameras available during the Wednesday sessions, so no videos of these presentations, sorry! But most of the presentations are already online - a few are still missing either because we didn&amp;rsquo;t have them or we are waiting for an updated version.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ICPSR Summer Program course on DDI</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2009/06/09/icpsr-summer-program-course-ddi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2009 11:33:54 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2009/06/09/icpsr-summer-program-course-ddi/</guid>
      <description>As you may have heard during last week&amp;rsquo;s wonderful IASSIST meeting in Tampere, there are still spaces available in the ICPSR Summer Program course on DDI, to be held at Cornell University in Ithaca, New York, on July 13-16. The course is titled &amp;ldquo;Documenting Data Using DDI 3.0: Supporting Research, Collection Management, and Access,&amp;rdquo; and instructors are Wendy Thomas (Minnesota Population Center, University of Minnesota) and Arofan Gregory (Open Data Foundation).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New IQ!</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2009/03/26/new-iq/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2009 08:35:15 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2009/03/26/new-iq/</guid>
      <description>The IASSIST Quarterly (IQ Vol. 31 issue 2 - 2007) is now available on the web:
http://iassistdata.org/publications/iq/iqvol31.html
This issue will be printed and mailed to the membership. From next issue IASSIST will be saving trees and only publish the IQ on the web. We hope you agree with our decision. Thanks.
Some of you are now getting ready for the IASSIST conference in Tampere, Finland 26.-29. of May. Remember if you are giving presentations that you could write the presentation as an article for the IQ.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Data Management and Sharing Guidance</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2009/02/04/new-data-management-and-sharing-guidance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2009 14:12:49 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2009/02/04/new-data-management-and-sharing-guidance/</guid>
      <description>The UK Data Archive would like to announce the release of its new suite of web pages providing guidance on data management and sharing. The pages provide data creators, data managers and data curators with best practice strategies and methods for creating, preparing and storing shareable datasets. Advice has been divided into a number of key areas or modules providing detailed information on each topic. These are:
· Sharing data - why and how?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Official Release of the Data Documentation Initiative 3.0 </title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2008/05/26/official-release-data-documentation-initiative-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2008 18:43:32 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2008/05/26/official-release-data-documentation-initiative-30/</guid>
      <description>May 21, 2008 &amp;ndash; The Alliance for the Data Documentation Initiative (DDI) is pleased to announce the official release of Version 3.0 of the DDI XML specification for documenting social science data. This long awaited version of the DDI represents a major advance by fully incorporating XML Schemas and moving to a data life cycle approach. We thank all the members of the DDI working groups as well as DDI users who have volunteered their time and efforts over the past years to make this specification a reality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upcoming ODaF meetings in Europe and US</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2008/02/22/upcoming-odaf-meetings-europe-and-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2008 14:30:15 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2008/02/22/upcoming-odaf-meetings-europe-and-us/</guid>
      <description>The Open Data Foundation is pleased to announce that an ODaF Europe 2008 meeting will take place at the UK Data Archive on April 14-15. This regional event is open to all members as well as individuals and agencies interested to learn more about ODaF or to share ideas. For further information and registration, see http://www.opendatafoundation.org/events/odaf_europe_2008.php
Looking into the future, we currently anticipate holding a US regional meeting on Oct 2-3 at the Sun Microsystems headquarters in Manhattan, NY and our Annual Meeting in Washington DC in December.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DDI, institutional repositories, and numeric data mashups</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2008/02/01/ddi-institutional-repositories-and-numeric-data-mashups/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2008 14:23:47 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2008/02/01/ddi-institutional-repositories-and-numeric-data-mashups/</guid>
      <description>Announcing new deliverables from the DISC-UK DataShare project:
 DISC-UK DataShare: Web 2.0 Data Visualisation Tools, by Stuart Macdonald.   The Data Documentation Initiative (DDI) and Institutional Repositories, by Luis Martinez.  Both briefing papers can be retrieved from http://www.disc-uk.org/deliverables.html .
There is also a new &amp;ldquo;Collective Intelligence&amp;rdquo; page with a tag cloud to links from our social bookmarks of reports, websites, and blogs related to the project themes. http://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST 2008 - Call for Papers! </title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2007/10/29/iassist-2008-call-papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2007 13:21:34 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2007/10/29/iassist-2008-call-papers/</guid>
      <description>Technology of Data: Collection, Communication, Access and Preservation The 34th International Association for Social Science Information Services and Technology (IASSIST) annual conference will be held at the Stanford University, Palo Alto, California, USA, May 27-30, 2008. This year&amp;rsquo;s conference, Technology of Data: Collection, Communication, Access and Preservation, examines the role of technology and tools in various aspects of the data life cycle.
The theme of this conference addresses how technology can affect aspects of data stewardship throughout the data lifecycle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New IQ issue - intro from the editor</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2007/06/15/new-iq-issue-intro-editor/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2007 05:51:45 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2007/06/15/new-iq-issue-intro-editor/</guid>
      <description>The IASSIST Quarterly (IQ Vol. 30 issue 2 - 2006) is now available on the web:
http://iassistdata.org/publications/iq/iqvol30.html
Winter came late in Denmark, but suddenly the situation was normal: snow came and traffic stopped. And now 14 days after spring was here in March. I sat outside in the sun reading articles. Still it&amp;rsquo;s more difficult to write articles outside, we are waiting for the improvements of the computer screens. However, some people have stayed inside to write articles for the IASSIST Quarterly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cataloging query:  how does cataloging data differ from traditional library material?</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2006/06/19/cataloging-query-how-does-cataloging-data-differ-traditional-library-material/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2006 14:55:30 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2006/06/19/cataloging-query-how-does-cataloging-data-differ-traditional-library-material/</guid>
      <description>In their never ending quest for information, Jen, Tiffani and Paula would like to know about people&amp;rsquo;s experiences cataloging data. Do you use MARC format? Have you tried using DDI? At what level do you tend to catalog collections? How does it depart from cataloging traditional library matter? Enquiring minds want to know.
  Contributed by Jen Darragh  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>