<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Best practices on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </title>
    <link>https://talatera.github.io/tags/best-practices/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Best practices on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2015 14:18:03 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://talatera.github.io/tags/best-practices/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>DMP Assistant: bilingual tool for preparing data management plans (DMPs)</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2015/10/26/dmp-assistant-bilingual-tool-preparing-data-management-plans-dmps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2015 14:18:03 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2015/10/26/dmp-assistant-bilingual-tool-preparing-data-management-plans-dmps/</guid>
      <description>DMP Assistant is a bilingual tool for preparing data management plans (DMPs). The tool follows best practices in data stewardship and walks researchers step-by-step through key questions about data management.
DMP Assistant was adapted from the (UK) Digital Curation Centre&amp;rsquo;s DMPOnline tool and is hosted at the University of Alberta. The French user interface was produced with support from the Université de Montréal Library. It is freely available to all researchers in Canada and provides specialized guidance to help researchers utilize the tool to develop their plan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataQ: A collaborative platform for answering research data questions in academic libraries</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2015/10/26/dataq-collaborative-platform-answering-research-data-questions-academic-libraries/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2015 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2015/10/26/dataq-collaborative-platform-answering-research-data-questions-academic-libraries/</guid>
      <description>DataQ is a collaborative platform for the community to use to ask and answer questions related to research data support in academic libraries. Library staff from any institution may submit questions on research data topics to the DataQ website, where questions are reviewed by an Editorial Team of experts with additional support from an active pool of Project Volunteers. Answers to these questions, from both the community and the Editorial Team, are posted to the DataQ website and include links to resources and tools, best practices, and practical approaches to working with researchers to address specific research data issues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>University of British Columbia Library: Research Data Management (RDM) Website</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2014/12/19/university-british-columbia-library-research-data-management-rdm-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2014 07:33:28 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2014/12/19/university-british-columbia-library-research-data-management-rdm-website/</guid>
      <description>University of British Columbia Library release their Research Data Management (RDM) website at http://researchdata.library.ubc.ca/.
The website is designed to be service-oriented. Four sections, Learn; Plan; Share and Find guide users to the RDM advice and systems solutions that meet their current needs. The Learn section includes a DataGuide (CC BY 3.0) - a quick standalone guide developed to get people started on Research Data Management, which could be re-used and adapted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Data Management Training online course</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/10/26/research-data-management-training-online-course/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2011 03:58:29 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/10/26/research-data-management-training-online-course/</guid>
      <description>The Research Data Management Training, or MANTRA project has produced an open, online training course for PhD and early career researchers to learn best practices in data management.
In addition to the interactive, online module which covers data management topics such as Organising Your Data, there are downloadable software modules covering data handling skills in SPSS, R, NVivo and ArcGIS.
The resource was created by EDINA and Data Library, University of Edinburgh, and was funded by the JISC Managing Research Data programme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Irish Qualitative Data Archive: Best Practice in Archiving Qualitative Data</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/05/11/irish-qualitative-data-archive-best-practice-archiving-qualitative-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2011 14:32:43 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/05/11/irish-qualitative-data-archive-best-practice-archiving-qualitative-data/</guid>
      <description>The Irish Qualitative Data Archive: Best Practice in Archiving Qualitative Data (PDF) handbook is intended to introduce the researcher and data curator to the issues they need to consider when developing an archiving strategy appropriate to their qualitative data set. The guidelines apply principally to textual data that have been generated in qualitative research projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>University of California, San Diego (UCSD) Research Cyberinfrastructure: Data Management Planning</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/05/04/university-california-san-diego-ucsd-research-cyberinfrastructure-data-management-planning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2011 08:06:30 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/05/04/university-california-san-diego-ucsd-research-cyberinfrastructure-data-management-planning/</guid>
      <description>UCSD Research Cyberinfrastructure: Data Management Planning contains resources, examples, and links to guides on writing a data management plan. Strong National Science Foundation (NSF) focus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UK Data Archive: Managing and Sharing Data: Best Practice for Researchers</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/30/uk-data-archive-managing-and-sharing-data-best-practice-researchers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2011 01:03:47 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/30/uk-data-archive-managing-and-sharing-data-best-practice-researchers/</guid>
      <description>The UK Data Archive&amp;rsquo;s guide Managing and Sharing Data: Best Practice for Researchers (PDF) provides guidance to support researchers in producing high quality research data that can be shared and re-used beyond the primary research. The guidance covers:
 Why and how to share research data Data management planning and costing Documenting data Formatting data Storing data and data security Ethics and consent for data sharing and re-use Data copyright Data management strategies for large investments  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UK Data Archive: Create and Manage Data</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/30/uk-data-archive-create-and-manage-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2011 00:50:17 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/30/uk-data-archive-create-and-manage-data/</guid>
      <description>UK Data Archive: Create and Manage Data provides best practice guidance for researchers on creating and managing data. Guidance covers data management and sharing planning, consent and ethics in data sharing, data ownership and copyright, documenting data, formatting data, storing data, data security and data management strategies for large-scale research investments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT) Libraries: Data Management and Publishing</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/30/massachusetts-institute-technology-mit-libraries-data-management-and-publishing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2011 00:29:40 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/30/massachusetts-institute-technology-mit-libraries-data-management-and-publishing/</guid>
      <description>The MIT Libraries Data Management and Publishing guide is aimed to provide academic researchers with practical tips for research data management. Includes guidance on a range of topics, covering both managing data during a project and sharing/archiving data upon completion. Includes page on developing data management plans.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distributed Data Curation Center (D2C2)</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/25/distributed-data-curation-center-d2c2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2011 13:55:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/25/distributed-data-curation-center-d2c2/</guid>
      <description>The Distributed Data Curation Center (D2C2) maintains projects and research for facilitating data curation. Includes an extensive list of data repositories that is searchable and browsable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oak Ridge National Laboratory Distributed Active Archive Center (DAAC): Data Provider Information</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/25/oak-ridge-national-laboratory-distributed-active-archive-center-daac-data-provider-informa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2011 12:13:16 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/25/oak-ridge-national-laboratory-distributed-active-archive-center-daac-data-provider-informa/</guid>
      <description>Oak Ridge National Laboratory DAAC: Data Provider Information outlines practices that data collectors and providers should follow to improve the usability of environmental data sets. Contains manual on Best Practices for Preparing Environmental Data Sets to Share and Archive (PDF).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Curation Centre (DCC)</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/25/digital-curation-centre-dcc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2011 12:01:53 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/25/digital-curation-centre-dcc/</guid>
      <description>The Digital Curation Centre is a hub of expertise in curating digital research data. It sponsors events, projects, and fora for communication, and maintains an extensive set of online resources, including its Curation Reference Manual. Includes page on data management plans which outlines UK research funder data planning and sharing policies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ICPSR: Guide to Social Science Data Preparation and Archiving</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/25/icpsr-guide-social-science-data-preparation-and-archiving/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2011 11:56:27 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/25/icpsr-guide-social-science-data-preparation-and-archiving/</guid>
      <description>The ICPSR Guide to Social Science Data Preparation and Archiving (PDF) guides researchers through best practices in preparing their research data for sharing. Chapters cover activities to be undertaken at various stages throughout the research lifecycle.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>