<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Policies on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </title>
    <link>https://talatera.github.io/tags/policies/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Policies on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2015 13:17:16 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://talatera.github.io/tags/policies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>LIBER: Research Data Management Case Studies</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2015/10/26/liber-research-data-management-case-studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2015 13:17:16 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2015/10/26/liber-research-data-management-case-studies/</guid>
      <description>In June 2014, the Scholarly Communication and Research Infrastructures Steering Committee of Association of European Rsearch Libraries (LIBER) published 11 case studies on Research Data Management. The case studies are hosted by or with strong involvement of libraries in research data management. These studies describe policies and strategies that pave the way for the creation, institutional integration and the running of support services and underlying infrastructures. In addition, challenges and lessons learned are described, and ways-forward outlined.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNC Data Stewardship Report</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2012/04/04/unc-data-stewardship-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2012 10:08:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2012/04/04/unc-data-stewardship-report/</guid>
      <description>In the spring of 2011, the UNC-Chapel Provost formed the Task Force on the Stewardship of Digital Research Data and charged its members with exploring the implications of data management for the University and making recommendations for University policy. The Task Force investigated the data management landscape through research in the literature, conversations with faculty and staff, and an in-depth faculty survey designed and administered by the Odum Institute. The resulting report was submitted to administrators in mid-February 2012 with recommendations for university policies and procedures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geospatial Data Preservation Resource Center</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/11/23/geospatial-data-preservation-resource-center-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2011 10:19:32 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/11/23/geospatial-data-preservation-resource-center-0/</guid>
      <description>The Geospatial Data Preservation Resource Center gathers freely available web-based resources about the preservation of geospatial information. A variety of selected resources are being added, including reports, presentations, standards, and information about tools for preparing geospatial assets for long-term access and use. The resources are indexed to enable searching of titles and are categorized to facilitate discovery by choosing among topics, resource types, or both.
The Geospatial Data Preservation Resource Center is a project of the National Digital Information Infrastructure and Preservation Program (NDIIPP), which is working with a national network of partners on a strategy for preserving digital information for use in the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geospatial Data Preservation Resource Center</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/06/21/geospatial-data-preservation-resource-center/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2011 07:53:59 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/06/21/geospatial-data-preservation-resource-center/</guid>
      <description>A new Web site, the Geospatial Data Preservation Resource Center, aims to help those responsible for producing and managing geospatial data learn about the latest approaches and tools available to facilitate long-term geospatial data preservation and access. The Web site provides descriptions and links for a variety of relevant resources, including education and training modules, useful tools and software, information on policies and standards for preserving geospatial data, and examples of successful preservation and associated benefits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Association of Research Libraries (ARL): The National Science Foundation (NSF) Data Sharing Policy: Resources for Data Management Planning</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/05/04/association-research-libraries-arl-national-science-foundation-nsf-data-sharing-policy-res/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2011 07:52:03 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/05/04/association-research-libraries-arl-national-science-foundation-nsf-data-sharing-policy-res/</guid>
      <description>The ARL NSF Resources for Data Management Planning pulls together resources for research libraries to support their researchers in complying with the NSF Data Sharing Policy. This portal represents a variety of sites containing examples, data management tools, and data repositories. Professionals can participate in ARL&amp;rsquo;s Group on Data Sharing Support.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>California Digital Library (CDL): Manage Your Data</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/30/california-digital-library-cdl-manage-your-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2011 00:32:58 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/30/california-digital-library-cdl-manage-your-data/</guid>
      <description>CDL: Manage Your Data provides guidance on data management plans, an overview of data requirements of USA funding agencies and general guidance on creating, organizing, managing, and sharing data by the California Digital Library. Data management planning information refers both to specific National Science Foundation (NSF) plan requirements and to more generic guidance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rural Economy and Land Use Programme (Relu): Data Management Planning</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/30/rural-economy-and-land-use-programme-relu-data-management-planning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2011 00:22:45 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/30/rural-economy-and-land-use-programme-relu-data-management-planning/</guid>
      <description>Relu&amp;rsquo;s Data Management Planning site has data management planning guidance, template and real-case examples of data management plans from the UK-based cross-disciplinary Rural Economy and Land Use Programme (social, environmental and biological sciences). Relu has its own data management and sharing policy and all funded projects are required to prepare a data management plan when they begin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Government of Canada: Canadian Institutes for Health Research (CIHR) Policy on Access to Research Outputs</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/27/government-canada-canadian-institutes-health-research-cihr-policy-access-research-outputs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2011 12:16:23 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/27/government-canada-canadian-institutes-health-research-cihr-policy-access-research-outputs/</guid>
      <description>TheCIHR Policy on Access to Research Outputs demonstrates the CIHR&amp;rsquo;s belief that greater access to research publications and data will promote the ability of researchers in Canada and abroad to use and build on the knowledge needed to address significant health challenges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Government of Canada: Social Sciences and Humanities Research Council (SSHRC) Research Data Archiving Policy</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/27/government-canada-social-sciences-and-humanities-research-council-sshrc-research-data-arch/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2011 12:14:33 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/27/government-canada-social-sciences-and-humanities-research-council-sshrc-research-data-arch/</guid>
      <description>The SSHRC funding council &amp;ldquo;is committed to the principle that the various forms of research data collected with public funds belong in the public domain. Accordingly, SSHRC has adopted SSHRC Research Data Archiving Policy to facilitate making data that has been collected with the help of SSHRC funds available to other researchers.&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Government of Canada: Access to Research Results: Guiding Principles</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/27/government-canada-access-research-results-guiding-principles/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2011 12:12:47 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/27/government-canada-access-research-results-guiding-principles/</guid>
      <description>The Government of Canada&amp;rsquo;s principal funders of research and scholarship in higher education collaborated to produce Government of Canada: Access to Research Results: Guiding Principles to ensure data produced by public funding remains as widely available as possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataCite: DataCite Metadata Schema for the Publication and Citation of Research Data </title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/27/datacite-datacite-metadata-schema-publication-and-citation-research-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2011 08:08:14 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/27/datacite-datacite-metadata-schema-publication-and-citation-research-data/</guid>
      <description>The DataCite Metadata Schema for the Publication and Citation of Research Data is a list of core metadata properties chosen for the accurate and consistent identification of data for citation and retrieval purposes, along with recommended use instructions. This schema was developed by DataCite International Data Citation Metadata Working Group, released March 2011.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OECD Principles and Guidelines for Access to Research Data from Public Funding</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/25/oecd-principles-and-guidelines-access-research-data-public-funding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2011 13:59:31 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/25/oecd-principles-and-guidelines-access-research-data-public-funding/</guid>
      <description>The OECD Principles and Guidelines for Access to Research Data from Public Funding (PDF) represents guidelines based on commonly agreed principles to facilitate cost-effective access to digital research data from public funding. It is intended to improve the international sharing of, and access to, research data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>University of Minnesota Libraries: Managing Your Data</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/25/university-minnesota-libraries-managing-your-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2011 13:52:27 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/25/university-minnesota-libraries-managing-your-data/</guid>
      <description>The University of Minnesota Libraries: Managing Your Data site examines the research data lifecycle and offers tools and solutions for creation, storage, analysis, dissemination, and preservation of data. Includes an extensive list of funding agency guidelines and links to example data management plans.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Curation Centre (DCC)</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/25/digital-curation-centre-dcc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2011 12:01:53 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/25/digital-curation-centre-dcc/</guid>
      <description>The Digital Curation Centre is a hub of expertise in curating digital research data. It sponsors events, projects, and fora for communication, and maintains an extensive set of online resources, including its Curation Reference Manual. Includes page on data management plans which outlines UK research funder data planning and sharing policies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ICPSR: Guidelines for Effective Data Management Plans</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/25/icpsr-guidelines-effective-data-management-plans/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2011 11:44:16 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/25/icpsr-guidelines-effective-data-management-plans/</guid>
      <description>The ICPSR Guidelines for Effective Data Management Plans provide a framework for creating a plan (including recommended elements), a list of sample data management plans in a range of disciplines, a list of U.S. federal agency policies, and links to resources.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>