<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>IASSIST 2012 on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </title>
    <link>https://talatera.github.io/tags/iassist-2012/</link>
    <description>Recent content in IASSIST 2012 on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 10:22:46 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://talatera.github.io/tags/iassist-2012/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Become rich and famous: publish in the IQ!</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/04/02/become-rich-and-famous-publish-iq/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 10:22:46 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/04/02/become-rich-and-famous-publish-iq/</guid>
      <description>These days many IASSIST members have received acceptance for their papers to the upcoming conference IASSIST 2013 in Cologne. There will be many interesting presentations at the conference. The conference presentation is your chance to present a project you are involved in, to air your argumentation for special areas, and in general to add to the IASSIST knowledge bank.
Projects are typically focused on support of social science research but the IASSIST related support now takes many forms with the developments of technology and applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some reflections on research data confidentiality, privacy, and curation by Limor Peer</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/03/07/some-reflections-research-data-confidentiality-privacy-and-curation-limor-peer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2013 11:43:38 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/03/07/some-reflections-research-data-confidentiality-privacy-and-curation-limor-peer/</guid>
      <description>Some reflections on research data confidentiality, privacy, and curation
Limor Peer
Maintaining research subjects&amp;rsquo; confidentiality is an essential feature of the scientific research enterprise. It also presents special challenges to the data curation process. Does the effort to open access to research data complicate these challenges?
A few reasons why I think it does: More data are discoverable and could be used to re-identify previously de-identified datasets; systems are increasingly interoperable, potentially bridging what may have been insular academic data with other data and information sources; growing pressure to open data may weaken some of the safeguards previously put in place; and some data are inherently identifiable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2012 Report from the Interest Group on Human Subjects Review Committees and Privacy and Confidentiality in Research</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2012/06/19/2012-report-interest-group-human-subjects-review-committees-and-privacy-and-confidentiality-res/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2012 16:02:15 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2012/06/19/2012-report-interest-group-human-subjects-review-committees-and-privacy-and-confidentiality-res/</guid>
      <description>For those of you exploring issues of human subjects, privacy and confidentiality, this group may be of interest. In the coming year we hope to put together some resources and guides for those working with confidential data or human subjects related work. Please contact libbie@ucla.edu if you are &amp;ldquo;interested&amp;rdquo;! ** ** Interest Group on Human Subjects Review Committees and Privacy and Confidentiality in Research This group will focus on issues related to conducting research using human subjects in the social sciences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iassist 2012 conference song</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2012/06/09/iassist-2012-conference-song/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2012 17:31:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2012/06/09/iassist-2012-conference-song/</guid>
      <description>My thanks to Vince Gray, Lisa Neidert, and Melanie Wright for help with the lyrics, Melanie for the great guitar accompaniment, and Melanie, Vince, and Kate McNeill for singing along (and thereby drowning out the sound of what passes for my singing voice :)
(Sung, sort of, to the tune of &amp;ldquo;America the beautiful&amp;rdquo;)
It&amp;rsquo;s 2012 in Washington, We met for IASSIST; Unfortunately we&amp;rsquo;re all done, But memories persist - IASSIST oh IASSIST, We look forward to you; The meetings and the people Give us so much to do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST 2012 - Registration Now Open</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2012/03/29/iassist-2012-registration-now-open/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Mar 2012 12:11:47 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2012/03/29/iassist-2012-registration-now-open/</guid>
      <description>We are pleased to announce that registration is now open for the IASSIST 2012 Conference!
IASSIST 2012 conference site: http://www.iassist2012.org/index.html
Conference Theme: Data Science for a Connected World: Unlocking and Harnessing the Power of Information
Dates: June 4th &amp;ndash; 8th, Washington D.C. USA.
Register before May 1st to take advantage of special conference and workshops rates. Fees and other details are available at: http://www.iassist2012.org/indexfolder/Register/index.php
The theme &amp;ldquo;Data Science for a Connected World: Unlocking and Harnessing the Power of Information&amp;rdquo; reflects the growing desire of research communities, government agencies and other organizations to build connections and benefit from the better use of data through practicing good management, dissemination and preservation techniques.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST Fellows application now closed</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2012/03/03/iassist-fellows-application-now-closed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2012 01:15:15 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2012/03/03/iassist-fellows-application-now-closed/</guid>
      <description>The application for IASSIST Fellows is now closed. Over 40 applications from 23 different countries have been received with the following number of applications by region:
 23 Latin America 12 Africa 6 Asia  The Fellows Committee is now working to evaluate the applications and will make the decisions in the following weeks. Good luck to all participants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST 2012 Fellows Program</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2012/01/31/iassist-2012-fellows-program/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2012 13:32:09 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2012/01/31/iassist-2012-fellows-program/</guid>
      <description>The IASSIST Fellows Program is now accepting applications for financial support to attend the IASSIST 2012 conference in Washington [http://www.iassist2012.org/], from data professionals from countries with emerging economies who are developing and managing data infrastructures at their home institutions.
Please be aware that funding is not intended to cover the entire cost of attending the conference. The applicant&amp;rsquo;s home institution must provide some level of financial support to supplement the IASSIST Fellow award.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call for Workshops</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2012/01/04/call-workshops/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2012 10:03:19 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2012/01/04/call-workshops/</guid>
      <description>Don&amp;rsquo;t forget to propose that extra special workshop for IASSIST 2012. Deadline is Jan 16. You can also propose Pecha Kuchas, posters, and roundtable discussions until Jan 16.
Call for Workshops Data Science for a Connected World: Unlocking and Harnessing the Power of Information
The 38th International Association for Social Science Information Services and Technology (IASSIST) annual conference will be hosted by NORC at the University of Chicago and will be held at the George Washington University in Washington DC, June 4 - 8, 2012.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST 2012 - Call for Workshops</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/12/13/iassist-2012-call-workshops/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2011 19:51:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/12/13/iassist-2012-call-workshops/</guid>
      <description>The Call for Papers for IASSIST 2012 is closed, but proposals for Workshops are now being accepted. The Call for Workshops is listed below:
 Call for Workshops Data Science for a Connected World: Unlocking and Harnessing the Power of Information
The 38th International Association for Social Science Information Services and Technology (IASSIST) annual conference will be hosted by NORC at the University of Chicago and will be held at the George Washington University in Washington DC, June 4 - 8, 2012.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reminder - Submit your paper and panel proposals to IASSIST 2012</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/12/06/reminder-submit-your-paper-and-panel-proposals-iassist-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2011 13:03:53 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/12/06/reminder-submit-your-paper-and-panel-proposals-iassist-2012/</guid>
      <description>Just a reminder that the deadline to submit an individual paper or a panel session to IASSIST 2012 is Friday December 9th. The Submission Form can be found at: http://www.iassist2012.org/index.php/CPMS/submissions2012.html Call for Papers Data Science for a Connected World: Unlocking and Harnessing the Power of Information
The theme of this year&amp;rsquo;s conference is Data Science for a Connected World: Unlocking and Harnessing the Power of Information. This theme reflects the growing desire of research communities, government agencies and other organizations to build connections and benefit from the better use of data through practicing good management, dissemination and preservation techniques.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST 2012 - Conference website</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/11/15/iassist-2012-conference-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2011 19:20:14 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/11/15/iassist-2012-conference-website/</guid>
      <description>The IASSIST 2012 conference website is now live and ready to receive submissions: http://www.iassist2012.org/index.html
Call for Papers Data Science for a Connected World: Unlocking and Harnessing the Power of Information
The theme of this year&amp;rsquo;s conference is Data Science for a Connected World: Unlocking and Harnessing the Power of Information. This theme reflects the growing desire of research communities, government agencies and other organizations to build connections and benefit from the better use of data through practicing good management, dissemination and preservation techniques.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST Latin Engagement Action Group </title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/11/03/iassist-latin-engagement-action-group/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2011 06:56:25 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/11/03/iassist-latin-engagement-action-group/</guid>
      <description>The Latin Engagement Action Group have come up with a number of outreach activities aimed at supporting data professionals from Spanish and Portuguese speaking educational institutions, namely:
1. Research Data Management Webinars (complete with IASSIST contribution) for Spanish/Portuguese data specialists (http://www.recolecta.net/buscador/webminars.jsp)
Stuart Macdonald and Luis Martínez-Uribe in collaboration with Alicia López Medina (UNED, Spain), the Spanish Agency of Science and Technology (FECYT) and the network of Spanish repositories RECOLECTA have organised a programme of webinars in 3 strands starting in October to discuss RDM issues:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST 2012 - Call for Papers</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/10/13/iassist-2012-call-papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2011 11:52:41 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/10/13/iassist-2012-call-papers/</guid>
      <description>The Call for Papers for IASSIST 2012 is below. The conference website is still under development, but we thought it important to disseminate the call for papers to IASSIST membership now. The Call will be reposted and further disseminated once the conference website is up and running. Thanks.
 2012 Conference Program Chairs
-Pascal, Oliver and Jake  ===========================
**Data Science for a Connected World: Unlocking and Harnessing the Power of Information ** The 38th International Association for Social Science Information Services</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>