<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Education on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </title>
    <link>https://talatera.github.io/tags/education/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Education on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2015 11:31:36 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://talatera.github.io/tags/education/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Data Information Literacy (DIL) Case Studies Directory</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2015/11/06/data-information-literacy-dil-case-studies-directory/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2015 11:31:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2015/11/06/data-information-literacy-dil-case-studies-directory/</guid>
      <description>The Data Information Literacy (DIL) Case Studies Directory is a repository of teaching cases and material on research data management. DIL case studies are available for re-use under a CC-BY license and information on how to cite a case study is provided. Recent Case Studies include:
Engineering / Faculty / Sapp Nelson / Purdue University / 2015 [Megan R. Sapp Nelson]{.auth}
Electrical and Computer Engineering/ Undergraduates/ Carlson &amp;amp; SappNelson/ Purdue University/ 2012 photobanda.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>University of British Columbia Library: Research Data Management (RDM) Website</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2014/12/19/university-british-columbia-library-research-data-management-rdm-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2014 07:33:28 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2014/12/19/university-british-columbia-library-research-data-management-rdm-website/</guid>
      <description>University of British Columbia Library release their Research Data Management (RDM) website at http://researchdata.library.ubc.ca/.
The website is designed to be service-oriented. Four sections, Learn; Plan; Share and Find guide users to the RDM advice and systems solutions that meet their current needs. The Learn section includes a DataGuide (CC BY 3.0) - a quick standalone guide developed to get people started on Research Data Management, which could be re-used and adapted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New England Collaborative Data Management Curriculum</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2014/05/13/new-england-collaborative-data-management-curriculum/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2014 08:08:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2014/05/13/new-england-collaborative-data-management-curriculum/</guid>
      <description>The New England Collaborative Data Management Curriculum (NECDMC) is an instructional tool for teaching data management best practices to undergraduates, graduate students, and researchers in the health sciences, sciences, and engineering disciplines. Each of the curriculum&amp;rsquo;s seven online instructional modules aligns with the National Science Foundation&amp;rsquo;s data management plan recommendations and addresses universal data management challenges. Included in the curriculum is a collection of actual research cases that provides a discipline specific context to the content of the instructional modules.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Information Literacy (DIL) Project Website</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2014/05/13/data-information-literacy-dil-project-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2014 08:01:44 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2014/05/13/data-information-literacy-dil-project-website/</guid>
      <description>The Purdue University Libraries, partnered with the libraries of the University of Minnesota, the University of Oregon and Cornell University, led this project to help raise awareness of research data management and curation issues among rresearchers, through developing and implementing data information literacy (DIL) instruction programs for graduate students. The website of the project has gathered updated information and development of the researcher interview instruments, the data management training curriculum, as well as research publications result from the project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Essentials 4 Data Support</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2012/03/01/essentials-4-data-support/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 10:59:25 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2012/03/01/essentials-4-data-support/</guid>
      <description>An introductory course for those people who (want to) support researchers in storing, managing, archiving and sharing their research data. You can combine the online course with face to face meetings, guided by trainers, or take the online-only course for free. Developed by 3TU.Datacentrum, a consortium of 3 institutions in Delft, the Netherlands, and organised by 3TU.Datacentrum, DANS and SURFsara.
Topics include data management (skills), technical skills, and acquisitions and advice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UK Data Archive&#39;s Managing and Sharing Data Training Resources</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/11/01/uk-data-archives-managing-and-sharing-data-training-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 12:08:48 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/11/01/uk-data-archives-managing-and-sharing-data-training-resources/</guid>
      <description>Our Managing and Sharing Data: Training Resources present a suite of flexible training materials for people who are charged with training researchers and research support staff in how to look after research data.
The Training Resources are modularised following the UK Data Archive&amp;rsquo;s seven key areas of managing and sharing data:
 sharing data - why and how data management planning for researchers and research centres documenting data formatting data storing data, including data security, data transfer, encryption, and file sharing ethics and consent data copyright  Each section contains:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Data Management Training online course</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/10/26/research-data-management-training-online-course/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2011 03:58:29 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/10/26/research-data-management-training-online-course/</guid>
      <description>The Research Data Management Training, or MANTRA project has produced an open, online training course for PhD and early career researchers to learn best practices in data management.
In addition to the interactive, online module which covers data management topics such as Organising Your Data, there are downloadable software modules covering data handling skills in SPSS, R, NVivo and ArcGIS.
The resource was created by EDINA and Data Library, University of Edinburgh, and was funded by the JISC Managing Research Data programme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Penn State University Libraries: Research Data Management Toolkit</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/05/06/penn-state-university-libraries-research-data-management-toolkit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2011 10:22:18 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/05/06/penn-state-university-libraries-research-data-management-toolkit/</guid>
      <description>The Penn State University Libraries Data Management Toolkit provides resources to help orient teaching and research faculty, as well as undergraduate and graduate students, around the topic of data management planning. While some sections are dedicated specifically to PSU students, faculty and staff, a large majority of the toolkit may be used generally by the public and offers great information on data management, planning, and sharing. The site also provides links to other institutions and organizations that offer resources on similar topics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UK Data Service (ESDS): Manage data</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/27/uk-data-service-esds-manage-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2011 12:10:41 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/27/uk-data-service-esds-manage-data/</guid>
      <description>The UK Data Service&amp;rsquo;s Manage data site contains data management guidance for researchers, data creators, data managers and data curators, on best strategies and methods for creating, preparing, and storing shareable datasets. Some guidance is specifically targeted at researchers funded by the UK Economic and Social Research Council (ESRC).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill (UNC-Chapel Hill) School of Information &amp; Library Science (SILS): Digital Curation Curriculum (DigCCurr)</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/27/university-north-carolina-chapel-hill-unc-chapel-hill-school-information-library-science-s/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2011 08:12:44 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/27/university-north-carolina-chapel-hill-unc-chapel-hill-school-information-library-science-s/</guid>
      <description>UNC-Chapel Hill&amp;rsquo;s Digital Curation Curriculum (DigCCurr) offers intensive training and symposia on digital curation for researchers and other professionals. The current funded project, DigCCurr II, will host three Professional Institutes aimed at assisting digital collection managers in developing their digital curation strategies. The site also offers fellowships in digital curation as well as a shared space for workshop participants to collaborate and share tools and strategies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ICPSR: Digital Preservation Management</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/27/icpsr-digital-preservation-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2011 08:03:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/27/icpsr-digital-preservation-management/</guid>
      <description>The ICPSR Digital Preservation Management site provides a listing of ICPSR-based workshops and tutorials on Digital Preservation Management*. Digital Preservation Management: Implementing Short-Term Strategies for Long-Term Solutions*, is an online tutorial developed for the Digital Preservation Management workshop, developed and maintained by Cornell University Library, 2003-2006; extended and maintained by ICPSR, 2007-on. This tutorial is available in English, French, and Italian.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign (UIUC) Graduate School of Library and Information Science (GSLIS): Data Curation Education Program</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/25/university-illinois-urbana-champaign-uiuc-graduate-school-library-and-information-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2011 14:01:28 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/25/university-illinois-urbana-champaign-uiuc-graduate-school-library-and-information-science/</guid>
      <description>The UIUC Graduate School of Library and Information Science&amp;rsquo;s Data Curation Education Program, a specialization within the Master of Library Science program, offers a focus on data collection and management, knowledge representation, digital preservation and archiving, data standards, and policy. GSLIS has also hosted several summer institutes on data curation, designed for working professionals to enhance their skills in this area.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supporting Data Management Infrastructure for the Humanities (Sudamih): Project Outputs</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/25/supporting-data-management-infrastructure-humanities-sudamih-project-outputs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2011 13:37:54 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/25/supporting-data-management-infrastructure-humanities-sudamih-project-outputs/</guid>
      <description>The Sudamih Project Outputs contains presentations and training materials on data management. Includes a bibliography on data management (PDF) covering topics such as policy issues, data sharing, digital curation and preservation, repositories, metadata, and personal information management.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DATUM for Health: Research Data Management Training Search Engine</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/25/datum-health-research-data-management-training-search-engine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2011 13:19:32 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/04/25/datum-health-research-data-management-training-search-engine/</guid>
      <description>DATUM for Health&amp;rsquo;s Research Data Management Training Search Engine is a customised Google search engine that contains web items (sites and documents) identified in a tailored literature review. Sources cover: research data management training, other relevant training, and content that would be useful as course materials or background reading.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>