<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>IASSIST 2006 on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </title>
    <link>https://talatera.github.io/tags/iassist-2006/</link>
    <description>Recent content in IASSIST 2006 on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2006 16:04:55 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://talatera.github.io/tags/iassist-2006/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Waxing Lyrical about IASSIST 2006</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2006/06/08/waxing-lyrical-about-iassist-2006/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2006 16:04:55 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2006/06/08/waxing-lyrical-about-iassist-2006/</guid>
      <description>Melanie Wright and her doo-wop partners, Jen Green and Joanne Juhnke, treated us to this year&amp;rsquo;s song at the wrap up session. These fine phrases should be set to the tune of &amp;ldquo;My Girl&amp;rdquo;
There was sunshine after weeks of rain When the IASSISTers to Ann Arbor came Why have we come so far? What can drag us from the bar? Data (data) talkin&amp;rsquo; &amp;lsquo;bout data (data)
GIS, SDA and Atlas-TI Data lifecycles, and of course DDI in the Reading Room we made some noise and ogled gorgeous jazz band boys and data (data) always talkin&amp;rsquo; &amp;lsquo;bout data (data)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conceptualizing the Digital Life Cycle</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2006/06/01/conceptualizing-digital-life-cycle/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2006 20:49:41 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2006/06/01/conceptualizing-digital-life-cycle/</guid>
      <description>The Digital Life Cycle was mentioned many times during the IASSIST 2006 conference. Reaction toward this concept was varied. Some were unsure they liked this idea claiming that the life cycle was a confusing or imperfect metaphor. Others applied a very exact meaning to the concept associating it to the stages through which information passes within a system or large process. The Session that I chaired on Institutional Repositories and Social Science Data: Supporting the Data Life Cycle (B1) provided different visual representations of the digital life cycle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog the Conference!</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2006/05/25/blog-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2006 16:33:49 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2006/05/25/blog-conference/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the 2006 IASSIST Conference in Ann Arbor! For those who can&amp;rsquo;t join in the fun, we (the Pubs committee and the Admin Committee) have decided it&amp;rsquo;s a good idea for us to blog the conference! (See San&amp;rsquo;s fine example below.) Use this post to comment with your thoughts on a session that really got you thinking. And, (IASSIST members only): become an editor if you would like to post more frequently - contact San.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metadata Musings from IASSIST 2006</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2006/05/25/metadata-musings-iassist-2006/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2006 11:54:42 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2006/05/25/metadata-musings-iassist-2006/</guid>
      <description>I will start with a disclaimer that I am not a metadata expert nor do I play one on TV but I have been spending a lot of time recently contemplating metadata issues. Granted they have been issues that deal with metadata in a time series world but it gave me an interesting frame of reference for attending several sessions on metadata-related issues. Here&amp;rsquo;s my thoughts:
After attending three and a half session exploring metadata issues, the one clear idea that has emerged is that there don&amp;rsquo;t seem to be any clear ideas.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>