<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>IASSIST 2016 on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </title>
    <link>https://talatera.github.io/tags/iassist-2016/</link>
    <description>Recent content in IASSIST 2016 on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 08:50:55 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://talatera.github.io/tags/iassist-2016/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST Quarterly (IQ) volume 40-2 is now on the website:  Revolution in the air</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2017/02/27/iassist-quarterly-iq-volume-40-2-now-website-revolution-air/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 08:50:55 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2017/02/27/iassist-quarterly-iq-volume-40-2-now-website-revolution-air/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the second issue of Volume 40 of the IASSIST Quarterly (IQ 40:2, 2016). We present three papers in this issue.
http://iassistdata.org/iq/issue/40/2
First, there are two papers on the Data Documentation Initiative that have their own special introduction. I want to express my respect and gratitude to Joachim Wackerow (GESIS - Leibniz Institute for the Social Sciences). Joachim (Achim) and Mary Vardigan (University of Michigan) have several times and for many years communicated to and advised the readers of the IASSIST Quarterly on the continuing development of the DDI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IQ 40:1 Now Available!</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2016/09/20/iq-401-now-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2016 05:18:11 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2016/09/20/iq-401-now-available/</guid>
      <description>Our World and all the Local Worlds Welcome to the first issue of Volume 40 of the IASSIST Quarterly (IQ 40:1, 2016). We present four papers in this issue. The first paper presents data from our very own world, extracted from papers published in the IQ through four decades. What is published in the IQ is often limited in geographical scope and in this issue the other three papers present investigations and project research carried out at New York University, Purdue University, and the Federal Reserve System.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feel the Berg! IASSIST 2016</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2016/06/07/feel-berg-iassist-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2016 09:47:08 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2016/06/07/feel-berg-iassist-2016/</guid>
      <description>The conference began with a reception from the Mayor of Bergen, beautifully performed Norwegian folk song, and dissent over the conference hashtag (it was #iassist16).
The next morning data talk began with Gudmund Hernes. His plenary theme is data availability or the latest &amp;ldquo;revolution&amp;rdquo; is, as it always has, causing a shift in power. The role of IASSISTers and data archives should be to &amp;ldquo;keep the record straight&amp;rdquo;.
UK Data Service Director Matthew Woollard&amp;rsquo;s plenary offered a similar theme of adjustment to a changed data world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST 2016 Conference Papers Announcement</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2016/05/25/iassist-2016-conference-papers-announcement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2016 14:46:03 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2016/05/25/iassist-2016-conference-papers-announcement/</guid>
      <description>Hello IASSISTers,
Thank you for the outstanding participation in this year&amp;rsquo;s Conference Paper Competition! We received a lot of quality submissions that will be presented next week at IASSIST 2016 in Bergen, Norway. In advance of the conference, and on behalf of the Program Committee, I&amp;rsquo;d like to announce the winners and runner-ups for the 2016 Conference Paper Award:
Congratulations to Sophia Lafferty Hess and Thu-Mai Christian from ODUM for their paper titled &amp;ldquo;More Data, Less Process: The Applicability of MPLP to Research Data&amp;rdquo;!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New to IASSIST or Willing to Mentor Someone New?</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2016/05/05/new-iassist-or-willing-mentor-someone-new/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 08:34:04 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2016/05/05/new-iassist-or-willing-mentor-someone-new/</guid>
      <description>New to IASSIST or Willing to Mentor Someone New?
We are excited to have new members in IASSIST. IASSIST is a home for data services professionals across many disciplines: librarians, data archivists, open data proponents, data support staff, etc. For some, it is an organization where you don&amp;rsquo;t have to explain what you do because our members already understand. We get metadata, data support, data access issues, database challenges, the challenge of replication and so much more!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interested in the “data revolution” and what it means for research? Here’s why you should attend IASSIST2016</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2016/05/03/interested-in-the-data-revolution-and-what-it-means-for-research-heres-why-you-should-attend-iassist2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2016 02:15:18 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2016/05/03/interested-in-the-data-revolution-and-what-it-means-for-research-heres-why-you-should-attend-iassist2016/</guid>
      <description>Part 1: Data sharing, new data sources and data protection IASSIST is an international organisation of information technology and data services professionals which aims to provide support to research and teaching in the social sciences. It has over 300 members ranging from data archive staff and librarians to statistical agencies, government departments and non-profit organisations.
The theme of this year&amp;rsquo;s conference is &amp;ldquo;Embracing the &amp;lsquo;data revolution&amp;rsquo;: opportunities and challenges for research&amp;rdquo; and it is the 42nd of its kind, taking place every year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2016 IASSIST Fellowships</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2016/04/12/2016-iassist-fellowships/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2016 04:34:17 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2016/04/12/2016-iassist-fellowships/</guid>
      <description>The IASSIST Fellows Committee are pleased to announce that we will be awarding an IASSIST Fellowship award for the 2016 conference to the following recipients:
Marijana Glavica - Systems Librarian, University of Zagreb, Faculty of Humanities and Social Sciences, Croatia
&amp;lsquo;As a systems librarian I work with bibliographic data and manage library automation systems. I am also involved in designing library policies and procedures. As a subject specialist I provide information services to psychology professors and students, and I teach a course about information resources in psychology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST Fellows Program 2015-16</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2015/12/14/iassist-fellows-program-2015-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2015 04:22:46 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2015/12/14/iassist-fellows-program-2015-16/</guid>
      <description>The IASSIST Fellows Program is pleased to announce that it is now accepting applications for financial support to attend the IASSIST 2016 conference in Bergen [http://iassist2016.org/] from data professionals who are developing, supporting and managing data infrastructures at their home institutions.
Please be aware that funding is not intended to cover the entire cost of attending the conference. The applicant&amp;rsquo;s home institution must provide some level of financial support to supplement an IASSIST Fellow award.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>