<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Social Science Datasets on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </title>
    <link>https://talatera.github.io/tags/social-science-datasets/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Social Science Datasets on IASSIST - International Association for Social Science Information Service and Technology </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 May 2016 07:13:42 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://talatera.github.io/tags/social-science-datasets/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST 2016 Program At-A-Glance, Part 2: Data infrastructure, data processing and research data management</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2016/05/06/iassist-2016-program-glance-part-2-data-infrastructure-data-processing-and-research-data-manage/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2016 07:13:42 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2016/05/06/iassist-2016-program-glance-part-2-data-infrastructure-data-processing-and-research-data-manage/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s another list of highlights from IASSIST2016 which is focusing on the data revolution. For previous highlights, see here.
Infrastructure  For those of you with an interest in technical infrastructure, the University of Applied Sciences HTW Chur will showcase an early protype MMRepo (1 June, 3F), whose function is to store qualitative and quantitative data into one big data repository.   The UK Data Service will present the following panel &amp;ldquo;The CESSDA Technical Framework - what is it and why is it needed?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interested in the “data revolution” and what it means for research? Here’s why you should attend IASSIST2016</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2016/05/03/interested-in-the-data-revolution-and-what-it-means-for-research-heres-why-you-should-attend-iassist2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2016 02:15:18 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2016/05/03/interested-in-the-data-revolution-and-what-it-means-for-research-heres-why-you-should-attend-iassist2016/</guid>
      <description>Part 1: Data sharing, new data sources and data protection IASSIST is an international organisation of information technology and data services professionals which aims to provide support to research and teaching in the social sciences. It has over 300 members ranging from data archive staff and librarians to statistical agencies, government departments and non-profit organisations.
The theme of this year&amp;rsquo;s conference is &amp;ldquo;Embracing the &amp;lsquo;data revolution&amp;rsquo;: opportunities and challenges for research&amp;rdquo; and it is the 42nd of its kind, taking place every year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding Historical Economic Data through FRASER and ALFRED </title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/08/26/finding-historical-economic-data-through-fraser-and-alfred/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2013 14:00:13 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/08/26/finding-historical-economic-data-through-fraser-and-alfred/</guid>
      <description>The North Carolina Library Association&amp;rsquo;s Government Resources Section had an excellent webinar yesterday on finding historical (or vintage) economic data using FRASER and ALFRED.The recording and slides are available to everyone. Enjoy!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST Fellows 2013</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/05/06/iassist-fellows-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2013 19:38:07 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/05/06/iassist-fellows-2013/</guid>
      <description>** **
The IASSIST Fellows Committee is glad to announce through this post the six recipients of the 2013 IASSIST Fellowship award. We are extremely excited to have such a diverse and interesting group with different backgrounds and experience and encourage IASSISTers to welcome them at our conference in Cologne, Germany.
Please find below their names, countries and brief bios:
**Chifundo Kanjala (Tanzania) **
Chifundo currently works as a Data Manager and data documentalist for an HIV research group called ALPHA network based at London School of Hygiene and Tropical Medicine&amp;rsquo;s department of Population Health, Chifundo spends most of his time in Mwanza, Tanzania but do travel from time around Southern and Eastern Africa to work with colleagues in the ALPHA network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update from COSSA: Changes to the Common Rule: The Implications for the Social and Behavioral Sciences</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/03/25/update-cossa-changes-common-rule-implications-social-and-behavioral-sciences/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 14:34:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/03/25/update-cossa-changes-common-rule-implications-social-and-behavioral-sciences/</guid>
      <description>This is from the COSSA Newsletter ([Consortium of Social Science Associations).]{.st} March 25, 2013 Volume 32, Issue 6 Regarding a workshop on proposed changes to the Common Rule. Readers of these blog entries will recall that these proposed changes would require that data identitified in social science research would be required to meet HIPPA standards; potentially rendering many public datasets unuseful for research purposes.
A link to the webcast is here: http://sites.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some reflections on research data confidentiality, privacy, and curation by Limor Peer</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/03/07/some-reflections-research-data-confidentiality-privacy-and-curation-limor-peer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2013 11:43:38 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2013/03/07/some-reflections-research-data-confidentiality-privacy-and-curation-limor-peer/</guid>
      <description>Some reflections on research data confidentiality, privacy, and curation
Limor Peer
Maintaining research subjects&amp;rsquo; confidentiality is an essential feature of the scientific research enterprise. It also presents special challenges to the data curation process. Does the effort to open access to research data complicate these challenges?
A few reasons why I think it does: More data are discoverable and could be used to re-identify previously de-identified datasets; systems are increasingly interoperable, potentially bridging what may have been insular academic data with other data and information sources; growing pressure to open data may weaken some of the safeguards previously put in place; and some data are inherently identifiable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ANES Announcement: : Deadlines for the ANES 2010-2012 EGSS Online Commons Proposals</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/07/15/anes-announcement-deadlines-anes-2010-2012-egss-online-commons-proposals/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2011 08:07:59 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/07/15/anes-announcement-deadlines-anes-2010-2012-egss-online-commons-proposals/</guid>
      <description>The American National Election Studies are continuing to accept proposals for the ANES 2010-2012 Evaluations of Government and Society Study. The deadline to submit proposals for EGSS 4 is 3:00p.m. EDT, August 30, 2011. The deadline for members of the Online Commons community to comment on proposals is September 8, 2011. The deadline for revisions to proposals is at 3:00p.m. EDT on September 14, 2011. For additional information about how to submit a proposal, please visit: http://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ANES Announcement: The ANES 2012 Time Series Study</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/07/15/anes-announcement-anes-2012-time-series-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2011 08:05:47 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/07/15/anes-announcement-anes-2012-time-series-study/</guid>
      <description>On June 30, 2011, the American National Election Studies (ANES) began accepting proposals for questions to include on the ANES 2012 Time Series Study. Proposals may be submitted through the ANES Online Commons. The following describes the goals of this study and the opportunity to include questions on it.
About The ANES 2012 Time Series Study
The ANES&amp;rsquo;s core mission is to promote cutting-edge and broadly-collaborative research on American national elections.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIST Quarterly (IQ) volume 34-2 now on the web</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/05/17/iassist-quarterly-iq-volume-34-2-now-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2011 09:02:31 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/05/17/iassist-quarterly-iq-volume-34-2-now-web/</guid>
      <description>The new issue of the IASSIST Quarterly is now available on the web. This is the volume 34 (number 2, 2010).
 http://iassistdata.org/iq/issue/34/2
The layout has changed. We hope you&amp;rsquo;ll enjoy the new style presented. It seems to be a more modern format and more suited for the PDF presentation on the web. Walter Piovesan &amp;ndash; our publication officer &amp;ndash; had a biking accident. To show that nothing is so bad that it is not good for something Walter used his recovery time to redesign the IQ.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Torture, Numbers, and Digital Tape</title>
      <link>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/02/02/torture-numbers-and-digital-tape/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2011 07:02:15 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talatera.github.io/blog/2011/02/02/torture-numbers-and-digital-tape/</guid>
      <description>The IASSIST Quarterly (IQ) volume 33 number 3 is now on the web:
[http://iassistdata.org/iq/issue/33/3]
With this issue concentrating on quantitative investigations and the use of statistics, I came to think of the Mark Twain citation &amp;ldquo;There are three kinds of lies: lies, damned lies, and statistics.&amp;rdquo; With the violent title of the first article (see below), the article on numbers and statistics, and the report from a national statistics agency, the &amp;ldquo;Torture,Numbers, and Digital Tape&amp;rdquo; title surfaced.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>